[
  {
    "question": "The FMS vertical navigation management is generally performed based on:",
    "feedback": "the baro altitude input from the ADC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is flight envelope protection provided in mechanical backup mode?",
    "feedback": "No, flight envelope protection is not provided in mechanical backup mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is descending from FL 390 to ground level at maximum speed. The limit(s) in speed is(are):",
    "feedback": "initially MMO, then VMO below a given flight level"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages provided by an air data computer to indicate the altitude are : 1. Position/pressure error correction 2. Density error correction 3. Remote data transmission capability 4. Capability of operating as a conventional altimeter in the event of a failure The combination of correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,2,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any vibration displayed on an engine vibration monitoring system for a turbojet:",
    "feedback": "indicates rotor imbalance"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the G/S mode (holding of ILS Glide Slope), the position of the horizontal command bar indicates:",
    "feedback": "the correction on the pitch to be applied to join and follow the ILS glide slope"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) present position (lat, long)\n2) altitude\n3) ground speed\n4) true heading\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram shows three gyro assemblies: A, B and C. Among these gyros,\n-one is a roll gyro (noted 1)\n-one is a pitch gyro (noted 2)\n-one is a yaw gyro (noted 3)\nThe correct matching of gyros and assemblies is:",
    "feedback": "1B, 2C, 3A"
  },
  {
    "question": "The on-board communication devices to transmit and receive datalink communication can be:  1) VHF COM 2) HF COM 3) SATCOM4) UHF COM  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a vibration monitoring system, a filter:\n1) Erases any output which is normal to the engine\n2) Allows through to the amplifier any frequency that is considered to be harmful to the engine",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gravity erector system is used to correct the errors on :",
    "feedback": "an artificial horizon."
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft is TCAS II equipped. To be able to generate a traffic advisory (TA), the intruder must be at least equipped with:",
    "feedback": "a transponder mode A"
  },
  {
    "question": "If, during a descent:\n\n- the pneumatic altimeter reading is constant\n- the vertical speed indicator shows zero\n- the IAS is increasing\n\nthe most likely explanation is that:",
    "feedback": "the static ports are completely blocked"
  },
  {
    "question": "The null-seeking (slotted) probe AoA sensor of (1) ...... will automatically rotate (2) ...... to automatically seek a balance point.",
    "feedback": "(1) figure A, (2) anti-clockwise"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of 'Schuler Tuning' as applied to the operation of Inertial Navigation Systems/ Inertial Reference Systems is applicable to:",
    "feedback": "both gyro-stabilised platform and 'strapdown' systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA):\n1) Engaged and armed modes have different colour or different font size2) Engaged modes are shown in white, while armed modes are shown in green3) The FMA indicates the capability to perform an automatic or semi-automatic landing4) Depending on the complexity of the aircraft, FMAs are divided into the sections vertical mode, lateral mode, and auto-thrust mode5) Autopilot and flight director annunciators indicate the AFCS status\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the northern hemisphere, during a deceleration following a landing in a westerly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "an apparent turn to the south"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the Mach meter, select the correct answer from the statements below:",
    "feedback": "VMO and MMO are maximum operating limit speeds for aircraft fitted with gas turbine engines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nQ = charge (Coulombs)\nU = potential difference between the plates (Volt)\nC= capacitance (Farads)\n\nThe correct relationship between these parameters is:",
    "feedback": "Q = C x U"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a dual FMS architecture, during normal operations:",
    "feedback": "One FMC is working as a master and one is working as a slave, but information is synchronized through a common bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "A computer output providing data on several connections and carrying different information simultaneously is called a:",
    "feedback": "Parallel bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Flight Management System (FMS), as for example installed in the B737-400, is to provide:",
    "feedback": "continuous automatic navigation guidance and performance management"
  },
  {
    "question": "The latitude at which the apparent wander of a directional gyro is equal to 0 is:",
    "feedback": "the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alarms are standardised and follow a code of colours. Those requiring action but not immediately, are signalled by the colour:",
    "feedback": "amber"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle between True North and Magnetic North is called :",
    "feedback": "variation"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the pilot flying of an aeroplane established on an ILS to perform an autoland. The aircraft is equipped with two autopilots, which are both engaged, and the autoland capability of the aeroplane is fail-operational. Passing 2000 ft one IRS fails, with the only technical consequence being a downgraded landing capability. Given the information below, what are the consequences of this failure and what should you do?\nApproach minima: 0 ftAlert height: 100 ft",
    "feedback": "The landing capability is now fail-passive and the approach may be continued to revised minima if all the required actions can be completed in a timely manner"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding the closed-loop control system in an aircraft?",
    "feedback": "The transducer converts the mechnical movement of the gyro into an electrical signal"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Machmeter is subject to position error. This error varies according to:\n\n1) angle of attack\n2) OAT\n3) TAS\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The needle of the Turn and Bank indicator shows:",
    "feedback": "The rate at which the aircraft is turning about the yaw axis."
  },
  {
    "question": "A radio altimeter uses the following frequency band:",
    "feedback": "SHF (Super High Frequency)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The standard temperature for all our aerodynamic computations is:",
    "feedback": "15° C or 59° F."
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of accidental closing of an aircraft's left static pressure port (rain, birds), the altimeter:",
    "feedback": "overreads the altitude in case of a sideslip to the left and displays the correct information during symmetric flight."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct regarding unstable/unreliable airspeed indications?\n1) An erroneous indicated airspeed can lead to a high possibility of reduced aircraft controllabilty2) If unreliable airspeed indications are detected, the flight crew are first required to maintain the appropriate pitch attitude and power setting for the phase of flight",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where and when are the INS positions updated?",
    "feedback": "Only on ground during the alignment procedure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The total air temperature (TAT) is:",
    "feedback": "the temperature resulting from the aircraft motion in the air"
  },
  {
    "question": "When climbing at a constant CAS in standard atmosphere:\n\n1) TAS decreases\n2) TAS increases\n3) Mach number increases\n4) Mach number decreases\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "To permit turbine exit temperatures to be measured, gas turbines are equipped with thermometers which work on the following principle:",
    "feedback": "thermocouple"
  },
  {
    "question": "Coefficient B, as used in aircraft magnetism, presents",
    "feedback": "A value representing the deviation registered on headings East and West"
  },
  {
    "question": "When considering a laser gyro, how can the 'lock in' effect be described using the choices below?",
    "feedback": "Special functional processing of the gyro is needed to measure very small rotational speeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic flight control system is coupled to the guidance outputs from an inertial navigation system. \nWhich pair of latitudes will give the greatest difference between initial track read-out and the average true course given, in each case, a difference of longitude of 10°?",
    "feedback": "60°N  to  60°N"
  },
  {
    "question": "In discussing parameters P, Q and R of aircraft hard iron magnetism",
    "feedback": "-Q indicates a blue pole in the left wing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is in take-off position, but the configuration does not allow a safe take-off. What will the take-off warning system provide?",
    "feedback": "It provides an aural warning only"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft in the northern hemisphere is making an accurate rate one turn to the right.  If the initial heading was 135°, after 30 seconds the direct reading magnetic compass should read:",
    "feedback": "more than 225°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A FMS with only a multiple DME sensor operating shall have a position error, 95 % probability, in a non-precision approach equal or less than:",
    "feedback": "0.3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "With an increase in magnetic latitude there will be a decrease in the:",
    "feedback": "directive force"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kalman filtering is used within the:",
    "feedback": "Navigation computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Because of the Earth's magnetic field, a compass placed anywhere on Earth will turn so that the north pole of the magnet inside the compass points towards the:",
    "feedback": "north magnetic pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what headings is the acceleration error of a direct reading compass at its maximum?",
    "feedback": "East and West"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a large transport aeroplane equipped with a fly-by-wire flight control system, the software used for flight controls:",
    "feedback": "is certified at the highest level of safety (level A)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert associated with the mode 3 (altitude loss after take-off or go-around) of the GPWS is:",
    "feedback": "\"DON'T SINK\""
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle of attack transmitter provides an electric signal varying with:\n\n1- the angular position of a wind vane\n2- the deviation between the airplane flight attitude and the path calculated by the inertial unit\n3- a probe differential pressure depending on the variation of the angle of attack\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1 and 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "The primary purpose of a direct reading compass (on a modern transport aircraft) is:",
    "feedback": "As a backup instrument"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the principle of an EVS (Enhanced Vision System)?",
    "feedback": "To generate a real-time image on the PFD or on the HUD using imaging sensors"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS cross track (XTK) is:",
    "feedback": "the abeam distance error, to the left or right from the desired flight plan leg to the aircraft position"
  },
  {
    "question": "To stop the warning generated by an overspeed warning system, the pilot:\n1) can push the inhibit aural warning button2) can switch off the overspeed warning system3) must reduce the airspeed\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding consequences of the loss of an ADC compared to the failure of individual instruments:\n1) A warning flag will appear on the appropriate ADS instrument if there is any loss of valid data2) With a purely mechanical system, comparison between left-and and right-hand instruments must be carried out visually",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "For capturing and keeping a preselected magnetic heading, the flight director computer takes into account:  1- track deviation 2- rate of track closure 3- rate of change of track closure 4- wind velocity given by the inertial reference unit  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,2,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data from the ADC are used by:  1) TCAS 2) EFIS 3) Automatic Flight Control System (AFCS)",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly describes the difference between an armed mode and an engaged mode in an autopilot system?",
    "feedback": "An armed mode will only become engaged when certain criteria are met"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the following display, the .... is indicated by a red square.",
    "feedback": "RA intruder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment time, at mid-latitudes, for an Inertial Navigation System using gymballed gyros is approximately:",
    "feedback": "20 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS cost index is used to adapt the:",
    "feedback": "Flight path to the direct operating cost"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a mode is engaged:",
    "feedback": "In the initial phase the attitude of the aircraft is changed to obtain a new trajectory"
  },
  {
    "question": "Below the tropopause in standard atmosphere, when descending at a constant Mach number:",
    "feedback": "TAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying an approach in low visibility using head up displays (HUD), the crew finds that some of their view of the outside world is obscured by HUD data. The crew should ......",
    "feedback": "activate the \"declutter\" function to remove all but essential flight data"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following an automatic landing, with the ROLL OUT mode engaged, the autopilot:",
    "feedback": "controls the rudder and nose wheel steering to keep the aeroplane on the localiser centreline"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is vacuum provided for the air-driven gyro instruments?",
    "feedback": "By an engine-driven pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a large aeroplane and according to the CS 25: when the speed is reduced, the stall warning must begin:",
    "feedback": "at a speed exceeding the stall speed by not less than 5 kt or 5% CAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Earth can be considered as being a magnet with the:",
    "feedback": "blue pole near the north pole of the earth and the direction of the magnetic force pointing straight down to the earth's surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ACARS allows air/ground datalink communications for:",
    "feedback": "Airline Operational and Air Traffic Communications (AOC & ATC)"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are two classes for the hardware that is used for EFB systems. These are ......",
    "feedback": "\"portable\" and \"installed\""
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying steadily at FL180 with the AP engaged you suspect erroneous altimeter indications. What could you check to know which altimeter delivers a correct indication?",
    "feedback": "GPS altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "To ensure that, in case of autopilot failure, flight path deviations remain within safe limits, when the autopilot is engaged ....",
    "feedback": "engagement occurs only if the aircraft is in trim, with control loads very low"
  },
  {
    "question": "When pressing the push button EVENT on the unit control of a flight data recorder:",
    "feedback": "a mark is set on the recording, enabling this event to be found rapidly at a subsequent analysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "When descending at a constant CAS in standard atmosphere:\n\n1) TAS increases\n2) TAS decreases\n3) Mach number increases\n4) Mach number decreases\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The computer of the autopilot system uses, among others, the following parameters:",
    "feedback": "CAS, altitude, vertical speed, heading, attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the source of magnetic variation information in a Flight Management System (FMS)?",
    "feedback": "Magnetic variation information is stored in each IRS memory; it is applied to the true heading calculated by the respective IRS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS Flight Plan, Navigation, Progress or Leg page generally displays the following parameters relative to the flight plan legs or waypoints:\n1- remaining fuel prediction\n2- aircraft position\n3- distance\n4- time prediction\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,3,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position data (lat, long) computed by an IRS can be used by the:",
    "feedback": "FMS"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the significance of the yellow arc in an airspeed indicator?",
    "feedback": "Structural warning range."
  },
  {
    "question": "A D-ATIS is:",
    "feedback": "an ATIS message received by datalink"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight director command bars provide the pilot with correction to apply to:",
    "feedback": "pitch and/or roll attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the use of the TCS (Touch Control Steering)?",
    "feedback": "temporary manual flying while the autopilot is still engaged"
  },
  {
    "question": "Acquired data from the Aircraft Condition Monitoring System (ACMS) may be used:",
    "feedback": "As part of an FDM and safety programme"
  },
  {
    "question": "The electronic tachometer sensor is composed of:",
    "feedback": "a notched wheel rotating in front of an electro-magnet."
  },
  {
    "question": "The sensors of an INS measure:",
    "feedback": "acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight director computer continuously:",
    "feedback": "compares the current attitude with the computed attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will be affected by a radio altimeter failure?\n1) Air Data Computer2) Autothrust3) GPWS4) Altitude alert system",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The limits of the green scale of an airspeed indicator are :",
    "feedback": "VS1 for the lower limit and VNO for the upper limit"
  },
  {
    "question": "A landing will be considered to be performed in the SEMI-AUTOMATIC mode when:\n1- the autopilot maintains the airplane on the ILS beam until  the decision height is reached then is disengaged automatically.\n2- the autothrottle maintains a constant speed  until the decision height is reached then is disengaged automatically.\n3- the autopilot maintains the airplane on the ILS beam until the flare.\n4- the autothrottle decreases the thrust when the height is approximately 30 ft.\n5- the flare and the ground roll are performed automatically.\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1 and 2."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following factors must the Air Data Computer (ADC) use for its calculations when going from IAS to TAS?\n1) Compressibility errors2) Density errors3) Instrument errors4) Pitot errors5) Position errors6) Temperature errors7) Yaw errors",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding the hold phase of the autopilot?",
    "feedback": "The autopilot maintains the set parameter without any change"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the flight level and Mach number remain constant, when the OAT increases:",
    "feedback": "CAS remains constant and TAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Synthetic Vision System (SVS) shows (1) ...... on (2) ....... display.",
    "feedback": "(1) Terrain and ground features database, (2) PFD"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft, operating in the VOR coupled mode, approaches the \"cone of confusion\" over a VOR station, the roll channel of the autopilot :",
    "feedback": "temporarily maintains a heading."
  },
  {
    "question": "The radio altimeter supplies data to the following system(s):\n\n1) altitude alert system\n2) TCAS\n3) GPWS\n4) automatic landing system\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic variation:",
    "feedback": "is caused by the different locations of the geographic north pole and the magnetic north pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nPt = total pressure\nPs = static pressure\nPd = dynamic pressure\n\nThe airspeed indicator measures:",
    "feedback": "Pt-Ps"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment time of a strapdown inertial system takes longer time when the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "at a high latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct or incorrect?\n1) GPS altitude can be used to replace the reading on the pressure altimeter2) Absolute altitude is the actual height of an aircraft above the surface",
    "feedback": "1) is not correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Control and Display Unit (CDU) on an FMS is:",
    "feedback": "used by the crew to input data into FMC"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turn indicator is an instrument which indicates rate of turn.\nRate of turn depends upon :\n\n1) bank angle\n2) aeroplane speed\n3) aeroplane weight\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1 and 2."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot engages the control wheel steering (CWS) of a conventional autopilot and carries out a manoeuvre in roll. When the control wheel is released, the autopilot will :",
    "feedback": "maintain the flight attitude obtained at that moment."
  },
  {
    "question": "CAS is obtained from IAS by correcting for the:",
    "feedback": "position and instrument errors"
  },
  {
    "question": "When descending at a constant Mach number:",
    "feedback": "CAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CPDLC messages may concern:\n\n1) route modifications\n2) speed changes\n3) voice contact request\n4) emergency messages\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the activation of the take-off warning when a take-off is initiated are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) An aural warning is given when the elevator is not in a safe position for take-off\n2) An aural warning is given when the brake pressure is too low",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The long term periodic change in the earth's magnetic field:",
    "feedback": "is reflected in the slow movement of the magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "The direction \"magnetic north\" at a position on the earth is:",
    "feedback": "the direction of the horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field at that position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The dip angle in the terrestrial magnetic field is given by the following equation:",
    "feedback": "Dip = cos-1 (H/T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The take-off and landing performance application of the EFB is certified as:",
    "feedback": "Type B software"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the instantaneous vertical speed indicator (IVSI):",
    "feedback": "It tends to overreact to turbulent flying conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the fuel mass unit is correct?",
    "feedback": "1 lb = 0.45 kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose(s) of the flight director system is (are) to:\n\n1) give the position of the aircraft according to radioelectric axis\n2) give the position of the aircraft according to waypoints\n3) to aid the pilot when flying manually\n\nthe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic flight control system (AFCS) in an aircraft is coupled to the guidance outputs from an inertial navigation system (INS) and the aircraft is flying from waypoint No. 2 (60°00'S  070°00'W)  to No. 3 (60°00'S  080°00'W).\nComparing the initial track (°T) at 070°00'W and the final track (°T) at 080°00'W, the difference between them is that the initial track is approximately:",
    "feedback": "9° less than the final one"
  },
  {
    "question": "The command bars of a flight director:",
    "feedback": "may be displayed when flying manually"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nMH=magnetic heading of the aircraft\nOmega= yawing rate of the aircraft\n\nThe yaw damper computer sends a motion order to the rudder if:",
    "feedback": "the derivative of Omega according to time is not equal to zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which function does auto throttle perform during the engine start sequence?",
    "feedback": "Auto throttle is not used for engine start"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS calculator is able to operate in the following modes :\n\n1- excessive descent rate \n2- excessive rate of terrain closure\n3- excessive angle of attack\n4- too high descent attitude \n5- loss of altitude after take-off\n6- abnormal gear/flaps configuration\n7- excessive glidepath deviation\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,5,6,7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode is selected on the Navigation Display (EHSI)?",
    "feedback": "Plan mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot wishes to turn left on to a southerly heading with 20° bank at a latitude of 20° North. Using a direct reading compass, in order to achieve this he must stop the turn on an approximate heading of :",
    "feedback": "160°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Match calibrated airspeed (CAS) with the associated definition:",
    "feedback": "Indicated airspeed corrected for installation and instrument errors."
  },
  {
    "question": "The T/C is .... and it will be reached at approximately ....",
    "feedback": "FMC calculated top of climb; 6 NM from present position"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following parameters, in a capacitance fuel gauge, the correct formula is:\n\nA = area of plates\nD = distance between plates\nE = dielectric permittivity",
    "feedback": "Capacitance = E x A / D"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic power control system (auto-throttle) of a transport aeroplane has the following mode(s) :\n\n1) capture and holding of speeds\n2) capture and holding of Mach number\n3) capture and holding of flight angle of attack\n4) capture and holding of N1 or EPR (Engine Power Ratio)\n5) capture and holding of flight paths\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Engine thrust is controlled by the automatic thrust control system (auto throttle) in response to:",
    "feedback": "Mode commands from the flight crew or the Flight Management Computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sequence of the automatic landing comprises several phases (from final approach to touch-down) actuated by:",
    "feedback": "the radio altimeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fuel quantity measurement are correct or incorrect?\n1) The quantity of fuel can be measured by volume\n2) The quantity of fuel can be measured by mass",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the flight warning system (FWS) identifies an overspeed condition (airspeed exceeding Vmo/Mmo), it generates:",
    "feedback": "a warning message"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aeroplane equipped with a constant speed propeller, the RPM indicator enables :",
    "feedback": "control of the propeller regulator and the display of propeller RPM."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of a failure of the trim system:\n1) Alerts consist of warning lights and/or suitable indications on the electronic display unit2) Aural alerts will sound in an actuator runaway situation3) The autopilot remains operative, if the auto-trim system is not available4) It is common practice to use the fully operative system, if another autopilot is available\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "At a constant Mach number, the calibrated air speed (CAS) :",
    "feedback": "decreases when the altitude increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sensor should be used to measure a temperature of 500ºC?",
    "feedback": "A thermocouple"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alternate static source is used:",
    "feedback": "when the static ports become blocked"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the FMS, entering a cost index of zero results in:",
    "feedback": "maximum range airspeed"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an EFIS control panel, the combination of mode and range selection can help the crew to assess:\n1) How to avoid weather phenomena2) The position of surrounding traffic3) The manoeuvre to avoid unusual attitude4) The aircraft's position relative to the underlying terrain5) The status of the autopilot engagement",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The figure shows a Multifunction Display (MFD) with AFCS controls and Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA). The pilot is performing a commercial air transport VFR flight and the passengers asked to deviate from the planned route. The pilot disengages the autopilot, turns off course and descends to a lower altitude. The Flight Director (FD) at this point indicates that the aircraft is not following the planned route. Should the pilot take further action?",
    "feedback": "Yes, the FD must either be switched OFF or the pilot must select modes and parameters for the new intended flight path for the FD to give appropriate guidance"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot flying an RNAV 5 leg in en-route or terminal airspace would expect to see what roll-mode indiations on their flight mode annunciator (FMA)?",
    "feedback": "LNAV or NAV"
  },
  {
    "question": "Absolute pressure is",
    "feedback": "measured from zero pressure (vacuum)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to flight plans is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "navigation database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The uplink datalink message \"AT (time) CLIMB TO AND MAINTAIN (altitude) means:",
    "feedback": "at the specified time a climb to the specified altitude is to be started and the specified altitude is to be maintained"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nE = electromotive force (emf)\nT = hot junction temperature\nK = constant\n\nThe relationship that applies to a thermocouple is:",
    "feedback": "E = K x T"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is equipped with an autopilot and an auto-throttle. When the altitude hold mode (ALT HOLD) is active:",
    "feedback": "the IAS is maintained constant by the auto-throttle system"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to cruising speeds is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The picture shows a common style of Multifunction Display (MFD) with AFCS controls and Flight Mode Annunciators (FMAs).\nThe pilot is manually flying an ILS approach and intends to use the Flight Director (FD) as guidance. The aircraft is established on, and following the trajectory of, the ILS as shown by the guidance from the raw data localiser (LOC) and glideslope (GS) indicators. Which statement is correct regarding the indications given by the FD?",
    "feedback": "Both LOC and GS modes are armed and the command bar is showing appropriate information to the pilot to pitch up the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot of a large transport aeroplane equipped with EFIS is flying in the cruise with the autopilot on. There is only one pilot at the controls, who is completing paperwork, and is not looking at the control panel when a potentially hazardous situation requires crew attention but not immediate action. How is the pilot's attention drawn to the problem?",
    "feedback": "A yellow or amber light in the pilot's normal primary field of vision with an aural alert"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to EASA AIR OPS regulations, the Cockpit Voice Recorder of a 50 seat multi-engined aircraft, having been granted an airworthiness certificate after 1st April 1998, shall start recording :",
    "feedback": "Automatically prior to the aircraft moving under its own power until flight completion when the aircraft is no longer able to move under its own power."
  },
  {
    "question": "A yaw damper is :",
    "feedback": "A rudder damper designed to avoid the \"Dutch roll\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "The position of the command bars of a flight director enables the pilot to know:\n\n1) the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to apply on the controls\n2) only the direction of the corrections to apply on the controls\n3) the attitude of the aircraft\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some of the FMS have a navigation mode called Dead Reckoning mode (DR), computing airspeed, heading, wind data ground speed and time. This mode is:",
    "feedback": "a back up navigation mode to compute a FMS position when the other navigation sensors are no longer operating."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the aircraft closed-loop control system:\n1) The aircraft attitude is sensed by the rate gyro that gives a measure of the output2) The servomotor converts processed signals into movement of the aircraft flight controls",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, to know the distance travelled, it is necessary to:\n\n1) integrate once the speed in time\n2) to know the initial position\n3) to know the initial speed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A basic computer (\"Von Neumann architecture\" type) consists of the following components:\n\n1) an Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU)\n2) a control unit\n3) a memory\n4) input and output devices\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In automatic landing mode, when the 2 autopilots are used, the system is considered:",
    "feedback": "\"fail operational\" or without failure effect with function always ensured."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the absence of position and instrument errors:",
    "feedback": "IAS = CAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the ground, during a right turn, the turn indicator indicates :",
    "feedback": "needle to the right, ball to left"
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern low altitude radioaltimeters emit waves in the following frequency band:",
    "feedback": "SHF (Super High Frequency)."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a large aeroplane and according to the CS 25: the regulatory margin between the stall and stall warning is:",
    "feedback": "5 kt or 5% of the CAS whichever is the greater"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on a freely suspended magnetic needle in the terrestrial magnetic field:",
    "feedback": "The needle will align itself with the direction of the magnetic lines of force"
  },
  {
    "question": "The systems that can be connected to the Communication Management Unit (CMU) are:\n\n1) EGPWS\n2) HF Communication Unit\n3) Multipurpose Control and Display (MCDU)\n4) VHF Communication Unit\n5) Satcom\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements is true?",
    "feedback": "The probes used for SAT measurements have a recovery factor of 0.75 to 0.90, while \nthe probes used for TAT measurements have a recovery factor of around 1.00."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which navigation receivers are commonly used for updates of the FMS position in flight?",
    "feedback": "DME, VOR, LOC, GPS"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many diaphragms are present in a basic Mach meter?",
    "feedback": "Two."
  },
  {
    "question": "Should a Schuler platform be displaced from the horizontal, it would oscillate with a period of about:",
    "feedback": "84 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nC = temperature in Celsius\nK = temperature in Kelvin\n\nThe correct relationship between these different units is:",
    "feedback": "C = K - 273"
  },
  {
    "question": "The open-ended tube parallel to the longitudinal axis of the aircraft senses the:",
    "feedback": "total pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding an Inertial Navigation System:\n1) The INS platform is maintained level and north-aligned after alignment is complete and the aircraft is in motion2) An incorrect entry of latitude may lead to a loss of alignment and is less critical than the incorrect entry of longitude",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An automatic pilot is a system which can ensure the functions of:",
    "feedback": "piloting and guidance of an aircraft in both the horizontal and vertical planes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The total Magnetic Force of the terrestrial magnetic field",
    "feedback": "Is strongest at the magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given :\nM is the Mach number\nTs is the static temperature\nTt is the total temperature",
    "feedback": "Ts = Tt /(1+0.2. M²)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot pitch channel controls speed for the mode combinations N1 and LVL CHG (climb), THR IDLE, and LVL CHG (descent), while the autothrust controls have a fixed thrust target:\n1) The autopilot is prevented from exceeding pitch attitudes that will result in speeds that are not within the flight envelope of the aircraft2) The autothrust system is prevented from exceeding thrust and speed limits displayed on the MCP if they are not within the flight envelope of the aircraft3) Below 400 ft RA, the A/T thrust response rates and engine power levels are not sufficient to place the engines in the rapid acceleration range\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a strapdown inertial system, the operating principle requires the use of at least:",
    "feedback": "3 laser gyros and 3 accelerometers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper, which suppresses Dutch roll:",
    "feedback": "controls the rudder, with the angular rate about the vertical axis as the input signal."
  },
  {
    "question": "An Inertial Navigation System (INS) is:",
    "feedback": "a self contained system which operates without signals from the ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nC = temperature in Celsius\nF = temperature in Fahrenheit\n\nThe correct relationship between these different units is:",
    "feedback": "F = (C x 1.8) + 32"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select from the options below the correct statement with regard to the \"performance factor. It is a:",
    "feedback": "Positive or negative factor intended to adjust the predicted rate of fuel flow"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is a null-seeking AoA device protected from icing?",
    "feedback": "Electric heating"
  },
  {
    "question": "A radio altimeter can be defined as a :",
    "feedback": "self-contained on-board aid used to measure the true height of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A rate gyro is used in a:\n\n1) directional gyro indicator\n2) turn co-ordinator\n3) artificial horizon\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "VNO is the maximum speed :",
    "feedback": "not to be exceeded except in still air and with caution."
  },
  {
    "question": "The image shows a typical FMA. Why is \"VOR/LOC\" in a smaller font of a different colour?",
    "feedback": "To distinguish between engaged modes and armed modes. MCP SPD HDG and ALT are engaged, VOR/LOC is armed"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an aircraft maintaining a constant CAS and flight level is flying from a cold air mass into warmer air:",
    "feedback": "TAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "When turning right from 330°(C) to 040°(C) in the northern hemisphere, the reading of a direct reading magnetic compass will:",
    "feedback": "under-indicate the turn and liquid swirl will increase the effect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure altitude is the altitude corresponding :",
    "feedback": "in standard atmosphere, to the pressure Ps prevailing at this point"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment of a strapdown inertial system consists in:",
    "feedback": "measuring the Earth rotation and local gravitation to position the reference trihedron"
  },
  {
    "question": "Indicated airspeed (as read on the airspeed indicator] will:",
    "feedback": "Remain unchanged in headwind and tailwind."
  },
  {
    "question": "The duration of a FMS navigation database loaded before expiring is:",
    "feedback": "28 days."
  },
  {
    "question": "On an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), the following fuel data may be displayed:\n1) Fuel quantity in each tank\n2) Total fuel quantity\n3) Fuel type\n4) Fuel temperature\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "FANS-A units utilize the following for data transmissions:",
    "feedback": "Satellite-based ACARS systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a Touch Control Steering (TCS) system work?",
    "feedback": "By pressing a button to disengage the flight controls from the autopilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the white/cyan colours are associated with the following indication:",
    "feedback": "armed mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "As a result of the failure of the central air data computer (CADC), the inertial navigation system (INS) will no longer provide information about:",
    "feedback": "the wind direction and speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, under normal conditions, what should each one of the three IRU mode selector switches be set to?",
    "feedback": "NAV, thus providing the outputs of acceleration, attitude and heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lists, which compares an Inertial Reference System that utilises Ring Laser Gyroscopes (RLG) instead of conventional gyroscopes, is completely correct?",
    "feedback": "There is little or no 'spin up' time and it is insensitive to gravitational ('g') forces"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) navigation database typically includes the following data:\n1) airports2) obstacles3) navaids4) airways5) terrain cells\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the flight level and Mach number remain constant, when the OAT decreases:",
    "feedback": "TAS decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the alignment phase of an inertial platform, the platform orientation is determined:",
    "feedback": "through platform gyroscopes sensing the earth's angular components"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic force causing compass deviation will be a force in direction",
    "feedback": "Perpendicular to the compass needle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which components form the basis of computer memory?",
    "feedback": "Capacitors"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a TCAS is operating, a failure of the active transponder will cause the TCAS to:",
    "feedback": "no longer operate normally"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS can automatically tune radio navigation facilities in its database. Its choice is based on the:",
    "feedback": "Suitability of the available signal in terms of geometry and strength"
  },
  {
    "question": "The disadvantages of a single-phase A.C. generator tachometer are:\n\n1- the presence of spurious signals due to a D.C. generator commutator\n2- the importance of line resistance on the information value\n3- the influence of temperature on the tachometer information\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an autopilot system, the function consisting in controlling the movements around the center of gravity of the aircraft is provided by the:",
    "feedback": "inner loop systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermocouple is a temperature sensor....",
    "feedback": "which makes use of the thermoelectric effect to measure a differential temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TAS is obtained from the IAS by correcting for the following errors:\n\n1) instrument\n2) position\n3) compressibility\n4) density\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason for mounting the detector unit of a remote reading compass in the wingtip of an aeroplane is:",
    "feedback": "to minimise the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment sequence of an Inertial Reference System (IRS) consists of:  1) search for the local vertical 2) search for the True North 3) comparison between the longitude find and the one entered by the operator 4) comparison between the latitude find and the one entered by the operator  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The EGPWS may propose the following functions:\n\n1) Abnormal Take-off Configuration (ATC)\n2) Terrain Clearance Floor (TCF)\n3) Predictive Wind Shear (PWS)\n4) Terrain Look Ahead Alerting\n5) Terrain Alerting and Display (TAD)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermocouple consists of:",
    "feedback": "a junction of two dissimilar metals"
  },
  {
    "question": "What additional information is required to be input to an Inertial Navigation System (INS) in order to obtain an W/V readout?",
    "feedback": "TAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the GPWS (Ground Proximity Warning System) activates, and alerts the pilot with an aural warning  \"DON'T SINK\" (twice times), it is because :",
    "feedback": "during take-off or missed approach manoeuvre, the aircraft has started to loose altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to CS-25, in case of an EFIS failure, standby instruments must normally be ......",
    "feedback": "available without additional flight crew action"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is an advantage of a remote reading compass as compared with a standby compass?",
    "feedback": "It senses the magnetic meridian instead of seeking it, increasing compass sensitivity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following items is/are operational limitations in order to legally perform an autoland procedure?\n1) Headwind, crosswind2) Pressure altitude3) Runway contamination\nThe answer containing all of the correct items, is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to STARs and SIDs is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "navigation database"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deviation on MH 180 is -5 and on MH 000 it is +3. Calculate coefficient C:",
    "feedback": "Coefficient C = +4"
  },
  {
    "question": "During initial alignment an inertial navigation system is north aligned by inputs from:",
    "feedback": "horizontal accelerometers and the east gyro"
  },
  {
    "question": "Within a temperature range of +50° and -20° C the VSI is accurate to within limits of:",
    "feedback": "+/- 200 ft/min."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a basic computer, the input and output devices are typically:\n\n1) a printer\n2) a keyboard\n3) a display\n4) an optical disk\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "When being engaged, and without selecting a particular mode, an automatic pilot enables :",
    "feedback": "aeroplane stabilisation with attitude hold or maintaining vertical speed and possibly automatic trim."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, the integration process makes a:",
    "feedback": "time multiplication"
  },
  {
    "question": "When can more than one autopilot be engaged at the same time in an aircraft?",
    "feedback": "During autoland"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the colour associated with a caution-type alert is:",
    "feedback": "amber or yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS Flight Plan, Navigation, Progress or Leg page generally displays the following parameters relative to the flight plan legs or waypoints:\n1- time prediction\n2- distance\n3- magnetic variation\n4-altitude constraint or prediction\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rate-of-turn is the:",
    "feedback": "change-of-heading rate of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The limits of the yellow scale of an airspeed indicator are :",
    "feedback": "VNO for the lower limit and VNE for the upper limit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gyromagnetic compass torque motor :",
    "feedback": "causes the directional gyro unit to precess"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the certification type of EFB systems in case a failure causes a minor impact on the safety of the flight?",
    "feedback": "Type B"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, to know the distance travelled:",
    "feedback": "integrating once the speed in time is sufficient"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, the principle used to obtain the change in speed is:",
    "feedback": "single integration of acceleration according to time"
  },
  {
    "question": "The use of an alternate static source fed from within the cabin results that the static pressure senses is likely to be:",
    "feedback": "lower than ambient pressure due to aerodynamic suction"
  },
  {
    "question": "A remote reading compass is fitted with a free/slave switch. When \"slave\" is selected and the system is synchronized, the source of the heading that is displayed is ....",
    "feedback": "the flux detection unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Except for airplanes under 5,7 t airworthiness certificate of which is subsequent to 31 march 1998, a flight data recording system must be able to store the recorded data for a minimum of the last :",
    "feedback": "25 hours."
  },
  {
    "question": "Reference should be made to the fuel supply system.\nIn flight, with center tank empty and APU operating, a fuel unbalance is detected (quantity in tank 1 < quantity in tank 2).\nRebalancing of the two tanks is:",
    "feedback": "possible with \"CROSSFEED\" open and tank 1 pumps \"OFF\" and tank 2 pumps \"ON\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert(s) associated with the mode 3 (altitude loss after take-off or go-around) of the GPWS is(are):\n\n1) \"TERRAIN\"\n2) \"DON'T SINK\"\n3) \"SINKRATE\"\n4) \"PULL UP\"\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot intends to have 70 USG total fuel on board of the aircraft and requests the aircraft to be refuelled accordingly. Has the aircraft been adequately refuelled, based on the systems display?",
    "feedback": "Yes, the amount of fuel on board is about 72 USG"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a basic computer (\"Von Neumann architecture\" type) the Central Processing Unit (CPU) includes:",
    "feedback": "an Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU) and a control unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The signal supplied by a transmitter fitted with a magnetic sensor, connected to an RPM indicator is :",
    "feedback": "an AC voltage, the frequency of which varies with the RPM; the indicator converts the signal into square pulses which are then counted"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about computer architecture are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The software part includes the programmes that make up the operating system (OS)\n2) The hardware part includes the physical components of the computer",
    "feedback": "1 is correct, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aneroid capsule:\n\n1) measures differential pressure\n2) measures absolute pressure\n3) is used for low pressure measurement\n4) is used for very high pressure measurement\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert associated with the mode 1 (excessive descent rate) of the GPWS is:",
    "feedback": "\"SINKRATE\""
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft radio equipment which emits on a frequency of 4400 MHz is the :",
    "feedback": "radio altimeter."
  },
  {
    "question": "The sideslip indication displayed on the PFD (Primary Flight Display) is generated by the:",
    "feedback": "inertial system"
  },
  {
    "question": "A three-phase electrical tachometer consists of:",
    "feedback": "a three-phase generator, a synchronous motor and a magnetic tachometer."
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of impending stall, the flight warning system (FWS) generates:",
    "feedback": "a warning message"
  },
  {
    "question": "The spin axis of the turn indicator gyroscope is parallel to the:",
    "feedback": "pitch axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does it mean when the ball of a turn indicator is centered?",
    "feedback": "Forces are along the normal axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight Director Information supplied by an FD computer is presented in the form of command bars on the following instrument:",
    "feedback": "ADI Attitude Display Indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "The directional gyro keeps its rotation axis aligned toward",
    "feedback": "a point in space."
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of excessive descent rate, the GPWS generates the following aural warnings:",
    "feedback": "\"SINK RATE, SINK RATE\" followed by \"WHOOP WHOOP PULL UP\" (twice)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermocouple can be made of:",
    "feedback": "Two metal conductors of different nature fixed together at one end"
  },
  {
    "question": "An autopilot is control system that uses control loops:",
    "feedback": "The two types of control loops used in the AFCS are closed loops and open loops"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 3 represents:",
    "feedback": "a right turn with insufficient rudder"
  },
  {
    "question": "If, in the event of a failure, the approach, flare and landing can be completed by the remaining part of the automatic system, such an automatic landing system is considered as:",
    "feedback": "fail-operational"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following information can be displayed on a Primary Flight Display (PFD): 1) Attitude 2) Maximum airspeed warning 3) Selected heading 4) Decision height 5) Ground speed  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long will the ADIRU alignment approximately take at around 60° latitude?",
    "feedback": "20 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a descent at a constant Mach number below the tropopause in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "CAS and TAS increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to V1, VR and V2 speeds is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The error induced by the location of the static pressure source is known as the:",
    "feedback": "position error"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a 3-phase synchronous motor type tachometer indicator :\n\n1- the transmitter is a direct current generator\n2- the voltage is proportional to the transmitter drive speed \n3- the frequency is proportional to the transmitter drive speed\n4- the speed indicating element is a galvanometer\n5. the speed indicating element is an synchronous motor driving a magnetic tachometer\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an autopilot system, the functions consisting in controlling the path of the aircraft are the:",
    "feedback": "guidance functions"
  },
  {
    "question": "EAS can be obtained from the following data:",
    "feedback": "CAS and pressure altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Full Authority Digital Engine Control (FADEC) has the following functions :\n\n1- flow regulation (fuel, decelerations and accelerations monitoring)\n2- automatic starting sequence \n3- transmissions of engine data to the pilot's instruments\n4- thrust management and protection of operation limits  \n5- monitoring of the thrust reversers\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altitude alerting system:",
    "feedback": "alerts the flight crew upon approaching a pre-selected altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The role of the FMS (Flight Management System) is to:\n\n1) aid the crew with navigation\n2) shut down the engine in case of a malfunction\n3) automatically avoid conflicting traffic when autopilot is engaged\n4) reduce crew workload\n5) aid fuel efficiency\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "For the autothrust part of the flight guidance system, which of the following modes are thrust modes?\n1) SPEED2) N13) THR IDLE4) TOGA5) V/S",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "When performing an automatic landing, some additional operational limitations may apply, like:\n1) Maximum headwind or crosswind\n2) Airport maximum pressure altitude\n3) Runway conditions\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight recorder duration must be such that flight data, cockpit voice and sound warnings may respectively be recorded during at least:",
    "feedback": "25 hours for flight data, 30 minutes for cockpit voices and warnings horns."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the INS control panel, the rotary knob can be selected to OFF, NAV or ATT positions. The correct statement is:",
    "feedback": "NAV is the normal system setting; the ATT position is the back up position in case of failure of the navigation function"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accelerometers of a strap-down Inertial Reference System are in line with:",
    "feedback": "the aircraft axes"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an autopilot system, the basic stabilisation modes are:\n\n1) altitude hold\n2) pitch attitude hold\n3) roll attitude hold\n4) IAS hold\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum number of accelerometers required on an INS platform?",
    "feedback": "Two"
  },
  {
    "question": "Precession in a gyroscope is",
    "feedback": "the reaction at 90 degrees in direction of rotation caused by a applied force to the spinning wheel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indications on a directional gyroscope or gyrocompass are subject to errors, due to:\n\n1- rotation of Earth.\n2- aeroplane motion on Earth.\n3- lateral and transversal aeroplane bank angles.\n4- north change.\n5- mechanical defects.\n\nChose the combination with true statements only:",
    "feedback": "1,2,3,5."
  },
  {
    "question": "Some inertial reference and navigation systems are known as \"strapdown\". \nThis means that:",
    "feedback": "the gyroscopes and accelerometers become part of the unit's fixture to the aircraft structure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of the Mach indicator is based on the computation of the ratio :",
    "feedback": "(Pt - Ps) to Ps"
  },
  {
    "question": "What may lead to loss of alignment in an INS?",
    "feedback": "Entering the wrong latitude before initial alignment"
  },
  {
    "question": "A blocked pitot head with a clear static source causes the airspeed indicator to:",
    "feedback": "react like an altimeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Flight Data Recorder (FDR) is to record specific parameters such as:\n1) Pressure altitude\n2) Propulse/thrust power on each engine\n3) The audio environment in the flight deck\n4) Heading\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS can warn the crew in case of:\n\n1) excessive climb rate\n2) unsafe terrain clearance when not in landing configuration\n3) descent path angle greater than 5 degrees\n4) windshear\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS 1 (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) provides :\n\n1- traffic information\n2- horizontal resolution (RA: Resolution Advisory)\n3- vertical resolution (RA: Resolution Advisory)\n4- ground proximity warning\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight warning system (FWS) generates a caution message if:",
    "feedback": "immediate crew awareness is required and subsequent crew action will be required"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pre-flight serviceability test of a direct reading compass consists of:",
    "feedback": "Comparing the indication to another reference (e.g. runway direction)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flying manually during a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the G/S mode (holding of ILS glide slope). If the aircraft is above the ILS glide slope, the horizontal command bar:",
    "feedback": "may be centred if the pilot is correcting to come back on the ILS glide slope"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the pilot flying of an aeroplane established on an ILS to perform an autoland. Your aircraft is equipped with two autopilots, which are both engaged, and the autoland capability of the aeroplane is fail-operational. Passing 400 ft one autopilot fails, with the only technical consequence being a downgraded landing capability. Given the information below, what are the consequences of this failure and what should you do?",
    "feedback": "The aircraft annunciates the failure but you perform a go around as there is no time to select a new minima"
  },
  {
    "question": "The EGPWS:",
    "feedback": "is an enhanced GPWS which has its own world terrain database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of compass swinging is to determine the deviation of a magnetic compass :",
    "feedback": "on any heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "The component used to enter a flight plan into the FMS is:",
    "feedback": "MCDU"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel flow can be expressed in:\n1) kg per m3\n2) lb per m3\n3) lb per hour\n4) kg per hour\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight director indicates the :",
    "feedback": "optimum instantaneous trajectory to reach selected radial"
  },
  {
    "question": "The platform of an inertial navigation system (INS) is maintained at right angles to the local vertical by applying corrections for the effects of:",
    "feedback": "aircraft manoeuvres, earth rotation, transport wander and coriolis"
  },
  {
    "question": "A capacitive fuel quantity measurement system provides the following indication:",
    "feedback": "The mass of the fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "During climb with the autopilot engaged in the V/S mode (holding of vertical speed), the auto-throttle:",
    "feedback": "can be operated in the SPEED mode (holding of IAS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a non-pressurized aircraft, if one or several static pressure ports are damaged, there is an ultimate emergency means for restoring a practically correct static pressure intake :",
    "feedback": "breaking the rate-of-climb indicator glass window"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main transfer device in a computer?",
    "feedback": "A Serial bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "On this Mode Control Panel, which switch is used to select the autothrottle OFF?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft without EFIS has an inflight MASTER CAUTION alert. How can the pilots find out what the failure is?",
    "feedback": "The pilots should check the annunciator panel of the flight warning system"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Machmeter is subject to position error. This error varies according to:",
    "feedback": "TAS and angle of attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time of a strapdown inertial system consists in:",
    "feedback": "measuring the earth rotation and local gravitation to position the reference trihedron"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram representing a right turn with insufficient rudder is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under which of the following conditions is EAS equivalent to TAS?",
    "feedback": "QNH 1013, 15°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "When accelerating on a westerly heading in the northern hemisphere, the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass will turn:",
    "feedback": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gimbal error of the directional gyro is due to the effect of :",
    "feedback": "a bank or pitch attitude of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic heading can be derived from the true heading by means of a :",
    "feedback": "map showing the isogonal lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The float type fuel gauges provide information on:",
    "feedback": "volume with the result that the indication varies with the temperature of the fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "When cruising, the auto-throttle system can be engaged in the following mode(s): \n\nHolding of constant:\n1) TAS\n2) IAS\n3) Mach number\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do some gyro instruments topple when the aircraft is placed in an extreme attitude?",
    "feedback": "because the gimbals reach their limiting stops"
  },
  {
    "question": "Once the self-induced oscillations of a closed-loop system have been identified by the flight crew, positive control of the aircraft can be regained by:\n1) Disconnecting the autopilot2) Establishing a straight and level aircraft attitude3) Trimming the control surfaces of the aircraft to the newly established straight and level attitude4) No manual inputs are to be made. The autopilot brings the aircraft back towards a stabilised condition",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of static blockage, the airspeed indicator:",
    "feedback": "under-reads in climb and over-reads in descent"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a particular position the horizontal and the total strength of the terrestrial magnetic field are the same. This position is",
    "feedback": "At the magnetic equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Ground Proximity Warning System (GPWS) generates the following sound signal or signals when the aircraft is sinking after a take-off or a go-around :",
    "feedback": "DON'T SINK repetitive only"
  },
  {
    "question": "By integrating a flow with respect to time we obtain:",
    "feedback": "a volume or a mass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about computer architecture are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) A multiprocessing configuration is a software solution\n2) A multiprocessing configuration results in more powerful performance than the multitasking method",
    "feedback": "1 is incorrect, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The modulation technique used by the Radio Altimeter is referred to as",
    "feedback": "Frequency Modulated Continuous Wave"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies steadily on a heading 270°. The flight director is engaged in the heading select mode (HDG SEL), heading 270° selected. If a new heading 360° is selected, the vertical trend bar:",
    "feedback": "deviates to the right and will be centered as soon as you roll the aircraft to the bank angle calculated by the flight director."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the principle of operation of the Enhanced Visual System (EVS)?",
    "feedback": "The EVS consists of several infrared cameras mounted to detect wavelengths in the thermal range, providing a real-time image on the PFD or HUD"
  },
  {
    "question": "The software used to run the ATSU applications (ATC and AOC):",
    "feedback": "is certified according to an equipment certification standard (ED12B, DO178B)"
  },
  {
    "question": "During cockpit preparation, the pilots notice that the FMS performance database is incorrect, being for an aircraft with a different engine type. The correct action is:",
    "feedback": "The mechanics must change the database"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compass deviation is defined as the angle between:",
    "feedback": "Magnetic North and Compass North"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a flight director of the command bars type:",
    "feedback": "the horizontal bar is associated with the pitch channel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The components of an autopilot system are the:\n\n1) actuators\n2) mode control panel\n3) EFIS control panel\n4) mode annunciator panel\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) navigation database typically includes the following data:\n1) obstacles2) waypoints3) SID, STAR4) terrain cells5) magnetic variation\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "To allow the coupling of a dual channel flight director:",
    "feedback": "both autopilot channels must be selected ON"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS navigation database is updated (1) ...., loaded (2) ...., and activated (3) .... .",
    "feedback": "(1) manually, (2) manually, (3) manually"
  },
  {
    "question": "ACARS messages may be of the following types:\n\n1) Air Traffic Control (ATC)\n2) Aeronautical Operational Control (AOC)\n3) Airline Administrative Control (AAC)\n4) Air-to-Air Communications (ATAC)\n5) Air-to-Air Data transmission (ATAD)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fuel management performed by most FMS along the flight plan is considered as:",
    "feedback": "a function which helps the crew to estimate the remaining fuel quantity along the flight plan but should not be considered as an accurate and reliable mean."
  },
  {
    "question": "The datalink communications between the aircraft and the ground can be performed by the following system:",
    "feedback": "ACARS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the display of a Boeing 737 aircraft. The subsequent FMA modes until landing, following those indicated in picture 1, are:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following functions of an autopilot are related to aeroplane stabilisation?\n1) Pitch angle hold2) IAS or Mach number hold3) Wings level hold4) VOR radial hold",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The figures presenting a pilot's view of a head-up display (HUD). Which figure contains the information that is required to be displayed on a HUD during cruise flight with the autopilot engaged?",
    "feedback": "Figure 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A MAYDAY datalink message can be sent to the ATC via the:",
    "feedback": "CPDLC application"
  },
  {
    "question": "The turning errors of a direct reading magnetic compass are:",
    "feedback": "maximum at the magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a strap down inertial system the accelerometers are oriented with their axes:",
    "feedback": "along yaw, longitudinal and lateral axis of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inclination of the Earth's magnetic field at the north magnetic pole is equal to:",
    "feedback": "90°"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a flight is performed with a higher \"Cost Index\" at a given mass which of the following will occur?",
    "feedback": "A higher cruise mach number."
  },
  {
    "question": "The ram air temperature (RAT) is defined as:",
    "feedback": "SAT plus the ram rise."
  },
  {
    "question": "While inertial platform system is operating on board an aircraft, it is necessary to use a device with the following characteristics, in order to keep the vertical line with a pendulous system:",
    "feedback": "with damping and a period of about 84 minutes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS provides the following functions:\n\n1- vertical flight plan management \n2- aid for fuel management\n3- lateral flight plan management\n4- terrain awareness and warning\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which FMS guidance modes does the pilot have to engage in order to follow the horizontal path, vertical path and speed profile?",
    "feedback": "LNAV and VNAV"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding loss of the Air Data Computer (ADC):\n1) Built-in test equipment (BITE) will give prompt indication of any malfunction that might occur2) The two types of BITE are Power Up BITE and Continuous BITE",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "During deceleration following a landing in northerly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "no apparent turn."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the TCAS II generates a Resolution Advisory (RA), the associated intruder appears on TCAS display as a:",
    "feedback": "solid red square"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft on a westerly heading on the northern hemisphere accelerates, the effect of the acceleration error causes the magnetic compass to:",
    "feedback": "indicate a turn towards the north"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to its conception, the altimeter measures a:",
    "feedback": "pressure altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "VLO is the maximum :",
    "feedback": "speed at which the landing gear can be operated with full safety."
  },
  {
    "question": "The block diagram of an auto-pilot is shown.\nFor each control channel (pitch, roll and yaw) the piloting law is the relationship between the deflection of the control surface commanded by the computer (BETA c) and the:",
    "feedback": "offset EPSILON at the computer input."
  },
  {
    "question": "Deviation on the standby compass is:",
    "feedback": "dependent on the heading of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Comparing the media used to transmit datalink communications, the appropriate classification from the slowest to the fastest data transmission rate is:",
    "feedback": "HF datalink, VHF datalink, SATCOM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode is selected on the Navigation Display (EHSI)?",
    "feedback": "Expanded NAV mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are typical threats to the autothrust system?\n1) The pilots may lose the sense of energy awareness, e.g. for speed and thrust2) Fluctuating airspeed indications when flying in turbulence and windshear lead to the autothrust overcompensating3) The pilots may need to take sudden corrective action if the correct speed and thrust settings are not used",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Different pressure sensors are used according to the intensity of the pressure measured (low, medium or high)\nClassify the following sensors by order of increasing pressure for which they are suitable :\n\n1) bellows type\n2) Bourdon tube type\n3) aneroid capsule type",
    "feedback": "3,1,2"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the computed aircraft position becomes less accurate, the Enhanced GPWS (EGPWS) function(s) affected is(are):\n\n1) the excessive rate of descent\n2) the terrain display on the navigation display\n3) the flight into terrain when not in landing conditions\n4) the excessive downward deviation from an ILS\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the automatic pitch trim system of a conventionally controlled aeroplane do?",
    "feedback": "It moves the trim to relieve any constant loads on the elevator control"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nQ = charge (Coulombs)\nU = potential difference between the plates (Volt)\n\nThe capacitance C (Farads) is defined as:",
    "feedback": "C = Q /U"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft flight envelope computations is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the amber/yellow colours are associated with the following alert:",
    "feedback": "caution"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot accidently turning OFF the INS in flight, and then turns it back ON a few moments later. Following this incident:",
    "feedback": "it can only be used for attitude reference"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, what is the function of the Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU)?",
    "feedback": "It is a digital circuit that performs basic operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "The heading information originating from the gyromagnetic compass flux valve is sent to the:",
    "feedback": "error detector."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to EASA AIR OPS regulations, the Cockpit Voice Recorder of a 50 seat multi-engined aircraft having been granted the airworthiness certificate after 1st April 1998 will record:  1- the radiotelephonic communications transmitted or received by the cockpit crew 2- the audio environment of the cockpit 3- the cabin attendants communications in the cabin via the interphone 4- the flight crew members communications in the cockpit via the interphone 5- the flight crew members communications in the cockpit via the public address system 6- the audio signals identifiying the navigation or approach aids  The combination regrouping the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,4,5,6"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the final phase of a flight the aircraft is awaiting capture of the ILS localizer. The Flight Director is active. When the localizer has been captured, the amber \"LOC\" light will .......",
    "feedback": "change to a green light"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an automatic landing is interrupted by a go-around :  1- the autothrottle reacts immediately upon the pilot action on the TO/GA (Take-off/Go-around) switch in order to recover the maximum thrust 2- the autopilot monitors the climb and the rotation of the airplane 3- the autopilot retracts the landing gear and reduces the flap deflection in order to reduce the drag 4- the pilot performs the climb and the rotation of the airplane 5- the pilot retracts the landing gear and reduces the flap deflection in order to reduce the drag  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2 and 5."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the northern hemisphere, during a take-off run in a westerly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "an apparent turn to the north"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter is subject to static pressure error. This error varies according to:",
    "feedback": "TAS and angle of attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer from the statements below:",
    "feedback": "GPS altitude cannot be used to replace the reading on the altimeter as GPS altitude is an indication of absolute altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common sensors interfacing a FMS to compute the aircraft position along the flight plan are: 1- MLS 2- GPS 3- VOR 4- IRS The combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2,3,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical speed indicator reads:",
    "feedback": "The differential pressure between the capsule pressure and the case pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The benefit of using a HUD over a PFD is the possibility to maintain a visual lookout, while:\n1) showing storm cells and other aircraft2) monitoring the behaviour and performance of the aircraft3) allowing lower departure and landing minima4) repeating warning type alerts",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb at a constant Mach number below the tropopause in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "IAS and TAS decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a mechanical oil pressure gauge the sensing element is",
    "feedback": "a bourdon tube"
  },
  {
    "question": "The energy required to operate a strapdown inertial system is supplied by:",
    "feedback": "the electrical system"
  },
  {
    "question": "An ring laser gyro can measure:",
    "feedback": "rotation about its sensitive axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the FMS, the cost index is computed by dividing:",
    "feedback": "aircraft operating cost by fuel cost"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane is in steady cruise at flight level 290. The autothrottle maintains a constant Mach number. If the total temperature increases, the calibrated airspeed:",
    "feedback": "remains constant."
  },
  {
    "question": "As you move from a lower to a higher southern magnetic latitude, the characteristics of the terrestrial magnetic field will change:",
    "feedback": "The inclination will increase and the vertical component of the field will increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "In case of radio altimeter failure, the following system(s) is/are affected:",
    "feedback": "Autothrust and EGPWS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The heading read on the dial of a directional gyro is subject to errors, one of which is due to the movement of the aircraft.\nThis error:",
    "feedback": "is dependent on the ground speed of the aircraft, its true track and the average latitude of the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a modern large transport aircraft ....",
    "feedback": "N1 is adjusted automatically as the aircraft climbs"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of an electronic torque meter is:",
    "feedback": "as power is increased, the torque shaft twists"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert(s) associated with the mode 1 (excessive descent rate) of the GPWS is(are):\n\n1) \"TERRAIN\"\n2) \"DON'T SINK\"\n3) \"SINKRATE\"\n4) \"PULL UP\"\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the activation of the take-off warning when a take-off is initiated are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) An aural warning is given when the stabiliser is not in a safe position for take-off\n2) An aural warning is given when the brake pressure is too low",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding to angle of attack (AoA) sensors and displays:\n1) An AoA display may consist of simple light arrays of green, amber and red lights2) Null-seeking (slotted) probes and vane detectors are protected against ice by means of a heater3) The AoA sensors use the stall warning systems as an input only4) An automated stall protection system requires the AoA probes to be fully functioning\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an IRS:",
    "feedback": "accelerometers and platform are both strapped down"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a stabilised platform inertial system, the platform is\n1) Azimuth-controlled to True North2) Azimuth-controlled to Magnetic North3) Gyro-erected during alignment only4) Continuously gyro-erected throughout operation",
    "feedback": "1 and 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic variation at any point on the Earth's surface is the angle:",
    "feedback": "between the horizontal component of the magnetic field and true north direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does an air-driven gyroscope attitude indicator give erroneous indications during acceleration?",
    "feedback": "The erecting system of the instrument displaces the spin axis from the vertical"
  },
  {
    "question": "A rate integrating gyro is a detecting element used in the following:\n1. Inertial attitude unit 2. Automatic pilot 3. Stabilizing servo system 4. Inertial navigation system 5. Rate-of-turn indicator",
    "feedback": "1,4."
  },
  {
    "question": "In transport airplanes, the temperatures are generally measured with :\n\n1- resistance thermometers\n2- thermocouple thermometers\n3- reactance thermometers\n4- capacitance thermometers\n5- mercury thermometers\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "In low altitude radio altimeters, the height measurement (above the ground) is based upon:",
    "feedback": "a frequency modulation wave, for which the frequency variation between the transmitted wave and the received wave after ground reflection is measured."
  },
  {
    "question": "The EAS is obtained from the CAS by correcting for:",
    "feedback": "compressibility error"
  },
  {
    "question": "Apparent drift in a direction indicator is",
    "feedback": "7  1/2°/hour at 30°N and 30°S, and zero at the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ground proximity warning system (GPWS), when mandatorily installed on board an aircraft, must in all cases generate :",
    "feedback": "at least one sound alarm to which a visual alarm can be added"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering the fuel indication given in litres, how much fuel must be added in order to obtain full fuel tanks?",
    "feedback": "72 USG"
  },
  {
    "question": "The relative altitude of the TA intruder is .... and the TA intruder is ....",
    "feedback": "1100 ft above your airplane, climbing at a vertical speed of at least 500 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMC calculates the present position of an aircraft from (among others):\n1) IRS/INS2) DME3) VOR4) Runway threshold position5) Fuel quantity values\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An Aeroplane Condition Monitoring System (ACMS) makes use of aircraft input data and also:",
    "feedback": "A data management unit, a recording unit, and outputs (e.g. a printer or ACARS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the climb, the vertical speed mode (V/S) is selected with a rate of climb of 1500 ft/min. The corresponding autothrottle mode should be ....",
    "feedback": "SPEED to control the airspeed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angular difference between the geographical meridian and the magnetic meridian running through the same position is named",
    "feedback": "Variation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason for usually mounting the detector unit of a remote indicating compass in the wingtip of an aeroplane is to:",
    "feedback": "reduce the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on magnetic variation:",
    "feedback": "The variation is east when True North seems to be located west of Magnetic North"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS may propose the Terrain Look-Ahead Alerting function; this function uses:",
    "feedback": "an electronic map of the world giving ground elevation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cockpit voice recorders shall record the following:",
    "feedback": "All speech and sound in cockpit, signals from radionavigation aids and radio communication."
  },
  {
    "question": "The resultant of the first integration of the output from the east/west accelerometer of an inertial navigation system (INS) in NAV MODE is:",
    "feedback": "velocity along the local parallel of latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS FLIGHT PLAN or LEG page displays the following parameters relative to the flight plan legs or waypoints:\n\n1) aircraft position (Long/Lat)\n2) speed\n3) distance\n4) track\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2,3,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The limits of the white scale of an airspeed indicator are :",
    "feedback": "VSO for the lower limit and VFE for the upper limit"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the LOC mode (holding of localizer axis). The position of the horizontal command bar indicates:\n\n1) the position of the aircraft relative to the localizer axis\n2) the roll attitude of the aircraft\n3) the correction on the bank to be applied to join and follow the localizer axis\n\nthe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What corrections must be applied to indicated airspeed to produce true airspeed?",
    "feedback": "Correction for altitude and temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS is approved  to provide guidance for the following approaches:\n1- RNAV\n2- ILS\n3- MLS\n4- VOR, NDB\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does \"apparent wander\" refer to?",
    "feedback": "The movement of the gyroscopic position about the vertical axis as observed by a person standing on the surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "A transport aircraft is purchased in Australia and flown to Europe where it will be engaged in commercial operations with a base in Germany. It will be necessary to perform a compass swing procedure because:",
    "feedback": "there was a large change of latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deviation applied to magnetic heading gives:",
    "feedback": "compass heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "There is a possibility of triggering spurious TAWS warnings as a result of mismanaging the flight path in the proximity to obstacles"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the magnetic equator, when accelerating after take off on heading west, a direct reading pivot suspended compass:",
    "feedback": "indicates the correct heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a FMS designed with the lateral navigation (LNAV) capability coupled to the autopilot, the FMS lateral command output is:",
    "feedback": "a roll angle or a heading target"
  },
  {
    "question": "To distinguish between an \"armed\" and an \"engaged\" mode on the Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA), the caption....",
    "feedback": "changes in colour or in font size, or becomes surrounded by a box"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the calculation of deviation, the following headings are recorded: MH CH 358 356 091 087 182 186 273 271 Coefficient C is",
    "feedback": "+3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common sensors interfacing a FMS to compute the aircraft position along the flight plan are: 1- DME 2- GPS 3- LOCALIZER 4- NDB The combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a Flight Director is to ....",
    "feedback": "reduce the pilots workload by presenting data in the form of control commands"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Flight Mode Annunciator FMA, the pilot can check:\n1) The engaged and armed modes of the autopilot\n2) The automatic landing capacity\n3) The ACAS mode\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main advantages of the integrated avionics EFB over the portable electronic devices (PED) EFB?\n1) It is usable during any flight phase2) Can be integrated with the aircraft's EFIS3) It is the cheapest EFB option available on the market4) Does not rely on external wires from a socket to be powered5) It is well visible under any lighting conditions6) It can be maintained by the flight crew itself7) It does not need any additional certification from the operator",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5, 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer architecture, the hardware is defined as:",
    "feedback": "the physical components of a computer system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning magnetic compasses, deviation is:",
    "feedback": "The angular difference between magnetic North and compass North."
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper affects:",
    "feedback": "rudder only"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maintaining CAS and flight level flight, a fall in ambient temperature results in:",
    "feedback": "lower True Airspeed (TAS) due to an increase in air density"
  },
  {
    "question": "Waypoints can be entered in an INS memory in different formats.\nIn which of the following formats can waypoints be entered into all INSs?",
    "feedback": "geographic coordinates"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS Required Time of Arrival (RTA) function can provide:",
    "feedback": "a speed target to satisfy a time constraint entered at a flight plan waypoint."
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot may automatically revert to an alternative mode if for example:\n1) There is no suitable data for the currently engaged mode2) There is a change in the altitude target when the ALT ACQ mode is inactive3) A mode is mismanaged to the extent that it results in the engagement of the autopilot envelope protection function4) When, as an example, an excessive V/S is selected that would otherwise result in a loss of speed control\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The azimuth gyro of an inertial unit has a drift of 0.01°/HR. After a flight of 12 HR with a ground speed of 500 kt, the error on the aeroplane position is approximately :",
    "feedback": "6 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "A FMS can correct its fuel computations for the following non-standard configurations:\n1) Landing gear down\n2) Speed brakes extended\n3) One engine out\n4) Slats/flaps not fully retracted\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a Category II automatic approach, the height information is supplied by the :",
    "feedback": "radio altimeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the ND, the TCAS generates the intruder aircraft symbol represented below. The correct intruder vertical information is:",
    "feedback": "level at your altitude, associated with a resolution advisory (RA)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) present position (lat, long)\n2) total pressure\n3) static air temperature\n4) true heading\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Failure of the electrical supply to an electrically driven direction indicator may be\nindicated by:",
    "feedback": "A red warning flag."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft fuel flow parameters are stored in the:",
    "feedback": "performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position error of a stand alone inertial system:",
    "feedback": "increases along the time"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main benefit of the HUD?",
    "feedback": "It reduces errors caused by the transition from instrument to visual flight, decreases the minimas for both take-off and landing, and reduces the risk of aircraft upsets"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engine instrument utilising an aneroid pressure diaphragm is the:",
    "feedback": "manifold pressure gauge"
  },
  {
    "question": "For most FMS the fuel prediction function, which computes the remaining fuel along the flight plan, takes into account the following situations: 1) The additional drag resulting in a flight carried out with the landing gear extended 2) The additional drag resulting in a missing fuselage or wing element in compliance with the CDL 3) The additional drag resulting in a flight carried out with the flaps stucked, partly extended 4) The current wind computed or the resulting ground speed  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A CVR consists of ......",
    "feedback": "a tape recorder, underwater locating device, area microphone, and control unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic heading can be derived from the true heading by means of a :",
    "feedback": "map showing the isogonal lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The input signal of the amplifier of the gyromagnetic compass resetting device originates from the:",
    "feedback": "error detector."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the properties of a simple bar magnet are correct or incorrect?\n1) North or south poles cannot exist separately\n2) Magnetism is concentrated at the extremities of the bar",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In northern hemisphere, during an acceleration in an easterly direction, the magnetic compass will indicate:",
    "feedback": "a decrease in heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a modern airplane equipped with an ECAM (Electronic centralized aircraft monitor), when a failure occurs in a circuit, the centralized flight management system:  1- releases an aural warning 2- lights up the appropriate push-buttons on the overhead panel 3- displays the relevant circuit on the system display 4- processes the failure automatically  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a FMS, MCDUs are used pre-flight to manually initialise with dispatch information the:\n\n1) Inertial Reference System (when installed)\n2) Flight Director and Auto Flight Control System\n3) Air Data Computer\n4) Flight Management Computer\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Torque can be determined by measuring the :",
    "feedback": "oil pressure at the fixed crown of an epicycloidal reducer of the main engine gearbox."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the altitude alert system is to generate a visual and aural warning to the pilot when the:",
    "feedback": "airplane altitude differs from a selected altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS is able to detect:\n\n1) excessive descent rate\n2) excessive terrain closing rate\n3) excessive angle of attack\n4) excessive descent pitch attitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stall warning computer of a large aeroplane uses the following data:\n\n1) pitch attitude\n2) angle of attack\n3) configuration (slats/flaps)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"close traffic advisory\" is displayed on the display device of the TCAS 2 (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) by :",
    "feedback": "a yellow full circle."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nMach number M = 0.70\nMeasured impact temperature = -48°C\nThe recovery factor (Kr) of the temperature probe = 0.85\n\nThe OAT is:",
    "feedback": "-65°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "If, when correcting an EAS value of 150 Kt, a TAS value of 146 Kt is obtained:",
    "feedback": "the density of the atmosphere must be greater than the ISA mean sea level air density."
  },
  {
    "question": "An air data computer\n\n1) supplies the ground speed and the drift angle\n2) determines the total temperature and the true altitude\n3) receives the static pressure and the total pressure\n4) supplies the TAS to the computer of the INS\n5) determines the Mach number, the outside (static) air temperature\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the operating system used for an on-board documentation (charts and company information):",
    "feedback": "there are no certification requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an occasion for carrying out a compass swing on a Direct Reading Compass?",
    "feedback": "After an aircraft has passed through a severe electrical storm, or has been struck by lightning"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an aircraft flying a true track of 360° between the 005°S and 005°N parallels, the precession error of the directional gyro due to apparent drift is equal to:",
    "feedback": "approximately 0°/hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to the rotation of the earth, the apparent drift of a horizontal free gyroscope at a latitude of 30°S is:",
    "feedback": "7.5°/hour to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if in a dual FMS architecture, one of the FMS fails?",
    "feedback": "Redundancy is lost, the operative FMS will fully take over"
  },
  {
    "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the left and the ball on the right, the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "turning left with not enough bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the following display, the .... is indicated by a white empty diamond.",
    "feedback": "other intruder"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane is in steady cruise at flight level 290. The autothrottle maintains a constant Mach number. If the total temperature decreases, the calibrated airspeed:",
    "feedback": "remains constant."
  },
  {
    "question": "An electromagnet is a type of magnet in which:",
    "feedback": "the magnetic field is produced by the flow of an electric current"
  },
  {
    "question": "A magnetic tachometer consists of:",
    "feedback": "a permanent magnet turning inside a non magnetic drag cup"
  },
  {
    "question": "On modern passenger aircraft, the navigation data base usually contains:",
    "feedback": "airport reference data"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb at a constant IAS below the tropopause in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "the Mach number and the TAS increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, an example of a storage peripheral is a:",
    "feedback": "hard disk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Some types of RPM indicators (Tachometers) require electrical power to provide an indication"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which parameter will be lost when the air data computer fails?",
    "feedback": "Wind direction and speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "All the last generation aircraft use flight control systems. The Flight Management System (FMS) is the most advanced system ; it can be defined as a:",
    "feedback": "global 3-D Flight Management System"
  },
  {
    "question": "The turning error of a direct reading magnetic compass:",
    "feedback": "increases when the magnetic latitude increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sensitivity of a direct reading compass varies:",
    "feedback": "directly with the horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "Vibration is indicated in the cockpit as:",
    "feedback": "a direct reading."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a manifold pressure gauge consistently registers atmospheric pressure, the cause is probably;",
    "feedback": "leak in pressure gauge line."
  },
  {
    "question": "On what heading is the aircraft currently flying?",
    "feedback": "125°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Engine speed is most commonly displayed as a:",
    "feedback": "percentage of a maximum engine speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The atmospheric pressure at FL 70 in a \"standard + 10\" atmosphere is:",
    "feedback": "781.85 hPa."
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 2 is showing:",
    "feedback": "a 20° left bank and 18° nose down attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "A basic computer (\"Von Neumann architecture\" type) uses:",
    "feedback": "a processing unit and a single storage structure to hold both instructions and data"
  },
  {
    "question": "TAS is equal to:",
    "feedback": "IAS corrected for instrument, position, compressibility and density errors"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to know in which mode the auto throttles are engaged, the crew will check the:",
    "feedback": "FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The crew is flying a heading assigned by ATC, 20 NM to the left and parallel to the planned route, for weather avoidance. Just after the weather is passed, ATC clears the flight on the flight planned route. The lateral navigation mode is set and the Pilot Monitoring (PM) reads on the Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA) that the navigation mode is armed.\nWhat will the aircraft do when it arrives abeam the right turn at the next waypoint on the Flight Management Computer (FMC) flight plan?",
    "feedback": "It will continue on the current heading, unless a heading intercepting the flight plan has been set by the pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are pages of the ECAM secondary display?\n1) engine2) fire3) trim4) hyd5) wheel6) cruise",
    "feedback": "1, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The apparent wander of a directional gyro is 15°/h:",
    "feedback": "at the north pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the display of a TCAS II, the traffic being the cause of a resolution advisory is represented by:",
    "feedback": "red full square."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the air-tight instrument case of the airspeed indicator we will find:",
    "feedback": "Static pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The accuracy of the altitude computed by a stand alone inertial system:",
    "feedback": "decreases exponentially with flight time"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data calculated by the ADC are:\n\n1) Attitude\n2) Pressure altitude\n3) TAT\n4) TAS\n5) CAS\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a typical order for an FMS pre-flight set-up process through the CDU/MCDU?",
    "feedback": "IDENT page - position initialisation - route initialisation - route programming - performance initialisation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of capacity gauges is based on the:",
    "feedback": "capacitance variation of a given capacitor with the type of dielectric."
  },
  {
    "question": "The voice recorder records on four different channels the following information:\n\n1- aural warnings\n2- radio communications\n3- conversations between the crew members through the cockpit interphone\n4- announcements to the passengers\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS navigation database processing should include the following check(s):",
    "feedback": "at each phase of the process, from the reception of each supplier's data to the distribution and loading of the formatted database."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft travels from point A to point B, using the autopilot connected to the aircraft's inertial system. The coordinates of A (45°S 010°W) and B (45°S 030°W) have been entered.\nThe true course of the aircraft on its arrival at B, to the nearest degree, is:",
    "feedback": "277°"
  },
  {
    "question": "After a failure, what is an appropriate procedure in the correct order for following an on-screen checklist?\n1) Confirm the failure2) Check the status of the FWS3) Follow the checklist slowly and methodically4) Seek confirmation prior to manipulating any guarded switches5) Assess the possible implications of making certain selections",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the Flight Director System (FDS) modes, which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "The modes available for the FDS are the same as those available for the autopilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "At a given altitude, the hysteresis error of an altimeter varies substantially with the:",
    "feedback": "time passed at this altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "A control system consisting of four pendulous vanes is used in:",
    "feedback": "an air driven artificial horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reactive wind shear aural warning sounds in the cockpit and is displayed on the PFD. Can you expect it to be displayed on the HUD as well?",
    "feedback": "Yes, the normal display mode will automatically display indications according to each phase of the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "A vibration indicator receives a signal from different sensors (accelerometers). It indicates the :",
    "feedback": "vibration amplitude at a given frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Mach number?",
    "feedback": "It is the ratio of the aircraft's true airspeed to the local speed of sound of the air in \nwhich the aircraft is moving."
  },
  {
    "question": "The direct reading magnetic compass is no more reliable when approaching:\n\n1) the magnetic poles\n2) the magnetic equator with a east or west heading\n3) the magnetic equator with north or south heading\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "With respect to an autopilot, what does the term \"self-induced oscillation\" refer to?",
    "feedback": "Oscillation caused by erroneous autopilot systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "feedback": "The two types of angle of attack (AoA) sensors are the null-seeking (slotted) probe and the vane detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to CS 25, the definition of the control wheel steering mode (CWS) is:\n\"Where the pilot has the ability to make inputs to the:",
    "feedback": "automatic pilot by movement of the normal control wheel\""
  },
  {
    "question": "The input data to the GPWS originate from the:\n\n1) transponder\n2) angle of attack sensor\n3) auto-throttle system\n4) ADC\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Check the following answers regarding the angle of attack (AoA) probes:\n1) Only the null-seeking (slotted) probe contains a heating function2) Air-data computers, stall warning systems and flight-envelope protection systems use the AoA as an input",
    "feedback": "1) is not correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nPt = total pressure\nPs = static pressure\nPd = dynamic pressure\n\nThe airspeed indicator is fed by:",
    "feedback": "Pd"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the alignment of the direct reading magnetic compass:",
    "feedback": "The magnetic compass aligns itself to both the horizontal (azimuth) and vertical (dip) components of the Earth's magnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output from an engine vibration transducer is:",
    "feedback": "always filtered to remove unwanted frequencies."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the pitot tube ices up during a flight, the affected equipment(s) is(are):\n\n1) the altimeter\n2) the variometer\n3) the airspeed indicator\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical command bar of a flight director:\n\n1) repeats the position information given by the EHSI\n2) repeats the position information given by the VOR\n3) gives information about the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to be applied.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the statements concerning a Synthetic Vision System (SVS) is correct? The SVS .....",
    "feedback": "solely uses data from a predefined fixed database to create a synthetic vision representation of the surroundings of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of a conflict, the TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) will give information such as :",
    "feedback": "climb/descent"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TAS is equal to the EAS only if:",
    "feedback": "P = 1013.25 hPa and OAT = 15°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The different types of ADS contracts can be:\n\n1) periodic: at periodic time intervals\n2) on demand: when asked for by the ATC\n3) on event: whenever a specified event occurs\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "While flying, a red flag labelled \"HDG\" appears in the indicator (HSI) of a Slaved Gyro Compass System.  This indicates that:",
    "feedback": "The flux valve is not supplying reliable information to the compass system."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressure of 6000 psi equals to approximately:",
    "feedback": "400 bar"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Primary Flight Display (PFD) displays information dedicated to:",
    "feedback": "piloting."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Flight Data Recorder (FDR) is to record specific parameters such as: 1) Time 2) Attitude 3) Airspeed 4) Flaps/slats configuration or cockpit selection  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The disadvantages of a float type fuel gauge are\n\n1) the design is complex\n2) the indications are influenced by the aircraft attitude variations\n3) the indications are influenced by the accelerations \n4) the indications are influenced by temperature variations\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the absence of position and instrument errors, CAS is equal to:",
    "feedback": "IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of capacitor gauges is based on:",
    "feedback": "the variation in capacity of a condensor with the nature of the dielectric"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is in steady climb. The autothrottle maintains a constant calibrated airspeed. If the total temperature remains constant, the Mach number :",
    "feedback": "increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in level flight at FL100 over a mountain range, which extends up to 2.400 metres AMSL. If the regional QNH is 998 hPa (use 30 ft/hPa), what is the approximate terrain clearance?",
    "feedback": "1.681 feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "The essential components of a flight director are :\n\n1) a computer\n2) an automatic pilot\n3) an auto-throttle\n4) command bars\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auto throttle engaged mode can be checked by the pilot, using:",
    "feedback": "Primary flight display"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS navigation data base usually contains:\n\n1) airport reference data\n2) ATC frequencies \n3) Company routes \n4) Nav. Aid frequencies \n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3 and 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Airspeed Indicator measures:",
    "feedback": "Differential pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The white sector of the arc of a temperature gauge corresponds to:",
    "feedback": "a special operating range."
  },
  {
    "question": "In aircraft fitted with IRS and FMS, the flight management computer (FMC) postion is normally derived from:\n1) Mathematical analysis of IRS2) GPS3) DME4) ADF5) VOR6) LOC",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight envelope protection system prevents the aircraft from exceeding the limits of the following parameters:\n\n1) N1\n2) angle of attack\n3) speed\n4) pitch attitude\n5) flight level\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What could be done if the flight crew cannot access the approach charts application in case of total EFB failure?",
    "feedback": "Most of the data could be asked to ATC, however, operator minimums and other data would not be provided"
  },
  {
    "question": "The characteristics of the Earth which are being used during the alignment of an INS platform are:",
    "feedback": "Earth rotation and gravity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is provided by the autotune function of the FMS? Automatic switching of:",
    "feedback": "Radio navigation frequencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "What could be the best backup to the EFB performance application/software, should it fail in flight?",
    "feedback": "Paper Quick Reference Handbook (QRH)"
  },
  {
    "question": "VLE is the maximum :",
    "feedback": "flight speed with landing gear down"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position error of a stand alone inertial system is:",
    "feedback": "small a few minutes after initialisation and increases along the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The probe used to measure the air intake pressure of a gas turbine engined powerplant is:",
    "feedback": "an aneroid capsule."
  },
  {
    "question": "The fields affecting a magnetic compass originate from:\n1. magnetic masses\n2. ferrous metal masses\n3. non ferrous metal masses\n4. electrical currents\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airborne instrument, equipped with a gyro with 1 degree of freedom and a horizontal spin axis is a:\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "turn indicator"
  },
  {
    "question": "When two waypoints are entered on the FMS flight plan page, a track between the two fixes is computed and can be displayed on the Navigation map display (ND). This leg created is:",
    "feedback": "a great circle arc."
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight data recorder must automatically stop data recording when the:",
    "feedback": "airplane cannot any longer move by its own power."
  },
  {
    "question": "ATT Mode of the Inertial Reference System (IRS) is a back-up mode providing:",
    "feedback": "only attitude and heading information"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is a TAWS working, i.e. receiving its signals in general?",
    "feedback": "By, among others, using a three dimensional map of the world and the radio altimeter to detect, if any terrain coincides with the flight path"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft and an intruding traffic are TCAS II equipped. Your TCAS can generate:",
    "feedback": "coordinated resolution advisories"
  },
  {
    "question": "To obtain the instantaneous position from the acceleration, it is necessary to:\n\n1) integrate twice the acceleration in time\n2) know the initial position\n3) know the initial speed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Mach trim system is to counteract:",
    "feedback": "The pitch down tendency at high Mach number"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment of a gyro stabilised inertial platform consists in positioning the platform relative to:",
    "feedback": "the vertical axis and true north"
  },
  {
    "question": "When, in flight, the needle and ball of a needle-and-ball indicator are on the left, the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "turning left with too much bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is flying at FL 140 with a CAS of 260 kts in standard conditions. The Mach number is:",
    "feedback": "0.51"
  },
  {
    "question": "At a constant calibrated airspeed (CAS), the Mach number :",
    "feedback": "increases when the altitude increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is \"unreliable airspeed\"?",
    "feedback": "Airspeed indications affected by pitot/static system errors, but without triggering a warning and being automatically removed from displays and computations"
  },
  {
    "question": "The mode selector of an inertial unit comprises the OFF - STBY - ALIGN - NAV - ATT positions:\n\n1) on STBY, the unit aligns on the local geographic trihedron\n2) the ATT position is used in automatic landing (mode LAND)\n3) on NAV the coordinates of the start position can be entered\n4) the platform is levelled before azimuth alignment\n5) in cruise, the unit can only be used in NAV mode\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A line of magnetic latitude on the earth is a line joining points of equal:",
    "feedback": "dip"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the effect of turning errors on a direct reading compass?",
    "feedback": "Turning errors are greatest on north/south headings, and are greatest at high latitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aircraft, only the INS/IRS and the TAS are available. Can the pilot check the wind speed and direction on the instruments?",
    "feedback": "Yes, because the INS/IRS uses the TAS to determine the W/V and display it on the ND"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do you disconnect the autopilot in an aircraft fitted with a sidestick?\n1) Push or pull the sidestick hard2) Via the A/P button on the glareshield3) Pressing the takeover pushbutton4) Moving the thrust levers",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Ground Proximity Warning System (GPWS) is a system working according to a height span ranging from :",
    "feedback": "50 ft to 2 500 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Before starting INS alignment the pilot has accidentally provided the system with the incorrect latitude. What is likely to happen?",
    "feedback": "The system will gradually lose its alignment, as the calculated drift due to Earth rotation will be wrong"
  },
  {
    "question": "Total air pressure consists of static pressure plus:",
    "feedback": "Dynamic pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the deviation table of a Direct Reading Compass below.   The desired True Heading is 155°. The variation in the area is 10°W. What should be the indication for the Direct Reading Compass?",
    "feedback": "164°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter is subject to the position error; this error varies substantially with the:",
    "feedback": "Mach number"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements concerning the principle, features and limitations of a Synthetic Vision System (SVS) are correct/incorrect?\n1) The synthetic vision displayed on the PFD is based on actual sensory information coming from external sensors\n2) An accurate aircraft position is needed for the SVS to produce a synthetic vision representation on the PFD",
    "feedback": "(1) is incorrect, (2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper system acts on:",
    "feedback": "the rudder only"
  },
  {
    "question": "The command functions of an autopilot include, among others, the holding of :\n\n1- vertical speed\n2- altitude\n3- attitude\n4- bank\n5- heading\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1 - 2 - 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "When climbing at a constant Mach number:",
    "feedback": "CAS decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert(s) associated with the mode 5 (excessive deviation below glide slope) of the GPWS is(are):\n\n1) \"TERRAIN\"\n2) \"TOO LOW GLIDESLOPE\"\n3) \"GLIDESLOPE\"\n4) \"PULL UP\"\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS navigation database includes the following data: 1- obstacles 2- navaids 3- SID, STAR and approaches procedures 4- waypoints 5- airways  The combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2,3,4,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position of a Flight Director command bar:",
    "feedback": "indicates the manoeuvers to execute, to achieve or maintain a flight situation."
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a fail-operational hybrid automatic landing system:\n1) It is a primary fail-passive autoland system with an additional guidance, independent from the fail-passive autoland system2) The head-up display (HUD) is an example of an independent guidance system3) If a failure of the primary system occurs, the flight crew is able to complete an automatic landing\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a Cockpit Voice Recorder is to ......",
    "feedback": "preserve, in the event of an accident, vital audio information that is recoverable for use by accident investigators"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the following display, the .... is indicated by a yellow circle.",
    "feedback": "TA intruder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following the entry of a starting position, an inertial navigation system provides continuous information on the aircraft's position by measuring the (1) .... in the vertical, horizontal, and lateral planes. A first integration over time gives the change in (2) ...., a second integration over time gives the (3) .... .",
    "feedback": "(1) acceleration, (2) velocity, (3) distance travelled"
  },
  {
    "question": "The density altitude is :",
    "feedback": "the altitude of the standard atmosphere on which the density is equal to the actual density of the atmosphere"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of an electrical induction tachometer are:\n\n1- the display is not sensitive to line resistance\n2- the measurement is independent of aircraft power supply\n3- the measurement is independent of temperature variations\n4- the option to use without restriction several indicators connected in parallel to a single transmitter\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct or incorrect with regard to Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA) monitoring?\n1) The altitude capture mode is a operationally relevant mode that requires positive annunciation2) Transition from capturing to tracking the ILS localizer is operationally relevant and requires positive annunciation",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isogonic lines connect positions that have:",
    "feedback": "the same variation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS provides the following functions:\n\n1) fuel management\n2) lateral flight plan management\n3) check-list completion\n4) aircraft position computation\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An autopilot capable of holding at least altitude and heading mode is compulsory:",
    "feedback": "for IFR or night flights with only one pilot."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS Flight Plan, Navigation, Progress or Leg page generally displays the following parameters relative to the flight plan legs or waypoints:\n1- track\n2- magnetic variation\n3- waypoint elevation\n4- time prediction\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lines on the earth's surface that join points of equal magnetic variation are called:",
    "feedback": "isogonals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about temperature are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) -273° Celsius = 0 Kelvin\n2) 52° Fahrenheit = 21° Celsius",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Primary Flight Display (PFD) of an EFIS equipped aircraft displays the following parameters:\n1) auto-throttle modes\n2) attitude\n3) vertical speed\n4) flight director command bars\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 4 is showing:",
    "feedback": "a 40° left bank and 15° nose up attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The directive force:",
    "feedback": "is the component of the earth's magnetic field which aligns the compass needle"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the outside temperature at 25 000 feet is -28°C, the local speed of sound is :",
    "feedback": "610 kts"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main advantage of a remote indicating compass over a direct reading compass is that it:",
    "feedback": "senses, rather than seeks, the magnetic meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "TAS is equal to:",
    "feedback": "EAS corrected for density error"
  },
  {
    "question": "What indications are received of an ECAM failure?",
    "feedback": "Light only"
  },
  {
    "question": "If indicated airspeed is corrected for a positive error, the resulting calibrated airspeed will be:",
    "feedback": "Lower."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FANS concept involves implementation of datalink systems for use in:",
    "feedback": "all of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the operation of an  Inertial Navigation System (INS)/Inertial Reference System (IRS) is correct?",
    "feedback": "NAV mode must be selected prior to movement of the aircraft off the gate"
  },
  {
    "question": "The full alignment of the stable platform of an Inertial Navigation System:",
    "feedback": "is only possible on the ground when the aircraft is at a complete stop"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gyroscrope or gyro is a fast rotating object ......",
    "feedback": "with its mass evenly distributed around its spin axis, and gimballed in one or two frames"
  },
  {
    "question": "The characteristics of the Random Access Memory (RAM) are:\n\n1) rapid access\n2) read and write access\n3) volatile type\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to the rotation of the earth, the apparent drift of a horizontal free gyroscope at a latitude of 45°N is:",
    "feedback": "11°/hour to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Without any external action, the axis of a free gyroscope is fixed with reference to:",
    "feedback": "space"
  },
  {
    "question": "The type of sensor which is typically used for temperature measurements up to 500° C is:",
    "feedback": "A temperature dependent resistor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The annunciator of a remote indicating compass system is used when:",
    "feedback": "synchronising the magnetic and gyro compass elements"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term drift refers to the wander of the axis of a gyro in:",
    "feedback": "the horizontal plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "A float type fuel gauge:\n\n1) gives a mass information\n2) gives information independent of aircraft's manoeuvres and attitude changes\n3) gives information all the more accurate as the tank is full\n4) is typically a DC powered system\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an CDU/MCDU:\n1) The scratchpad is the bottom portion of the MCDU screen where the flight crew can input information about the flight that is to be be conducted2) The information entered in the scratchpad can not be manipulated by the system keys that follow3) The CDU/MCDU comprise a cathode ray tube (CRT) display on which different pages of selected data can be shown4) The CDU can not be used to command completely automatic control of the aircraft\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The upper antenna of the TCAS II is:",
    "feedback": "directional and separate from the transponder antenna"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, which of these statements about multitasking are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) Multitasking gives the appearance of running several programs simultaneously\n2) The Central Processing Unit (CPU) switches rapidly between each programme in turn",
    "feedback": "1 is correct, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The direct reading magnetic compass is made aperiodic (dead beat) by:",
    "feedback": "keeping the magnetic assembly mass close to the compass point and by using damping wires"
  },
  {
    "question": "An on-screen (electronic) checklist is associated with a failure scenario and commands a certain action:",
    "feedback": "The failure must be confirmed and acknowledged by both flight crew members prior to performing any of the actions"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stall warning system of a large transport aeroplane includes:\n\n1) an angle of attack sensor \n2) a computer\n3) an independent pitot probe\n4) a transmitter of the flap/slat position indicating system\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft closed-loop control system comprises:\n1) Attitude sensor2) Transducer3) Transponder4) Signal processor5) Servomotor",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The auto-throttle:\n\n1) can capture and maintain the N1 RPM\n2) can capture and maintain the N2 RPM\n3) can capture and maintain an IAS\n4) is always engaged automatically at the same time as the autopilot\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the properties of a simple bar magnet are correct or incorrect?\n1) North or south poles can exist separately\n2) Magnetism is concentrated at the extremities of the bar",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment phase of a gyro stabilised platform consists in:",
    "feedback": "levelling the platform and determining its orientation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main cause of precession?",
    "feedback": "Bearing friction."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at an TAS of 310 Kt at FL290, temperature deviation is -6º C.\nThe local speed of sound is:",
    "feedback": "583 Kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a twin-engined aeroplane, the synchroscope uses the following principle:",
    "feedback": "it measures the frequency difference between the two engine driven alternators"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC (Full Authority Digital Engine Control) provides:\n\n1) thrust reverser control\n2) engine operation within safe limits\n3) automatic engine starting sequence\n4) automatic thrust rating control\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft experiences a power failure of the inertial system during flight and as a result, alignment is lost with subsequent los of the (1) .... data, but with the (2) .... information still available. The pilot (3) .... perform in-flight re-alignment",
    "feedback": "(1) navigation, (2) attitude, (3) cannot"
  },
  {
    "question": "During FMS pre-flight preparation, you notice that the aircraft performance database is based on the wrong aeroplane and engine configuration. Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Engineering must be notified, as flight crew cannot make any modifications to the database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical command bar of a flight director:",
    "feedback": "gives information about the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to be applied on the bank of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The validity period of the \"permanent\" data base of aeronautical information stores in the database of a FMS is:",
    "feedback": "28 days"
  },
  {
    "question": "After alignment of the stable platform of an Inertial Navigation System, the output data from the platform is:",
    "feedback": "acceleration north/south and east/west, attitude and true heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under normal conditions, in a dual FMS architecture, the master FMC sends its commands to the: (FMC=Flight Management Computer)",
    "feedback": "autopilot, flight director and autothrottle"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) computer receives information :\n\n1- about the pressure altitude through the mode S transponder\n2- from the radio-altimeter\n3- specific to the airplane configuration\n4- from the inertial units\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a flight director of the command bars type:",
    "feedback": "the vertical bar is associated with the roll channel"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane is in steady cruise at FL 290. The autothrottle maintains a constant Mach number. If the total temperature decreases, the calibrated airspeed:",
    "feedback": "remains constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "As an airplane climbs higher, the true airspeed for a given indicated airspeed will:",
    "feedback": "Increase."
  },
  {
    "question": "The total pressure head comprises a mast which moves its port to a distance from aircraft skin in order:",
    "feedback": "to locate it outside the boundary layer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the fuel mass unit is correct?",
    "feedback": "1 t = 2200 lb"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter is supplied by :",
    "feedback": "static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What flight protection limits does the auto throttle have?",
    "feedback": "Current thrust limit"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb at a constant Mach number below the tropopause in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "CAS and TAS decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "The total air temperature (TAT) is:",
    "feedback": "higher or equal than Static Air Temperature (SAT); TAT is a function of Mach number and SAT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the IVSI is to",
    "feedback": "give an instantaneous indication of the aircraft's vertical speed when a climb or descent has been initiated."
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, an example of an input peripheral is a:",
    "feedback": "keyboard"
  },
  {
    "question": "An Inertial Navigation System can:",
    "feedback": "operate as stand alone equipment without any interface with other navigation equipments"
  },
  {
    "question": "In standard atmosphere, when descending at constant CAS:",
    "feedback": "TAS decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter indicates 17000 ft, altimeter setting 1013,25 hPa. The local QNH is 1003 hPa and the OAT -3°C.\n\nWhat is the pressure altitude?",
    "feedback": "17000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Primary Flight Display (PFD) of an EFIS equipped aircraft displays the following parameters:",
    "feedback": "IAS, attitude, altitude, heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "When disengaging the autopilot, the function providing a smooth \"hand-over\" is the:",
    "feedback": "automatic pitch trim function"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft is TCAS II equipped; an intruding traffic only has a mode A transponder. The information available to your TCAS equipment is:",
    "feedback": "two dimensional only; your TCAS cannot generate RAs (Resolution Advisories)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the yellow colour on an EGPWS display refer to?",
    "feedback": "Terrain is 500 ft below to 1000 ft above the aircraft altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a stabilised platform inertial system, this platform:\n\n1) can be servo-controlled in azimuth\n2) is kept levelled during alignment phase only\n3) is always kept levelled\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the CH = 220°, var. = E12, dev. = W2, what is the corresponding TH?",
    "feedback": "TH = 230°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about temperature are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) 15° Celsius = 288° Kelvin\n2) 15° Celsius = 59° Fahrenheit",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ADS is a FANS application which consists in:",
    "feedback": "sending automatically aircraft surveillance data to the air traffic controller"
  },
  {
    "question": "When using the autopilot, the function of the pitch channel automatic trim is to:\n\n1- cancel the hinge moment of the elevator\n2- ease as much as possible the load of the servo-actuator \n3- restore to the pilot a correctly trimmed airplane during the autopilot disengagement \n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2 and 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "Flying manually during a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the LOC mode (holding of localizer axis). If the aircraft is right of the localizer axis, the vertical command bar:",
    "feedback": "may be centered if the pilot is correcting to come back on the localizer axis."
  },
  {
    "question": "The lateral flight path modes of an autopilot system are:\n\n1) heading hold\n2) speed hold\n3) FMS lateral navigation\n4) TAS hold\n5) localizer intercept and track\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The static air temperature (SAT) is :",
    "feedback": "a relative temperature expressed in degrees Celsius"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the tanks of your airplane only contain water, the capacitor gauges indicate:",
    "feedback": "a mass of water different from zero, but inaccurate."
  },
  {
    "question": "The value of magnetic variation:",
    "feedback": "has a maximum of 180°"
  },
  {
    "question": "When climbing at a constant Mach number through an isothermal layer, the CAS:",
    "feedback": "decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer architecture, the software is defined as:",
    "feedback": "a collection of computer programs"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS cross track error (XTK) is:",
    "feedback": "The abeam distance error, to the left or right from the desired flight plan leg to the aircraft position"
  },
  {
    "question": "Changes in temperature of the fuel affect its density, volume and dielectric value Er. An increase in temperature causes:",
    "feedback": "a increase in volume, decrease in density and decrease in Er"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the EASA AIR OPS regulations, the Cockpit Voice Recorder of a 30 seat multi-engined aircraft, having been granted an airworthiness certificate after 1st April 1998, shall start recording:",
    "feedback": "Automatically prior to the aircraft moving under its own power until flight competion when the aircraft is no longer able to move under its own power"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which instrument does not connect to the static system?",
    "feedback": "Vacuum gauge."
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot pitch channel has a fixed pitch target for the mode combinations MCP SPD and ALT HOLD, MCP SPD and VSP (climb), or MCP SPD and VSP (descent), while the autothrust controls speed:\n1) The autopilot is prevented from exceeding pitch attitudes that will result in speeds that are not within the flight envelope of the aircraft2) The autothrust system is prevented from exceeding thrust and speed limits displayed on the MCP if they are not within the flight envelope of the aircraft3) Below 400 ft RA, the A/T thrust response rates and engine power levels are not sufficient to place the engines in the rapid acceleration range\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Electrical requirements for an alumel/chromel indicating system are:",
    "feedback": "power for gauge lighting only."
  },
  {
    "question": "When the autopilot is engaged, the role of the automatic trim is to:",
    "feedback": "relieve the A.P. servo motor and return the aircraft in-trim at A.P. disconnect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding an Inertial Navigation System:\n1) In-flight realignment is not possible and loss of alignment leads to loss of navigational data. Attitude information may still be available2) An incorrect entry of latitude may lead to a loss of alignment and is less critical than the incorrect entry of longitude",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The navigational database of the FMS:",
    "feedback": "Contains some additional space so that the crew may create navigational data"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an autocoupled ILS approach followed by an automatic landing, the guidance signals in the vertical plane under 200 ft are computed according to the:",
    "feedback": "radio altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are the flight director modes displayed?",
    "feedback": "PFD"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct explanation on how is speed controlled in an automatic thrust control system?",
    "feedback": "In certain mode combinations, autothrust controls speed and the autopilot pitch channel has a fixed pitch target"
  },
  {
    "question": "The higher the airspeed is:",
    "feedback": "The higher the bank angle must be to turn at the standard rate."
  },
  {
    "question": "When side-slipping, one of the instruments below will give an incorrect indication:",
    "feedback": "Airspeed Indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "After alignment, is is possible to update the IRS positions?",
    "feedback": "No"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Central Processing Unit (CPU) of a computer essentially consists of:\n\n1) an Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU)\n2) a control and timing unit\n3) registers\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main characteristic of the combiner in a HUD system?",
    "feedback": "It is made of multi-layered plastic material, creating a holographic effect for improved vision"
  },
  {
    "question": "The autothrust system protects the flight envelope by:",
    "feedback": "Reversion modes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight data recorder must start data recording automatically:",
    "feedback": "before the airplane is able to move by under its own power."
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS automatically provides distinctive warning to the flight crew in case of:\n\n1) impeding stall\n2) excessive descent rate\n3) altitude loss after take-off or go-around\n4) unsafe terrain clearance with abnormal gear/flaps configuration\n5) dangerous ground proximity\n6) downward glide-slope deviation\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ADC fails, which of the following instruments related to the pitot-static system are affected?\n1) Air Speed Indicator2) Vertical Speed Indicator3) Altimeter4) Attitude Indicator",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "If OAT increases whilst maintaining a constant CAS and flight level:",
    "feedback": "Mach number remains constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stall warning system receives information about the :\n\n1- airplane angle of attack\n2- airplane speed\n3- airplane bank angle\n4- airplane configuration\n5- load factor on the airplane\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The control law of an autopilot control channel may be defined  as the relationship between the:",
    "feedback": "computer input deviation data and the output control deflection signals"
  },
  {
    "question": "When only one autopilot is used for climbing, cruising and approach, the system is considered:",
    "feedback": "\"fail passive\" or without failure effect but with disconnection."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMC database is divided into two broad sections, namely",
    "feedback": "The Navigation database and the Performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the FMS aircraft database updated?",
    "feedback": "After an FMS software update"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft and an intruding traffic both are TCAS II equipped. Your TCAS determines the range of the intruding aircraft by:",
    "feedback": "measuring the time lapse between the transmission of an interrogation signal and the reception of a reply signal from the transponder of the intruder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS LEG page typically displays the following parameters:\n1) True track2) Magnetic variation3) Elevation of waypoints4) TAS5) Distance to waypoints\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "VFE is the maximum speed :",
    "feedback": "with the flaps extended in a given position."
  },
  {
    "question": "The position of the flight director command bars:",
    "feedback": "indicates the manoeuvres to execute, to achieve or maintain a flight situation"
  },
  {
    "question": "With EAS and density altitude, we can deduce:",
    "feedback": "TAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indication of the directional gyro is valid only for a limited period of time. The causes of this inaccuracy are:\n\n1) rotation of the earth\n2) longitudinal accelerations\n3) aircraft's moving over the surface of the earth\n4) vertical components of the earth's magnetic field\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Yaw Damper signal for a given rate of oscillation, is",
    "feedback": "varied inversely according to the airspeed."
  },
  {
    "question": "The inclination of the Earth's magnetic field at the magnetic equator is equal to:",
    "feedback": "0°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of Auto Trim function in autopilot is to :",
    "feedback": "control elevator trim tab in order to relieve elevator load"
  },
  {
    "question": "The elements which take part in the local vertical alignment of an inertial strap-down unit are:",
    "feedback": "the accelerometers"
  },
  {
    "question": "During flight the commander would like to check whether the actual wind matches what the forecast says. The commander turns the mode selector knob on the INS CDU to \"WIND\". The actual wind is displayed on the INS CDU. To calculate the wind, the system uses ....",
    "feedback": "INS/IRS data and TAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nP = power\nT = torque\nOmega = Angular Velocity\n\nThe correct relationship is:",
    "feedback": "P = T x Omega"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying with an IVSI, when another aircraft in front, same level and route, reports moderate turbulence. How does this affect the IVSI?",
    "feedback": "Overreact"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS uses the following data:\n\n1) CAS\n2) radio altitude\n3) glide slope deviation\n4) flaps position\n5) gear position\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "When, in flight, the needle of a needle-and-ball indicator is on the right and the ball on the left, the aircraft is :",
    "feedback": "turning right with not enough bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding the capture phase of the autopilot?",
    "feedback": "A given rate of change of trajectory is maintained to achieve a new parameter without undershooting"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly lists the order of available selections of the Mode Selector switches of an inertial reference system (IRS) mode panel?",
    "feedback": "OFF  -  ALIGN  -  NAV  -  ATT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select from the options below the combination regrouping all correct IRS output data:\n1) True heading2) Magnetic heading3) True airspeed4) Ground speed5) Actual latitude and longitude parameters6) EGPWS modes 1 to 7",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the RA on the following EHSI, the intruder is:",
    "feedback": "300 ft above your aircraft and descending at 500 ft/min or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the command bars of a flight director:",
    "feedback": "it is possible to remove them by switching the flight director OFF"
  },
  {
    "question": "A dynamic pressure measurement circuit is constituted of the following pressure probes:",
    "feedback": "total pressure and static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The airspeed indicator of an aircraft is provided with a moving red and white hatched pointer. This pointer indicates the:",
    "feedback": "maximum speed in VMO operation versus altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gyromagnetic compass, the gyro axis:\n\n1) is maintained vertical\n2) is maintained horizontal\n3) is servo-controlled in azimuth\n4) is free in azimuth\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an EFB fails to function properly when it is being used to carry out performance calculations, this can lead to ....",
    "feedback": "erroneous take-off speeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "An \"intruding traffic advisory\" is represented on the display system of the TCAS 2 (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) by displaying :",
    "feedback": "a yellow full circle."
  },
  {
    "question": "What indications should you get from the turn-and-slip indicator during taxi?",
    "feedback": "the ball moves freely opposite the turn, and the needle deflects in the direction of \nthe turn"
  },
  {
    "question": "At flight level and mach number constant, if OAT increases, the CAS:",
    "feedback": "remains constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure probe used to measure the pressure of a low pressure fuel pump is:",
    "feedback": "an aneroid capsule."
  },
  {
    "question": "What measurement is used to carry out alignment of an Inertial Navigation System?",
    "feedback": "Acceleration sensed by the east gyro horizontal accelerometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The types of sensors used in an engine vibration monitoring system may be:\n1) magnet\n2) tachometer\n3) piezo electric crystal\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which variable is needed to calculate and obtain the TAS from the CAS?",
    "feedback": "Compressibility and density"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is lined up on runway 23, which is aligned with a magnetic bearing of 232°. During pre-flight checks it is observed that the direct reading magnetic compass reads 243°. What action should be taken by the flight crew in order to comply with maximum permissible deviation errors?",
    "feedback": "Cancel the flight and return to maintenance"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot has to carry out a single-pilot IFR flight on a light twin-engined aircraft for cargo transport. The purpose of the automatic pilot is at least to hold the:",
    "feedback": "heading and to hold the altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method of entering waypoints can be used on all INS equipment?",
    "feedback": "Latitude and longitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft and an intruding traffic both are TCAS II equipped. Your TCAS determines the relative height of the intruding aircraft by:",
    "feedback": "comparing the mode C pressure altitudes of the two aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The commands sent out by the yaw damper computer:",
    "feedback": "are added to or subtracted from the rudder deflection orders sent out by the pilot or the autopilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an automatic thrust control system is in the THRUST mode:",
    "feedback": "thrust is set to a computed thrust according to a performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "An advanced electronic checklist system is installed in an aircraft to direct the pilot through the proper procedures in the event that one or more of its systems fail. When the pilot completes the ordered action, the command is erased from the screen in this particular electronic checklist. Which statement regarding the use of entirely monitored electronic checklists is true?",
    "feedback": "The pilot must maintain awareness of the technical implications of his/her actions, and not simply follow commands because they appear on the screen."
  },
  {
    "question": "For a large transport aeroplane equipped with a fly-by-wire flight control system and an FMS:",
    "feedback": "the operating system of the FMS is certified at a level equal or lower than the software used for flight controls"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb, the total pressure probe of the airspeed indicator becomes blocked; if the pilot tries to maintain a constant indicated airspeed, the true airspeed:",
    "feedback": "decreases until reaching the stall speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System (INS), Ground Speed (GS) is calculated:",
    "feedback": "by integrating measured acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "In accordance with (ICAO) Annex 6 part I, the flight data recorder is to be located in the aircraft :",
    "feedback": "as far to the rear as practicable"
  },
  {
    "question": "A closed-loop system:",
    "feedback": "Monitors the controlled parameter, calculates an error, corrects the error"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which indication can be displayed by the directional gyroscope?",
    "feedback": "Any heading as required by the pilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the ND, the TCAS generates the intruder aircraft symbol represented below. The correct intruder vertical information is:",
    "feedback": "300 ft below, descending"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying in cold air (colder than standard atmosphere), indicated altitude is:",
    "feedback": "higher than the true altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The signal supplied by a transmitter fitted with a 3-phase AC generator, connected to RPM indicator, is :",
    "feedback": "a three-phase voltage, the frequency of which varies with the RPM; the indicator is provided with a motor which drives a magnetic tachometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic flight control system (AFCS) in an aircraft is coupled to the guidance outputs from an inertial navigation system (INS).\nThe aircraft is flying between inserted waypoints No. 3 (55°00'N  020°00'W) and No.4 (55°00'N 030°00'W).\nWith DSRTK/STS selected on the CDU, to the nearestwhole degree, the initial track read-out from waypoint No. 3 will be:",
    "feedback": "274°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic properties of a gyroscope are:\n1) The gyros weight2) The rigidity in space3) The inertia4) The high RPM5) The precession",
    "feedback": "2, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "All the anemometers are calibrated according to:",
    "feedback": "St-Venant's formula which takes into account the air compressibility."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of auto throttle is:",
    "feedback": "to maintain constant engine power or airplane speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are pitot-static instruments that would be affected in case of a failure of the ADC?\n1) Airspeed Indicator2) Altimeter3) Attitude Indicator4) Vertical Speed Indicator",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the flight level and Mach number remain constant, when the OAT decreases:",
    "feedback": "CAS remains constant and TAS decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statement from the answers given below:",
    "feedback": "The difference between following the FMS data compared to raw data from radionavigation receivers, is that pilots lose spatial awareness when relying too heavily on the automation of the FMS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lists the first three pages of the CDU/MCDU normally used to enter data on initial start-up of the FMS?",
    "feedback": "IDENT - POS INIT - RTE"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a stabilised platform inertial system, the accelerations are measured in a trihedron which is:\n(NB: \"aircraft trihedron\" = pitch, roll and yaw axis)",
    "feedback": "free from the aircraft trihedron"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a datalink system, the uplink communications consist in transmitting data:",
    "feedback": "from the ground to the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The characteristics of the gyroscope used in a gyromagnetic compass system are:  (NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "two degrees of freedom, whose horizontal axis corresponding to the reference direction is maintained in the horizontal plane by an automatic erecting system"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gravity type erector is used in a vertical gyro device to correct errors on :",
    "feedback": "an artificial horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "The upper airspeed limit of the green arc on the airspeed indicator represents:",
    "feedback": "Maximum structural cruising speed (VNO)"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gyromagnetic compass, the signal feeding the precession amplifier comes from:",
    "feedback": "error detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a large aeroplane, the input data of the stall warning system are:\n\n1) angle of attack\n2) weight\n3) bank angle\n4) configuration (slats/flaps)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the computed aircraft position becomes less accurate, the Enhanced GPWS (EGPWS) function(s) affected is(are):\n\n1) the \"FIVE HUNDRED\" voice call out\n2) the excessive rate of descent\n3) the terrain display on the navigation display\n4) the negative climb rate or altitude loss after take-off\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following aircraft components are used for an autoland?",
    "feedback": "Autopilot(s), autothrust, radio altimeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of Flowmeters, or \"unit flow meters,\" the most commonly used at the present time, is to measure across their system the :",
    "feedback": "quantity of fuel movement"
  },
  {
    "question": "A direct reading compass should be swung when:",
    "feedback": "there is a large, and permanent, change in magnetic latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the principle of operation of Synthetic Vision (SVS)?",
    "feedback": "It is based on a terrain and ground features database that is shown on the PFD to increase the pilot's situation awareness"
  },
  {
    "question": "A transport airplane is compelled to carry on board a Ground Proximity Warning System  (GPWS). This system will warn the crew in case of :\n\n1 - keeping the altitude at a lower level than the one shown in the flight plan entered in the FMS.\n2 - dangerous ground proximity.\n3 - loss of altitude during take-off or missed approach.\n4 - wrong landing configuration.\n5 - descent below glidepath, within limits.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2,3,4,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A direct reading compass is used at North Magnetic Latitude. Starting a right hand turn from heading 300 will result in",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which procedures are available for assessing the performance of individual IRUs after a flight?\n1) Reviewing the residual indicated ground speeds when the aircraft has parked2) Reviewing the total system drift in NM/h after a flight has been completed3) Access the IRS data by selecting the NAV mode4) Assess the performance by comparing pitch and roll information with the ATT mode selected",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 1 is showing:",
    "feedback": "a 40° left bank and 15° nose down attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct or incorrect?\n1) The instantaneous vertical speed indicator (IVSI) incorporates an accelerometer unit2) The main disadvantage of an instantaneous vertical speed indicator (IVSI) is the problem of lag",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An angle of attack sensor may consist of:\n\n1) an inertial system computing the difference between flight path and flight attitude\n2) a conical slotted probe which positions itself to determine the angle of attack\n3) a vane detector which positions the rotor of a synchro-transmitter\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under normal conditions, in a dual FMS architecture:\n(FMC=Flight Management Computer)",
    "feedback": "one FMC is working as the master and the other as a slave: both FMC are synchronised via an exchange bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter contains one or more aneroid capsules. Inside these capsules is:",
    "feedback": "a very low residual pressure and outside is static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an aircraft EFIS equipped:\n\n1) the ND displays flight director command bars\n2) the PFD displays the altimeter setting\n3) the ND displays the attitude of the aircraft\n4) the flight mode annunciator is part of the ND\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following N1 parameters can be displayed on an electronic display unit?\n1) Present N12) Commanded N13) N1 limit for operation",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "When accelerating on an easterly heading in the Northern hemisphere, the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass will turn :",
    "feedback": "clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the north"
  },
  {
    "question": "With a TCAS II, when a corrective resolution is generated:",
    "feedback": "the vertical speed must be effectively modified without delay"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an auto-pilot slaved powered control circuit, the system which ensures synchronisation :",
    "feedback": "can itself, when it fails, prevent the automatic pilot from being engaged."
  },
  {
    "question": "The role of the FMS (Flight Management System) is to aid the flight crew with:\n\n1) immediate actions in case of emergency procedure\n2) navigation\n3) in-flight performance optimization\n4) electronic check-lists\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indicated Mach number is independent from:",
    "feedback": "temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an automated en-route flight, the autotrim fails. What are the implications of such a failure?",
    "feedback": "The autopilot should disconnect, with an associated warning for the situation. The pilot flying must be ready to take controls"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are several types of temperature sensors. Which one has a maximum scale range from -200ºC up to 2000ºC?",
    "feedback": "Thermocouple"
  },
  {
    "question": "A typical FMS installation consists of 2 EFIS and 2 CDU. When the FMC switch is placed in the \"ALTN\" position",
    "feedback": "The related CDU and EFIS displays will be connected to the other computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rate of turn given by the rate of turn indicator is valid:",
    "feedback": "for the airspeed range defined during the calibration of the instrument"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, when exceeding the limits of the flight envelope, the colour accepted to alert the flight crew is:",
    "feedback": "red"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a strapdown inertial system, the IRU (Inertial Reference Unit) measures:",
    "feedback": "accelerations and angular rates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sound propagates through the air at a speed which only depends on :",
    "feedback": "temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS calculator receives the following signals :\n\n1 - vertical speed\n2 - radio altimeter height\n3 - pressure altitude\n4 - glidepath deviation \n5 - gear and flaps position\n6 - angle of attack\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,2,4,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of the inductive probe tachometer is to measure the:",
    "feedback": "frequency of the electric impulse created by a notched wheel rotating in a magnetic field."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the components of a ring laser gyro?",
    "feedback": "2 beams of laser light"
  },
  {
    "question": "A remote indicating compass is fitted with a \"free/slave\" switch. When \"free\" is selected and the system is synchronised, the source of the heading that is displayed is ....",
    "feedback": "the gyroscopic unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer(s) from the statements below:\n1) There is no risk for an out-of-trim situation when manual trim is used with the autopilot engaged2) The autopilot may not engage unless the aircraft controls are in trim",
    "feedback": "1) is not correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Components of the FMS are:\n\n1) CDU (Control and Display Unit)\n2) database\n3) FMC (Flight Management Computer)\n4) electronic check-lists\n5) GPWS mode controller\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ADI presentation shows that the aircraft is (VSI reading zero):",
    "feedback": "in straight and level flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Machmeter is subject to position error. This error concerns:",
    "feedback": "pitot tubes and static ports"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb, if the total pressure head is rapidly clogged up by ice, the sensed total pressure remains constant and:",
    "feedback": "the static pressure decreases, implying a increasing IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a compass deviation correction card. The .......",
    "feedback": "residual deviation is noted on the card after the compass swinging procedure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Permanent magnetism in aircraft arises chiefly from:",
    "feedback": "hammering, and the effect of the earth's magnetic field, whilst under construction"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning a fail-passive flight control system, in the event of a failure:\n\n1) there may be a significant deviation of flight path or attitude\n2) there is no significant deviation of flight path or attitude\n3) the landing is not completed automatically\n4) the landing is completed automatically\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sensor(s) feeding the EPR indicator is(are):",
    "feedback": "pressure probes, one located upstream from the compressor inlet, and the other downstream from the turbine outlet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following functions of an autopilot, those related to the airplane stabilization are:\n\n1) pitch attitude holding\n2) IAS or Mach number holding\n3) horizontal wing holding\n4) VOR radial holding\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The error in a direction indicator caused by the convergence of the meridians in northerly and southerly latitudes is called",
    "feedback": "transport error"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the northern hemisphere, during deceleration following a landing in an Easterly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "an apparent turn to the South."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can an unstable (unreliable) airspeed be identified by the crew?\n1) Recognizing a variation in airspeed through cross referencing ASI in multi crew aircraft2) Aerodynamic buffeting3) Unusual aircraft attitude4) Irregular ambient wind noise inside the aircraft\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn towards North if",
    "feedback": "an aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading."
  },
  {
    "question": "The red pointer which is normally on the red line on the EGT (Exhaust Gas Temperature)  indicators:",
    "feedback": "moves when the corresponding value is exceeded and remains positioned at  the maximum  value that has been reached."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the flux-valve is:",
    "feedback": "to sense the direction of the earth's magnetic field relative to the airplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight warning system (FWS):\n\n1) increases the situation awareness of the crew\n2) transmits automatically to ATC distress messages\n3) gives suitable indications to the crew of the action necessary to avoid impending danger\n4) prioritises warnings\n5) can not generate alerts in case of aerodynamic limits exceeding\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nC = temperature in Celsius\nK = temperature in Kelvin\n\nThe correct relationship between these different units is:",
    "feedback": "K = C + 273"
  },
  {
    "question": "The navigational database of Flight Management Systems (FMS):",
    "feedback": "contain additional space so that crew members can add their own waypoints"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter indicates true altitude:",
    "feedback": "in standard atmosphere only"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight with ETD at 20:00 UTC is scheduled for a long-haul 12-hour flight. During the preflight checks the flight crew notices that the navigation database expires at the end of the day. What must the crew do?",
    "feedback": "Complete the flight with the database installed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parameters are used by the FMS vertical guidance function?\n1) Angle of attack2) Flight path angle3) Airspeed",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A magnetic variation of 20°W means that the magnetic heading to an object is:",
    "feedback": "115° when the true heading is 095°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A paddle-wheel placed in a the fuel circuit of a gas turbine engine initially measures:",
    "feedback": "volumetric flow by a tally of the impulses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a barometric VSI with a logarithmic scale. This means that ....",
    "feedback": "A small rate of change in ROC and ROD are read easily than a large rate of change"
  },
  {
    "question": "VNE is the maximum speed :",
    "feedback": "which must never be exceeded"
  },
  {
    "question": "A radio altimeter uses:",
    "feedback": "two antennas: one for the transmission, and an other for the reception"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aeroplane outside air temperature probe measures the :",
    "feedback": "total air temperature minus kinetic heating effects in order to obtain the static temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a modern commercial aircraft, the FMS provides:",
    "feedback": "lateral and vertical navigation, and guidance performance management"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the position data (lat, long) is no longer computed by an IRS, the affected system(s) is(are):",
    "feedback": "FMS"
  },
  {
    "question": "A laser gyro consists of :",
    "feedback": "a laser generating two light waves"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statements about fuel flow are correct or incorrect?\n1) Fuel flow may be measured by volume per unit of time\n2) Fuel flow may be measured by mass per unit of time",
    "feedback": "1 is correct, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of the Schuler pendulum is used in the design of a:",
    "feedback": "stabilised platform inertial system"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the autoland sequence, there is a final approach phase and a touch down phase. The transition from one phase to another is triggered by the:",
    "feedback": "Radio altimeter"
  },
  {
    "question": "A manifold pressure gauge of a piston engine measures :",
    "feedback": "absolute pressure in intake system near the inlet valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel flow parameters are contained in the",
    "feedback": "FMC performance data base"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position data (lat, long) computed by an IRS can be used by the:\n\n1) yaw damper\n2) FMS\n3) radio altimeter\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft flies into the vicinity of one of the magnetic poles, why does the magnetic compass becomes unreliable or even useless?",
    "feedback": "The horizontal component becomes so weak that the directive force is insufficient for a reliable compass indication"
  },
  {
    "question": "The horizontal command bar of a flight director:\n\n1) repeats the position information given by the ILS in the horizontal plane\n2) repeats the position information given by the ILS in the vertical plane\n3) gives information about the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to be applied on the pitch of the aircraft\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The centre of gravity of the compass rose of a direct reading magnetic compass lies below the pivot point in order to reduce the influence of the:",
    "feedback": "magnetic inclination"
  },
  {
    "question": "The oncoming stall of a large transport airplane appears in the form of:",
    "feedback": "control stick vibrations simulating natural buffeting."
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the systematic errors of the directional gyro, the error due to the earth  rotation make the north  reference turn in the horizontal plane. At a mean latitude of 45°N, this reference turns by:",
    "feedback": "10.5°/hour to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "After having programmed your flight director, you see that the indications of your ADI (Attitude Director Indicator) are as represented in the diagram. On this instrument, the command bars indicate that you must bank your airplane to the left and :",
    "feedback": "decrease the flight attitude until the command bars recentre on the symbolic airplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere, a magnetic compass will normally indicate a turn towards North if:",
    "feedback": "An aircraft is accelerated while on an east or west heading."
  },
  {
    "question": "After a radio altimeter failure, which of the following systems are affected?\n1) Autobrake system2) EGPWS3) Autothrottle4) ISIS",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nC = the temperature in Celsius\nK = the temperature in Kelvin\nF = the temperature in Fahrenheit\n\nWhich of these statements about temperature units are correct or incorrect?\n1) C = K -273\n2) F = (C x 1.8) + 32",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An autopilot system:",
    "feedback": "must provide at least aircraft stabilisation functions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering the fuel indication given in litres. The pilot requests that the aircraft is refuelled to obtain 70% full tank. What is the amount of fuel that must be uplifted to obtain that value?",
    "feedback": "109 litres"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is flying at FL 320 and Mach number 0.79. The OAT is -53°C.\n\nConsidering that the probe recovery coefficient is 0.96, the indicated total air temperature is:",
    "feedback": "-27°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the deviation table of a Direct Reading Compass below.   The Direct Reading Compass indicates a heading 242°. The variation in the area is 22°E. What is the True Heading of the aircraft?",
    "feedback": "262°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The data base of a FMC (flight management computer) is divided into two major sections:",
    "feedback": "aeroplane performance and navigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of a float type fuel gauge are (is):\n\n1) easy construction\n2) independence of indications with regard to aircraft attitude\n3) independence of indications with regard to the accelerations \n4) independence of indications with regard to temperature variations\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Computer memory can consist of ......",
    "feedback": "capacitors"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the intruding aircraft is equipped with a transponder without altitude reporting capability, the TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) issues a :",
    "feedback": "\"traffic advisory\" only."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is correct regarding an Enhanced Visual System (EVS)?",
    "feedback": "It generates real-time imagery, to display on the PFD or HUD, of the surroundings of the aircraft based on external sensors"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram representing a left turn with insufficient rudder is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principal function of the synchroniser circuit in an autopilot pitch channel is to:",
    "feedback": "Ensure a smooth transition in pitch after switching on the autopilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is cruising at FL 220. The autothrottle maintains a constant CAS. If the OAT increases, the Mach number:",
    "feedback": "remains constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Variation is defined as the angle between:",
    "feedback": "TN and MN."
  },
  {
    "question": "Some FMS have an autotuning function.\nWhich parameters can be automatically tuned?",
    "feedback": "Radio navigation frequencies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning an aircraft with a torquemeter as the main power indicator, which of the following would be the most appropriate power setting for take-off?",
    "feedback": "95%"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight warning system (FWS):\n\n1) draws the attention of the crew to the existence of an abnormal condition\n2) gives indications to the crew to identify an abnormal condition\n3) transmits automatically to ATC urgency messages\n4) can not generate alerts in case of engine malfunctions\n5) prioritises warnings\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft equipped with an Inertial Navigation System (INS) flies with INS 1 coupled with autopilot 1. Both inertial navigation systems are navigating from way-point A to B. The inertial systems' Central Display Units (CDU) shows:\n- XTK on INS 1 = 0\n- XTK on INS 2 = 8L\n(XTK = cross track)\nFrom this information it can be deduced that:",
    "feedback": "at least one of the inertial navigaton systems is drifting"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which instrument are the flight director bars normally present?",
    "feedback": "ADI"
  },
  {
    "question": "The navigational database of Flight Management Systems (FMS):",
    "feedback": "Contains additional space so that crew members can add their own waypoints"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airborne instrument, equipped with a gyro with 2 degrees of freedom and a horizontal spin axis is:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "a directional gyro"
  },
  {
    "question": "After alignment of the stable platform of an Inertial Navigation System, the output data from the INS computer to the platform is:",
    "feedback": "rate corrections to the gyros"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight guidance system has mixed modes. What describes the functions of the take-off mode (considering the autopilot only)?",
    "feedback": "Pitch commands should stabilise at a speed referenced to V2 and the roll commands should maintain the runway centreline or wings level"
  },
  {
    "question": "The directional gyro axis spins about the local vertical by 15°/hour :",
    "feedback": "on the North pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"status\" page in aircraft fitted with an Engine Indicating and Crew Alert System (EICAS):",
    "feedback": "Needs to be selected manually and provides information on the lower EICAS screen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Software levels according to document \"DO-178B\" are based on the potential of the software to cause safety-related failures identified in the system safety assessment. DO-178B has 5 levels of certification. The level that poses the greatest risk to the operation of the aircraft should the software fail is:",
    "feedback": "Level A"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you recognize the declutter function of a HUD?",
    "feedback": "Indications can be just shown as numbers at various unusual places of the HUD, that don't necessarily respect the typical instrumentation conventions"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is known as the \"Schuler Period\" has a length of",
    "feedback": "84.4 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about temperature are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) 20° Celsius = 68° Fahrenheit\n2) 273 Kelvin = 0° Celsius",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the display of a TCAS II, a proximate traffic is represented by:",
    "feedback": "a white or cyan solid lozenge"
  },
  {
    "question": "At high angles of attack and according to the type of aeroplane, the stall protection system can:\n1) inhibit the pitch trim orders in the nose up direction2) retract the speed brakes3) increase thrust\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a capacitor are correct or incorrect?\n1) The capacitance is proportional to distance between plates\n2) The capacitance is proportional to the surfaces of the plates",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When engaged in the pitch hold mode, the autopilot uses data issued by the:",
    "feedback": "attitude reference system"
  },
  {
    "question": "A laser reference system (IRS), as compared to a gyro reference system (INS):",
    "feedback": "is strapped down and is not adversely affected by g-forces"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main input of a stall protection system is:",
    "feedback": "the angle of attack"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gyro begins to precess when:",
    "feedback": "A force is applied at right angles to its rotational axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gyromagnetic compass, the heading information from the flux valve is sent to the:",
    "feedback": "error detector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the vertical speed indicator (VSI) and the instantaneous vertical speed indicator (IVSI):\n1) The IVSI incorporates an accelerometer unit to overcome the problem of lag2) The vertical speed indicator is a barometric type VSI3) The barometric VSI capsule is fed with static pressure4) The case of a barometric VSI is also fed with static pressure through a restricted choke5) The IVSI tends to overreact to turbulent flying conditions\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fail-operational hybrid landing system is fitted to an aircraft. This consists of a:",
    "feedback": "fail-passive automatic landing system and a secondary independent guidance system such as a head-up display (HUD). This enables the pilot to land manually if the automatic landing system fails"
  },
  {
    "question": "The capacity fuel gauges provide information:",
    "feedback": "on mass whose indication is independent of the temperature of the fuel."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a Flight Data Monitoring (FDM) programme is to collect flight data ......",
    "feedback": "anonymously, to improve safety"
  },
  {
    "question": "With reference to an inertial navigation system (INS), the initial great circle track between computer inserted waypoints will be displayed when the control display unit (CDU) is selected to:",
    "feedback": "DSRTK/STS"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Flight Mode Annunciator FMA, the pilot can check:\n1) The flight director selection\n2) The flaps/slats selection\n3) the auto-throttle modes\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft in the northern hemisphere makes an accurate rate one turn to the right/starboard. If the initial heading was 330°, after 30 seconds of the turn the direct reading magnetic compass should read:",
    "feedback": "less than 060°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A turn indicator displays the ......",
    "feedback": "rate of change of heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main input data to the Stall Warning Annunciator System are :\n\n1- Mach Meter indication\n2- Angle of Attack\n3- Indicate Airspeed (IAS)\n4- Aircraft configuration (Flaps/Slats)\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The measurement of exhaust gas temperature (EGT) is normally based upon the principle of",
    "feedback": "voltage generation in a thermocouple"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an occasion for carrying out a compass swing on a Direct Reading Compass?",
    "feedback": "After an aircraft has passed through a severe electrical storm, or has been struck by lightning"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isogonals are lines of equal :",
    "feedback": "magnetic variation."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the value of the magnetic dip at the magnetic south pole ?",
    "feedback": "90°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deviation compensation in a flux gate compass is done:",
    "feedback": "Mechanically"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding automatic flight control, which equipment is required for the FMS to control the vertical axis?",
    "feedback": "Auto throttle"
  },
  {
    "question": "The calculator combined with the stick shaker system of a modern transport airplane receives information about the: \n\n1- angle of attack\n2- engine R.P.M.\n3- configuration\n4- pitch and bank attitude\n5- sideslip\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1 and 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a selected axis capture mode, the autopilot gives a bank attitude input :",
    "feedback": "proportional to the deviation between the selected heading and the current heading but not exceeding a given value."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nE = electromotive force (emf)\nTc = cold junction temperature\nTh = hot junction temperature\nK = constant\n\nThe relationship that applies to a thermocouple is:",
    "feedback": "E = K x Th"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an automatic landing, between 50 ft AGL and touch down, the autopilot maintains:",
    "feedback": "A vertical speed depending on the radio altimeter height, with a constant vertical speed of about 2 feet/second during the last phase of the flare manoeuvre"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the static source to an altimeter becomes blocked during a climb, the instrument will:",
    "feedback": "continue to indicate the reading at which the blockage occured"
  },
  {
    "question": "Aircraft with pressurized cabin in flight: When switching to the alternate static pressure source, the pointer of the Vertical Speed Indicator :",
    "feedback": "indicates a climb, then settles down and reads correctly."
  },
  {
    "question": "When engaged in the FMS lateral navigation mode (LNAV) the autopilot uses the command provided by:",
    "feedback": "FMS"
  },
  {
    "question": "As the INS position of the departure aerodrome, coordinates 35°32.7'N 139°46.3'W are input instead of 35°32.7'N 139°46.3'E. When the aircraft subsequently passes point 52°N 180°W, the longitude value shown on the INS will be:",
    "feedback": "099° 32.6'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CAS is obtained from IAS by correcting for the following errors:\n\n1) position\n2) compressibility\n3) instrument\n4) density\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an electronic display unit, the following N1 parameters can be displayed:\n1) Present N1\n2) Commanded N1\n3) Maximum N1 operating limit\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a Turn-indicator, the measurement of rate-of-turn consists for :",
    "feedback": "low bank angles, in measuring the yaw rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the initial position indicated on the Inertial Reference System (IRS) display is correct?",
    "feedback": "It is not updated once the IRS mode is set to NAV"
  },
  {
    "question": "Speed of sound is proportional to:",
    "feedback": "the square root of the absolute temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight envelope protection (FEP) can include:\n1) the stall protection2) the overspeed protection3) the maximum vertical speed protection\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS navigation database includes the following data: 1- obstacles 2- waypoints 3- SID, STAR 4- relief 5- magnetic variation  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2,3,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The resultant of the first integration from the north/south accelerometer of an inertial navigation system (INS) in the NAV MODE is:",
    "feedback": "velocity along the local meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying an EGPWS equipped aircraft, performing a visual approach to a runway that has an ILS for that runway. What should you do to prevent false warnings during approach?",
    "feedback": "Disable the glideslope functionality on the EGPWS"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a typical challenge for the use of the standby instruments, supplementing the EFIS in the event of display units failing?",
    "feedback": "Their size and position on the flight deck"
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of warning is to be expected when disconnecting the autopilot for manual flying during the approach?",
    "feedback": "Both visual and aural warnings"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying a fly-by-wire aeroplane manually, the automatic pitch trim system eliminates the need for the pilot to make control column inputs to compensate for:\n1) a windshear2) slats/flaps configuration changes3) thrust changes\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to align an inertial reference system (IRS), it is required to insert the local geographical coordinates. This enables the IRS to:",
    "feedback": "Compare the latitude it finds with that entered by the operator"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the autothrust part of the flight guidance system is in speed mode, the thrust is ....",
    "feedback": "varied as required to maintain the selected airspeed or Mach Number"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the speed of sound at 15000 feet, at an OAT of -10º C?",
    "feedback": "632 kts"
  },
  {
    "question": "To stop the warning generatred by a stall warning system, the pilot:\n1) can push the inhibit aural warning button2) can switch off the stall warning system3) must leave the stall conditions\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The heading reference unit of a three-axis data generator is equipped with a gyro with:",
    "feedback": "2 degrees of freedom and horizontal spin axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a typical remote reading compass, the gyro is kept aligned with the magnetic meridian by means of",
    "feedback": "A torque motor"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an average or heavy weight  transport airplane, generally, the fuel quantity is measured by \"capacitor\" gauges because these give :\n\n1- indications partly independent of fuel temperature variations\n2- indications almost independent of the airplane's attitude and accelerations\n3- indications expressed in density\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "In flight, the IRS detects a critical fault with excessive position error. Regarding the mode selector switch, the crew should select:",
    "feedback": "ATT, to retain attitude information"
  },
  {
    "question": "The datalink communication message \"CHECK STUCK MICROPHONE (frequency)\" refers to a request from:",
    "feedback": "the ATC to the pilot to check microphone buttons due to a continuous transmission detected on the frequency"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rotational speed of an air-driven gyro is normally:",
    "feedback": "9000- 12000 RPM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What instrument is shown above?",
    "feedback": "INS/IRS"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ring laser gyro is:",
    "feedback": "a device which measures angular movements"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to a dual Flight Management System (FMS), which statement is correct?(FMC = Flight Management Computer)",
    "feedback": "Both FMC are decoupled in independent mode, and cross-checking between them does not occur"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is hydraulic pressure sensed?",
    "feedback": "By a transducer that receives an electric signal from a remote pressure sensor"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mach number is :",
    "feedback": "the ratio of the aircraft true airspeed to the sonic velocity at the altitude considered"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mach Trim is a device to compensate for :",
    "feedback": "backing of the aerodynamic center at high Mach numbers by moving the elevator to nose-up"
  },
  {
    "question": "The engagement of an autopilot is not possible when:\n\n1- there is a fault in the electrical power supply\n2- the controlled-turn knob is not set to centre-off\n3- there is a synchronization fault in the pitch channel\n4- there is a fault in the attitude reference unit\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "Near the magnetic pole:",
    "feedback": "the horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field is too small to permit the use of a magnetic compass"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Earth's north magnetic pole is:",
    "feedback": "located approximately in northern Canada"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) radio height\n2) attitude\n3) true track\n4) static pressure\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The next waypoint to be overflown is (i) and the estimated (ii) is (iii):",
    "feedback": "(i) XYZ, (ii) time of arrival, (iii) 22:59"
  },
  {
    "question": "Comparing the present position display on the Boeing 737-400 FMC, you note that there is a 10-mile difference between the left IRS and the right IRS position. This means that:",
    "feedback": "at least one of the IRS is drifting"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prior to the flight the initial fuel is inserted into the FMS. After refueling, the FMS indicates the fuel as being wrong. What could be the consequences?",
    "feedback": "FMS needs to be reinitialized to give correct calculations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approaching top of descent (TOD), the destination aerodrome ATIS includes RVRs around 200 metres, with Low Visibility Procedures (LVP) in force. The commander's windscreen heat failed in the cruise, with an annunciated alert. The screen is clear. What implications does the failure have on the briefing for the approach and landing?",
    "feedback": "A check of the FCOM is required, in case the defect causes a reduction in the aircraft's approach capability. Diversion, or an increased height minimum and/or RVR might be necessary"
  },
  {
    "question": "For most radio altimeters, when a system error occurs during approach the ..",
    "feedback": "Height indication is removed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lists all the stages of flight when it is possible to change the route in the active flight plan in an FMS equipped aircraft?",
    "feedback": "At any time before take-ff and throughout the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error varies according to:\n\n1) altimeter setting\n2) speed\n3) angle of attack\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The parameter that determines the relationship between EAS and TAS is:",
    "feedback": "density altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ACARS digital datalink communications system can use the following means for the data transmission:",
    "feedback": "SAT-COM, HF, VHF"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ...... is responsible for transferring data between other components inside a computer.",
    "feedback": "Data bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) present position (lat, long)\n2) TAS\n3) attitude\n4) ground speed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The RPM indicator  (or tachometer) of a piston engine can include a small red arc within the arc normally used (green arc)\nIn the RPM range corresponding to this small red arc the :",
    "feedback": "propeller generates vibration, continuous rating is forbidden"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the deviation when flying on a heading of 119°(C)?",
    "feedback": "1°E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the TCAS II, when receiving a Resolution Advisory (RA), crew members should:",
    "feedback": "immediately initiate the required manoeuvre"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft and an intruding aircraft both are TCAS II equipped. The information relating to this intruding traffic available on your TCAS equipment is:",
    "feedback": "three dimensional; your TCAS can generate both TAs (Traffic Advisories) and RAs (Resolution Advisories)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The radio altimeter:\n\n1) operates in the frequency band 1600-1660 MHz\n2) operates in the frequency band 4200-4400 MHz\n3) measures frequency difference\n4) measures amplitude difference\n\nThe combination of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens when speed becomes unreliable?",
    "feedback": "It is shown on the PFD, \"Speed disagreement\""
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nPt = total pressure\nPs = static pressure\nPd = dynamic pressure",
    "feedback": "Pt = Pd + Ps"
  },
  {
    "question": "A slaved directional gyro derives it's directional signal from :",
    "feedback": "the flux valve."
  },
  {
    "question": "If warning, caution, or advisory lights are installed in the flight deck, they must, unless otherwise approved by the Authority, be green for:",
    "feedback": "safe operation lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "The drift of the azimuth gyro on an inertial unit induces an error in the position given by this unit. \"t\" being the elapsed time.\nThe total error is:",
    "feedback": "proportional to the square of time, t²"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an aircraft maintaining a constant CAS and flight level is flying from a warm air mass into colder air:",
    "feedback": "TAS decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "What input data is required by an AoA sensor?\n1) Thrust2) Flaps3) Slats4) CAS5) TAS",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) navigation database typically includes the following data:\n1) airports2) take-off speeds3) navaids4) terrain cells5) runways\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the calculation of deviation, the following  headings are recorded:\nMH       CH\n358        356\n091        087\n182        186\n273        271\nCoefficient A is",
    "feedback": "+1"
  },
  {
    "question": "IRS is a self-contained system because",
    "feedback": "the system calculates the position of the aircraft without reference to externally generated (man-made) signals."
  },
  {
    "question": "A magnetic meridian is an equivalent imaginary line connecting the magnetic south and north poles and can be taken as the ..... of magnetic force lines along the surface of the earth. The missing word or phrase is:",
    "feedback": "horizontal"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft has hard iron magnetism only, and this hard iron magnetism is represented by a red pole in relative bearing 070 from the compass.  On what heading will the westerly deviation be maximum?",
    "feedback": "Heading 020"
  },
  {
    "question": "After having programmed your flight director, you see that the indications of your ADI (Attitude Director indicator) are as represented in diagram N°1. On this instrument, the command bars indicate that you must :",
    "feedback": "increase the flight attitude and bank your airplane to the left until the command bars recentre on the symbolic aeroplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying a heading of 088°(C). What is the corresponding deviation?",
    "feedback": "2°E"
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper system:\n\n1) counters any wrong pilot action on the rudder pedals\n2) counters dutch roll\n3) is active only when autopilot is engaged\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements are:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the static ports are completely clogged up by ice during a climb, the vertical speed indicator shows:",
    "feedback": "zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic modes of an autopilot consist in:",
    "feedback": "stabilizing the aircraft around its centre of gravity"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the southern hemisphere, during deceleration following a landing in a westerly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "an apparent turn to the north."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a magnetic compass compensation is to:",
    "feedback": "correct for deviations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding an Inertial Navigation System:\n1) In-flight realignment is possible and loss of alignment leads to loss of navigational data. Attitude information may still be available2) An incorrect entry of latitude may lead to a loss of alignment and is more critical than the incorrect entry of longitude",
    "feedback": "1) is not correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Enhanced GPWS (EGPWS) terrain display uses the following colours:",
    "feedback": "green, amber, red, magenta"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about temperature are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) 15° Celsius = 273° Kelvin\n2) 15° Celsius = 59° Fahrenheit",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a directional gyro, gimballing errors are due to:",
    "feedback": "a banked attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The take-off warning of a large transport aeroplane must provide to the pilot an aural warning if during the initial take-off roll:\n1) take-off thrust is not fully applied2) the flaps are not in the approved range for take-off3) speed brakes are extended4) the parking brake is unreleased\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name given to an Inertial Reference System (IRS) which has the gyros and accelerometers as part of the unit's fixture to the aircraft structure?",
    "feedback": "Strapdown"
  },
  {
    "question": "Command bars of the flight director may be present on the:\n\n1) HSI\n2) CDU\n3) ADI\n\nthe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Certification Specifications for Large Aeroplanes (CS-25), for standby compass instruments, the accuracy of the magnetic heading indications after correction should be better than or equal to:",
    "feedback": "10°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode is selected on the Navigation Display (EHSI)?",
    "feedback": "Expanded VOR mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cockpit voice recorder (CVR) will record :\n\n1. the information exchanged by the cabin crew\n2. the conversations between the crew members and voice communications transmitted from or received on the flight deck by radio\n3. the announcements made via the public address even if it has not been selected\n4. the conversations and alarms audible in the cockpit\n5. the captain conversations only\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the advantage of a servo altimeter over a sensitive altimeter?",
    "feedback": "It is a more accurate design"
  },
  {
    "question": "A failed RMI rose is locked on 090° and the ADF pointer indicates 225°. The relative bearing to the station is :",
    "feedback": "135°."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct answer(s) from the statements below:\n1) The autopilot may not engage unless the aircraft controls are in trim2) Use of manual trim when the autopilot is engaged will normally lead to autopilot disconnection",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The input data of an ADC are:  1) OAT 2) TAT 3) Static pressure 4) Total pressure  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alternate static source of a light non-pressurized aircraft is located in the flight deck. When used, the static pressure sensed is likely to be:",
    "feedback": "lower than ambient pressure due to aerodynamic suction"
  },
  {
    "question": "What time is left for a pilot to respond to an EGPWS caution alert before hitting terrain?",
    "feedback": "40 to 60 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "The requirement to carry a GPWS (Ground Proximity Warning System) concerns aeroplanes which are, depending on their age, weight and passenger capacity :\n\n1- turboprop-powered\n2- piston-powered\n3- jet-powered\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) navigation database typically includes the following data:\n1) obstacles2) navaids3) SID, STAR, and approach procedures4) waypoints5) airways\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the static source to an airspeed indicator (ASI) becomes blocked during a descent the instrument will:",
    "feedback": "over-read"
  },
  {
    "question": "A thermocouple type temperature sensor is composed of:",
    "feedback": "two dissimilar metals joined together at one end (called hot junction or measuring junction)"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the LOC mode (holding of localizer axis). If the vertical command bar is deviating to the left, it means that the aircraft:",
    "feedback": "must be rolled to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "Computer main memory comes in two principal varieties:",
    "feedback": "Random Access Memory (RAM) and Read Only Memory (ROM)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the circle followed by the letters \"KABC\" indicate?",
    "feedback": "An off-route airport"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter indicates 16000 ft with a subscale setting of 1013,25 hPa. QNH is 993 hPa, OAT is -3°C. \n\nThe pressure altitude of the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "16000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A transport airplane has to be equipped with an altitude warning device. This system will warn the crew about :\n\n1 - getting close to the preselected altitude, during both climb and descent.\n2 - getting close to the preselected altitude, during climb only.\n3 - the loss of altitude during take-off or missed approach.\n4 - a wrong landing configuration.\n5 - a variation higher or lower than a preselected altitude.\n\nThe combination regrouping the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main inputs to the flight envelope protection system are:\n\n1) GPWS signals\n2) ACAS signals\n3) angle of attack\n4) bank angle\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main limitation of the EVS?",
    "feedback": "The fact that an infrared camera uses temperature and temperature difference in order to produce an image"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which formula is used to calculate the capacitance C of a capacitor where:\ne = dielectric constant\nA = area of the plates\nd = distance between the plates?",
    "feedback": "C = e * (A / d)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a flight director of the command bars type:\n\n1) the vertical bar is always associated with the roll channel\n2) the vertical bar may be associated with the pitch channel\n3) the horizontal bar may be associated with the roll channel\n4) the horizontal bar is associated with the pitch channel\n\nthe combination containing all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The different types of tachometers are:",
    "feedback": "mechanical, electrical, electronic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum percentage for N1 that can be selected?",
    "feedback": "Sometimes above 100%"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying with the aid of an inertial navigation system (INS) connected to the autopilot. The following two points have been entered in the INS computer: WPT 1: 60°N 030°W WPT 2: 60°N 020°W When 025°W is passed the latitude shown on the display unit of the inertial navigation system will be:",
    "feedback": "60°05.7'N"
  },
  {
    "question": "At high angles of attack and according to the type of aeroplane, the stall protection system can:\n1) extend the flaps to the full position2) increase thrust3) inhibit the pitch trim orders in the nose down direction\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an electronic display unit, the source of the vibrations sensed by an engine vibration monitoring system:",
    "feedback": "can be displayed (N1 or N2)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot wishes to turn right on to a northerly heading with 20° bank at a latitude of 40° North. Using a direct reading compass, in order to achieve this he must stop the turn on to an approximate heading of :",
    "feedback": "330°"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a yaw damper system, sensing of a disturbance in yaw is usually by:",
    "feedback": "a rate gyro or an accelerometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the speed exceeds VMO/MMO and according to the type of aeroplane, the overspeed protection function can:\n1) extend the speed brakes2) reduce thrust to idle3) inhibit the pitch trim orders in the nose down direction\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "The correct answers are: 3, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mach number is a function of the",
    "feedback": "Absolute temperature of the air."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft has turned 270 degrees with a constant attitude and bank, the pilot observes the following on a classic artificial horizon :",
    "feedback": "too much nose-up and bank too high."
  },
  {
    "question": "The computer of the autopilot system uses, among others, input signals from the :\n\n1) attitude reference system\n2) mode annunciator panel\n3) ADC\n4) mode control panel\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operation of the radio altimeter of a modern aircraft is based on:",
    "feedback": "Frequency modulation of the carrier wave"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS cross track (XTK) is:",
    "feedback": "the abeam distance error, to the left or right from the desired flight plan leg to the aircraft position."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a modern aircraft, the flight director modes are displayed on the:",
    "feedback": "upper strip of the PFD (Primary Flight Display)."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the current active waypoint?",
    "feedback": "VIW"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of an electric float gauge are:\n\n1- ease of manufacture\n2- independence of the indication relative to the variations of the aircraft power system if the measurement is made by a ratiometer\n3- independence of the indication relative to the variations of the aircraft power system if the measurement is made by a galvanometer\n4- independence of the indication relative to temperature variations\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the LOC mode (holding of Localizer axis). The position of the vertical command bar indicates:",
    "feedback": "the correction on the bank to be applied to join and follow the Localizer axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a steep turn, the northerly turning error on a magnetic compass on the northern hemisphere is:",
    "feedback": "equal to 180° on a 090° heading in a right turn."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the pilot typically use the Flight Director System (FDS) during the final approach phase of a non-automated landing?",
    "feedback": "Flight director only"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), the following EGT parameters may be displayed:\n1) Instantaneous EGT\n2) Maximum continuous EGT\n3) Maximum takeoff EGT limit\n4) Maximum start EGT limit\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding typical user-defined waypoints:",
    "feedback": "It may be entered if the navigation database does not contain a waypoint that is required to safely complete a flight route"
  },
  {
    "question": "A closed loop control system in which a small power input controls a much larger power output in a strictly proportionate manner is known as :",
    "feedback": "a servomechanism."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, the principle used to obtain position is:\n\n1) single integration of acceleration according to time\n2) double integration of acceleration according to time\n3) single integration of speed according to time\n4) double integration of speed according to time\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2 or 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "We are maintaining a constant flight level.  That means:",
    "feedback": "the outside air pressure is constant."
  },
  {
    "question": "Upon application of power, which page is displayed on the FMS after the self-test is executed?",
    "feedback": "IDENT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The guidance functions of an autopilot consist in:",
    "feedback": "monitoring the movements of the centre of gravity in the three dimensions of space"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressue is defined as:",
    "feedback": "A force per unit area"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is in a steady climb. The autothrottle maintains a constant Mach number. If the total temperature remains constant, the calibrated airspeed :",
    "feedback": "decreases."
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot is divided into two basic modes, what are they called?",
    "feedback": "Lateral mode (HDA) and Vertical mode (VS)."
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an airplane automatic trim system is to trim out the hinge moment of the :",
    "feedback": "elevator(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the ground run takeoff phase, the auto-throttles allow to:",
    "feedback": "hold N1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Flight Mode Annunciator FMA is to:",
    "feedback": "check and confirm in which modes the automatic flight control systems are armed and/or engaged"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compared with a stabilised platform inertial system, a strapdown inertial system:\n\n1) can align while the aircraft is moving\n2) has a quicker alignment phase\n3) is more reliable in time\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The attitude data computed by an IRS can be used by the:",
    "feedback": "auto pilot system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering an air-driven artificial horizon, when an airplane accelerates during the take-off run, the result is:",
    "feedback": "a false nose-up attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Total fuel consumption is obtained by:",
    "feedback": "integrating the fuel flow with respect to time"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical flight path modes of an autopilot system are:\n\n1) pitch attitude hold\n2) altitude hold\n3) track hold\n4) glide slope intercept and track\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The anticollision logic of a TCAS II is based on the following criteria:",
    "feedback": "time"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is in steady cruise at flight level 270. The autothrottle maintains a constant calibrated airspeed. If the total temperature decreases, the Mach number :",
    "feedback": "remains constant."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot wishes to turn right on to a southerly heading with 20° bank at a latitude of 20° North. Using a direct reading compass, in order to achieve this he must stop the turn on an approximate heading of :",
    "feedback": "190°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Only one autopilot may be engaged at any time except for when APP is armed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Landing shall be considered as having been carried out automatically when the autopilot and the auto-throttle of an aircraft are disengaged by flight crew :",
    "feedback": "during ground roll."
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning direct reading magnetic compasses, in the northern hemisphere, it can be said that :",
    "feedback": "on an Easterly heading, a longitudinal acceleration causes an apparent turn to the North"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isogonals converge at the:",
    "feedback": "North and South geographic and magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the direct reading magnetic compass:",
    "feedback": "turning error is due to the vertical component of the earth's magnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the measurements to overcome the lock-in effect of a laser gyro or how can it be described?",
    "feedback": "A special processing function of the gyro is needed to measure very low rates of rotation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An isogonal",
    "feedback": "Is a line running through all positions having the same variation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) number of satellites tracked\n2) Mach number\n3) ground speed\n4) true track\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the HUD typically include?\n1) Liquid crystal display2) Computer3) Projector4) Collimator",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A direct reading compass should be swung when:",
    "feedback": "there is a large and permanent change in magnetic latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a FMS designed with the vertical navigation (VNAV) capability coupled to the autopilot, the FMS vertical command output can be:  1) an angle of attack 2) a flight path angle 3) a speed target  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pilot Flying (PF) is manually flying using the Flight Director (FD) and on a heading ATC clears the aircraft to fly direct to \"POL\" which is on the flight planned route 20° right of the current heading and 50 NM away. The Pilot Monitoring (PM) makes the appropriate selections, which are verified by the PF. What should the PF do next?",
    "feedback": "Check on the FMA that the NAV mode is engaged, and that the FD commands a turn towards POL. If it does not, ask the PM to set the heading or track mode and a suitable heading or track"
  },
  {
    "question": "The take-off warning of a large transport aeroplane must provide to the pilot an aural warning if during the initial take-off roll:\n1) one engine fails2) the longitudinal trim is not in the approved range for take-off3) take-off thrust is not fully applied\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A portable EFB ....",
    "feedback": "can be used in the aircraft but is not part of the certified aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "When engaged, the autopilot manoeuvres the aeroplane in accordance within a set of control laws. The purpose of these control laws is to ....",
    "feedback": "prevent unacceptable loads on the aeroplane or prevent hazardous deviations from the flight path"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following statement regarding magnetic variation. \nThe charted values of magnetic variation on earth normally change annually due to:",
    "feedback": "magnetic pole movement causing numerical values at all locations to increase or decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following correctly lists some inputs for a TAWS?",
    "feedback": "The correct answers are: Air Data System, IRS, ILS, radio altimeter, FMS and GPS, FMS and GPS only"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight envelope protection function(s) consist(s) in:\n\n1) automatically performing an evasion manoeuvre if necessary\n2) preventing the aircraft from exceeding the limits for specific flight parameters\n3) alerting the flight crew in case of dangerous proximity with a threatening traffic\n4) preventing any incursion beyond an ATC clearance\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ADC (Air Data Computer) uses the following parameters as input data:",
    "feedback": "Static pressure, total pressure, total air temperature (TAT)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can eventually be included in the EFB?",
    "feedback": "Performance calculations, mass and balance tables, AFM, OFP, etc."
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic synchronisation function of an autopilot control system:  1) operates only when the autopilot is engaged 2) prevents the aircraft's control system from jerking when disengaging the autopilot 3) prevents the aircraft's control system from jerking when engaging the autopilot4) works in approach, heading and nav mode  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "At sea level, on a typical servo altimeter, the tolerance in feet from indicated must not exceed :",
    "feedback": "+/-30 feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "The printer is connected to a(n) ......",
    "feedback": "external bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pendulum type detector system of the directional gyro feeds :",
    "feedback": "a levelling erection torque motor"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a 180º steep turn is made to the right and the aircraft is rolled out to straight and level flight by visual reference, the miniature aircraft on the Attitude Indicator will ...",
    "feedback": "show a slight climb and turn to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle of attack transmitter placed laterally on the forward part of the fuselage supplies an electrical signal which can indicate the angular position of:\n\n1) a specific slaved pitot probe\n2) a vane detector\n3) a conical slotted probe\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the magnetic heading if the deviation is -2°?",
    "feedback": "088°(M)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rotary mode-selector knob (CTR) of the EFIS ND allows the crew to select ......",
    "feedback": "MAP-EXP-ARC-PLAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compass needle marked red",
    "feedback": "Is called \"The North-seeking Pole\""
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft in the northern hemisphere makes an accurate rate one turn to the right/starboard. If the initial heading was 330°, after 30 seconds of the turn the direct reading magnetic compass should read",
    "feedback": "less than 060°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following lists all the stages of flight when it is possible to change the route in the active flight plan on an FMS equipped aircraft?",
    "feedback": "At any time before take-off and throughout the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an autopilot coupled approach, GO AROUND mode is engaged:",
    "feedback": "by the pilot pushing a button located on the throttles."
  },
  {
    "question": "According to CS25, a CVR (Cockpit Voice Recorder) must record:\n\n1) communications transmitted from or received in the aircraft by radio\n2) communications of flight crew members on the flight deck\n3) communications of flight crew members on the flight deck using the aircraft's interphone system\n4) audio signals identifying navigation or approach aids introduced into a headset or speaker.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Inertial Strapdown Unit of an IRS is programmed with co-ordinates during alignment in order to:",
    "feedback": "establish the trihedron with reference to the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "A temperature sensor has a recovery factor of 0.95. The temperature measured is equal to:",
    "feedback": "static air temperature (SAT) + 95% of the ram rise"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Altitude Select System:",
    "feedback": "Is annunciated by light and/or sound when airplane is approaching selected altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The outputs of the EGPWS are:\n1) Pitch up command to the AFCS2) Verbal aural alert3) Verbal aural warning4) Aural klaxon alert5) Terrain shown on the ND",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "An automatic flight control system (AFCS) series actuator is:",
    "feedback": "displayed in the cockpit as a function of input and output signals"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens when the static pressure supply, to a Vertical Speed Indicator, becomes blocked during a descent?",
    "feedback": "Reading gradually reduces to zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "After an aircraft has passed through a volcanic cloud, the total pressure probe inlet of the airspeed indicator is blocked. \nThe pilot begins a stabilized descent and finds that the IAS:",
    "feedback": "decreases steadily"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the barometric subscale of the altimeter is adjusted to 1013.2 hPa, what type of altitude is being measured?",
    "feedback": "Pressure altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is flying at FL 300 with a TAS of 470 kts in standard conditions. The Mach number is:",
    "feedback": "0.80"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying a CAT IIIB approach with no visual references, no decision height, and below the alert height. An ILS indication failure is displayed, all other parameters working as normal.\nWhat should you do as the pilot monitoring?",
    "feedback": "Continue as pilot monitoring until landing"
  },
  {
    "question": "An automatic landing is carried out when the automatic pilot :",
    "feedback": "and the autothrottle ensure a correct final approach, at least up to ground roll"
  },
  {
    "question": "The static air temperature (SAT) is :",
    "feedback": "the ambient outside air temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "When Enhanced GPWS (EGPWS) terrain is displayed, if the computed aircraft position becomes less accurate:",
    "feedback": "the terrain display will diverge from the real terrain environment around the aircraft position"
  },
  {
    "question": "An EFIS includes the following components:",
    "feedback": "symbol generator, display unit(s), control panel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The source of the data displayed on the Primary Flight Display (PFD) and Navigation Display (ND) are:\n1) Inertial Navigation System\n2) FMS\n3) weather radar\n4) radio altimeter\n5) ADC\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What implications may arise in case of an EFB malfunction in a fully electronic flight deck environment?\n1) Erroneous ECAM alerts2) Erroneous performance calculations3) Access to ACARS is unavailable4) Access to charts and manuals is unavailable",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "When turning right from 330°(C) to 040°(C) in the northern hemisphere, the reading of a direct reading magnetic compass will:",
    "feedback": "under-indicate the turn and liquid swirl will increase the effect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Four scenarios of VOR axis interception are represented in the picture. The one corresponding to the optimal interception path calculated by a flight director is number :",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete the following sentence:\nYour aircraft is equipped with TCAS II and another aircraft in close proximity is also equipped with TCAS II. The intruder will be displayed as a (1) .... on the ND, and a (2) .... aural message will be generated in case of a climbing RA.",
    "feedback": "(1) solid red square, (2) CLIMB - CLIMB"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pressure altimeters are calibrated to ISA conditions. Temperature deviations may lead to errors and for this reason, the altimeter correction table is required and used. This is because when the temperature is ......",
    "feedback": "lower than ISA, the aircraft will be lower than the altimeter reading"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"Landing Compass\"",
    "feedback": "Is used to establish aircraft magnetic heading during a compass swing"
  },
  {
    "question": "The transmitter of RPM indicator may consist of :\n1- a magnetic sensor supplying an induced AC voltage\n2- a DC generator supplying a DC voltage\n3- a single-phase AC generator supplying an AC voltage\n4- a three-phase AC generator supplying a three-phase voltage\nThe combination of correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,2,3,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The colour red in an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS) indicates:",
    "feedback": "Warnings, flight envelope and system limits"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pitot blockage of both the ram air input and the drain hole with the static port open causes the airspeed indicator to :",
    "feedback": "react like an altimeter."
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum directional gyro error due to the earth rotation is:",
    "feedback": "15°/hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, integrating once the speed in gives:",
    "feedback": "a distance travelled"
  },
  {
    "question": "When decelerating on a westerly heading in the Northern hemisphere, the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass will turn :",
    "feedback": "clockwise giving an apparent turn toward the south"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parallax error is:",
    "feedback": "a reading error"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle between Magnetic North and Compass North is called:",
    "feedback": "compass deviation"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the auto throttle be used for limit protection?",
    "feedback": "A/T arm without selecting a speed or N1 target"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a multi crew aircraft you have a Pilot Flying (PF) and a Pilot Monitoring (PM). What are the roles and responsibilities of each of the pilots?",
    "feedback": "PF flies the aircraft or monitors the autopilot, PM has some similar functions, other ancillary functions and does the radios"
  },
  {
    "question": "A line drawn on a chart which joins all points where the value of magnetic variation is zero is called an:",
    "feedback": "agonic line"
  },
  {
    "question": "A TCAS Resolution Advisory (RA) voice message \"CLIMB - CLIMB NOW\" repeated twice is generated:",
    "feedback": "after a \"DESCEND\" RA when a reversal in the vertical manoeuvre sense is required"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the colours used are:",
    "feedback": "red for flight envelope and system limits, green for autopilot or flight director engaged modes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position error of a stand alone inertial system is approximately:",
    "feedback": "0.5 to 2 NM per hour"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the GPWS is ....",
    "feedback": "to provide information and alert the pilots of a potentially hazardous terrain situation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will cause a MASTER CAUTION alert?",
    "feedback": "Anti-skid system fault"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Flight Data Recorder makes use of ......",
    "feedback": "a recording system, an \"event\" button, and an underwater locating device"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following variables affect deviation?  1) Magnetic latitude 2) Aircraft heading 3) Aircraft altitude 4) Aircraft electronic equipment  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot basic modes include, among other things, the following functions :\n\n1- pitch attitude hold \n2- pressure altitude hold\n3- horizontal  wing hold\n4- heading hold \n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alternate static source of a light non-pressurized aircraft is located in the flight deck. As the alternate static source is opened, the vertical speed indicator may:",
    "feedback": "indicate a momentary climb"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS overfly function consists in:",
    "feedback": "manually selecting a flight plan waypoint to fly over when sequencing it instead of flying by at the transition"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following points are entered into an inertial navigation system (INS). WPT 1: 60°N 30°W WPT 2: 60°N 20°W WPT 3: 60°N 10°W The inertial navigation system is connected to the automatic pilot on route (1-2-3). The track change when passing WPT 2 will be approximately:",
    "feedback": "a 9° decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "The quantity of fuel in the tanks is measured by capacitor type contents gauges. The working principle of these sensors is to measure the :",
    "feedback": "charge of condensors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about computer architecture are correct or incorrect?  1) Multitasking and multiprocessing are based on the same hardware configuration 2) The multitasking method is a software solution",
    "feedback": "1 is incorrect, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter is based upon the same principle as:",
    "feedback": "The aneroid barometer."
  },
  {
    "question": "The horizontal command bar of a flight director:",
    "feedback": "gives information about the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to be applied on the pitch of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical command bar of a flight director:",
    "feedback": "gives information about the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to be applied on the bank of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Check the following answers regarding the angle of attack probes:\n1) The vane detector is a counter balanced aerodynamic vane2) Only the null-seeking (slotted) probe contains a heating function",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main function of a compass needle?",
    "feedback": "To determine the direction of the horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight control system is fail-operational if, in the event of a failure:",
    "feedback": "the approach, flare and landing can be completed automatically"
  },
  {
    "question": "During preflight check, serviceability of a direct reading standby compass indication can be compared preferably with:\n1) Runway direction during line-up2) Main compass indication3) Test VOR indication4) An ADF bearing5) An Airborne Weather Radar bearing\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The airspeed indicator circuit consists of pressure sensors. The pitot tube directly supplies:",
    "feedback": "the total pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is following ATC vectors for the purpose of weather avoidance. It is currently flying parallel to its FMS flight plan route with a lateral offset of 20 NM to the left. The crew is then instructed to return to the flight planned route. The autoflight system is set to LNAV and the NAV mode is displayed as armed on the flight mode annunciator (FMA)\nWhat will happen when the aircraft arrives abeam the next waypoint on the FMS planned route at which a right turn is programmed?",
    "feedback": "It will turn right direct towards the next waypoint on the FMS flight plan"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a basic computer (\"Von Neumann architecture\" type) the memory:",
    "feedback": "holds both instructions and data"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot of a modern, large turbojet aeroplane sets the vertical speed mode of the autopilot to carry out a climb. What must the pilot be particularly careful of?",
    "feedback": "If the climb is prolonged, there is a risk that the airspeed may reduce towards the stall"
  },
  {
    "question": "The properties of a gyroscope are:\n\n1 - rigidity in space\n2 - rigidity on earth\n3 - precession\n4 - Schuler oscillations\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The auto-throttle system:",
    "feedback": "can be used for take-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "When descending through an isothermal layer at a constant Calibrated Airspeed (CAS), the True Airspeed (TAS) will:",
    "feedback": "decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft and an intruding aircraft both are TCAS II equipped. If the transponder of the intruder is switched off or unserviceable:",
    "feedback": "the intruding aircraft is invisible to your TCAS equipment"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the autothrust system is ......",
    "feedback": "to maintain the required engine thrust for the corresponding flight regime"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about computer architecture are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) The software part does not include the programmes that make up the operating system (OS)\n2) The hardware part does not include the physical components of the computer",
    "feedback": "1 is incorrect, 2 is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct concerning an autopilot system performing an autoland and engaged in the ROLL-OUT mode?",
    "feedback": "The autopilot uses the ILS signals and manipulates the rudder and nose wheel steering in order to stay on the runway center line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning FMC databases:",
    "feedback": "the navigation database may be customized for the specific airline operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under normal operating conditions, when an aircraft is in a banked turn, the rate-of-turn indicator is a valuable gyroscopic flight control instrument ; when it is associated with an attitude indicator it indicates :\n\n1. the angular velocity of the aircraft about the yaw axis\n2. The bank of the aircraft\n3. The direction of the aircraft turn\n4. The angular velocity of the aircraft about the real vertical\n\nThe combination of correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,3."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the navigation display (ND) of an EFIS equipped aircraft, the colours used are:",
    "feedback": "magenta or white for the active waypoint (TO waypoint), green for light precipitation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is flying at FL 180 and Mach number 0.36. The indicated total air temperature is -5°C.\n\nConsidering that the probe recovery coefficient is 0.84, the present weather conditions compared with the standard atmosphere are:",
    "feedback": "Standard + 10°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "The correction of the control surface deflection made by the automatic pilot calculator in order to stabilize the longitudinal attitude will be all the more significant as the :\n\n1- difference between the reference attitude and the instantaneous attitude is high.\n2- rate of change of the difference between the reference attitude and the instantaneous attitude is high.\n3- temperature is low.\n4- pressure altitude is high.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2."
  },
  {
    "question": "The component of a FMS used to enter flight plan routing and performance parameters is the:",
    "feedback": "Multi-Function Control Display Unit (MCDU)"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the initial alignment of an inertial navigation system (INS) the equipment:",
    "feedback": "will not accept a 10° error in initial latitude but will accept a 10° error in initial longitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum TAS is obtained at:",
    "feedback": "the Flight Level at which simultaneously CAS = VMO and M = MMO"
  },
  {
    "question": "The resultant of the second integration from the North/South accelerometer of an Inertial Navigation System (INS) in the NAV mode is:",
    "feedback": "distance North/South"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nPt = total pressure\nPs = static pressure\nPso = static pressure at sea level\n\nCalibrated airspeed (CAS) is a function of:",
    "feedback": "Pt-Ps"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic poles are the two positions on the Earth's surface where the lines of the magnetic field:",
    "feedback": "are entirely vertical"
  },
  {
    "question": "The two main sources of information used to calculate turbojet thrust are the:",
    "feedback": "fan rotation speed (or N1) or the EPR (Engine Pressure Ratio)."
  },
  {
    "question": "A modern computer makes use of different internal buses to:",
    "feedback": "Transfer address-, data-, and control signals"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the magnetic heading if the deviation is -3°?",
    "feedback": "087°(M)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Is there, by convention, a difference between an INS and an IRS?",
    "feedback": "Yes, the INS is an older system based on a stabilised platform and mechanical gyros, while the IRS is a more modern, fixed system based on ring laser gyros or fibre optic gyros"
  },
  {
    "question": "An automatic landing system which can keep on operating without deterioration of its performances following the failure of one of the autopilots is called \"FAIL...:",
    "feedback": "\"OPERATIONAL\""
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS warns the crew in case of:\n\n1) deviation above or below the selected altitude\n2) deviation below the selected altitude\n3) unsafe terrain clearance with flaps not in landing configuration\n4) unsafe terrain clearance with landing gear not down\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in climb when the pilots receive an ACAS Resolution Advisory to descend. They must follow the RA immediately because the ACAS system anticipates:",
    "feedback": "Their response will be correct and timely"
  },
  {
    "question": "What value is selected by the heading selector (heading bug)?",
    "feedback": "120°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main advantage of the Enhanced Visual System (EVS) over Synthetic Vision (SVS)?",
    "feedback": "The EVS equipped aircraft can benefit from lower minimas"
  },
  {
    "question": "When climbing at a constant CAS in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "TAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), the following fuel data may be displayed:\n1) Fuel density\n2) Fuel quantity in each tank\n3) Total fuel quantity\n4) Fuel temperature\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alternate static source of a light non-pressurized aircraft is located in the flight deck. When used:\n\n1) the airspeed indicator tends to under-read\n2) the airspeed indicator tends to over-read\n3) the altimeter tends to under-read\n4) the altimeter tends to over-read\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Southern hemisphere, during deceleration following a landing in an Easterly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "an apparent turn to the North."
  },
  {
    "question": "A MEL item is found before start-up. Due to possible performance changes, the flight crew wants to correctly consider this when on the FMS \"INIT\" page.  How can this be done?",
    "feedback": "The FMS does not take into account the MEL items"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the absence of position and instrument errors, IAS is equal to:",
    "feedback": "CAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The systems that can be connected to the Communication Management Unit (CMU) are:\n\n1) Flight Director\n2) FMS\n3) Multipurpose Control and Display (MCDU)\n4) communication unit (VHF, HF, Satcom)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a Slaved Gyro Compass System the output of the flux-valve is fed to:",
    "feedback": "the stator in the slaved gyro control."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a turn and bank indicator, if the needle is deflected and the ball is centered, the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "Yawing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the activation of the take-off warning when a take-off is initiated are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) An aural warning is given when the elevator is not in a safe position for take-off\n2) An aural warning is given when the parking brake is still ON",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the errors inherent in a ring laser gyroscope occurs at low input rotation rates tending towards zero when a phenomenon known as 'lock-in' is experienced. What is the name of the technique, effected by means of a piezo-electric motor, that is used to correct this error?",
    "feedback": "dither"
  },
  {
    "question": "A semi-automatic landing system disconnects itself automatically:",
    "feedback": "at approximately 100 ft."
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight director provides information for the pilot:",
    "feedback": "to join to a desired path with the optimum attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the properties of a simple bar magnet are correct or incorrect?\n1) North or south poles cannot exist separately2) Magnetism is concentrated at the extremities of the bar",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft engine thrust characteristics are stored in the:",
    "feedback": "Performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Primary Flight Display (PFD) of an EFIS equipped aircraft can display information relative to the following conditions:",
    "feedback": "altitude capture, TCAS resolution advisory, autopilot and flight director mode changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"sensor part\" of the flux-valve is:",
    "feedback": "The three pick-up coils."
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical command bar of a flight director:\n\n1) repeats the position information given by the ILS in the horizontal plane\n2) repeats the position information given by the ILS in the vertical plane\n3) gives information about the direction and the amplitude of the corrections to be applied on the bank of the aircraft\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying manually with the Flight Director (FD) engaged. When both FD bars cross in the centre of the aircraft symbol, it means that....",
    "feedback": "your aircraft is in the optimum attitude computed for the planned flight path"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hard iron magnetism in aircraft may be caused by",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The response time of a vertical speed detector may be decreased by adding a:",
    "feedback": "correction based on an accelerometer sensor."
  },
  {
    "question": "The static pressure error of the static vent on which the altimeter is connected varies substantially with the:",
    "feedback": "Mach number of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an approach, the pilot uses the Flight Director System (FDS), combining the flight director with the autopilot. Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "The autopilot manipulates the control surfaces of the aircraft in response to the steering commands provided by the FDS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft and an intruding traffic both are TCAS II equipped. Your TCAS determines the bearing of the intruding aircraft by:",
    "feedback": "using a specific directional antenna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Match groundspeed (GS) with the associated definition:",
    "feedback": "Actual speed of an aircraft over ground."
  },
  {
    "question": "A flux valve detects the horizontal component of the Earth's magnetic field.\n\n1- the flux valve is made of a pair of soft iron bars\n2- the information can be used by a \"flux gate\" compass or a directional gyro\n3- the flux gate valve signal comes from the error detector\n4- the error in the value of the magnetic field indication is less than 0,5%\n\nWhich of the following combinations contains all of the correct statements?",
    "feedback": "2 - 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The interception of a localizer beam by the autopilot takes place :",
    "feedback": "at a constant heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the flight warning system (FWS), warning messages:",
    "feedback": "are highest priority alert messages"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA) is correct?",
    "feedback": "If the mode changes, a caption on the Electronic Attitude Direction Indicator will change colour or appearance"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS is approved to provide guidance for the following approaches:",
    "feedback": "non precision approaches."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the airspeed indicator of a twin-engine aeroplane, the blue radial line corresponds to:",
    "feedback": "best single-engine rate of climb"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to measure temperature the cylinder head temperature (CHT) gauge utilises a :",
    "feedback": "thermocouple consisting of two dissimilar metals."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying with a constant Mach number of 0.70 at FL390. The autothrottle is engaged while passing a cold front. The actual outside air temperatur is dropping by a few degrees. Which of the following statements about the situation is correct?",
    "feedback": "IAS increases, TAS decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compared with a conventional gyro, a laser gyro :",
    "feedback": "has a longer life cycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Digital instruments with a speed tape provide VMO/MMO indications. Typically, these indications are represented as:",
    "feedback": "bottom of a striped bar located on the upper part of the speed tape"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cockpit voice recorder must preserve the conversation and aural warnings of the last :",
    "feedback": "30 minutes of operation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compressibility correction to CAS to give EAS:\n\n1) may be positive\n2) is always negative\n3) depends on the Mach number only\n4) depends on pressure altitude only\n\nThe combination regrouping the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IAS or Mach hold mode is provided by:\n\n1) the autopilot pitch channel in the climb mode at a constant IAS or Mach number\n2) the auto-throttles in the climb mode at a constant IAS or Mach number\n3) the autopilot pitch channel in the altitude or glide path holding mode\n4) the auto-throttles in the altitude or glide path holding mode\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS enables to fly an optimum flight profile. For this, the FMC (Flight Management Computer) uses:\n\n1) flight-crew entered flight plan data\n2) data from ADC\n3) aircraft position\n4) a memorised relief world data base\n5) data from the FMC navigation data base\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Double integration of the output from the east/west accelerometer of an inertial navigation system (INS) in the NAV MODE give:",
    "feedback": "distance east/west"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the northern hemisphere, an aircraft takes-off on a runway with an alignment of 045°. During the take-off run, the compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "a value below 045°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the fuel mass unit is correct?",
    "feedback": "1 kg = 2.2 lb"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering how altitude is displayed on aircraft equipped with EFIS. Which of the following designs or features are used?\n1) Numerical indication of the maximum certified altitude2) Rolling altitude scale with a numerical indication of the current altitude3) Numerical indication of the current outside pressure setting in hPa4) Indication or bug for the selected altitude",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A stand-by-horizon or emergency attitude indicator:",
    "feedback": "Contains its own separate gyro"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rate of turn indicator uses a gyroscope:\n\n1) the spinning wheel axis of which is parallel to the yawing axis\n2) the spinning wheel axis of which is parallel to the pitch axis\n3) the spinning wheel axis of which is parallel to the roll axis\n4) with one degree of freedom\n5) with two degrees of freedom\n\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The atmospheric pressure at FL 70 in a \"standard + 10°\" atmosphere is:",
    "feedback": "782 hPa"
  },
  {
    "question": "The EPR (Engine Pressure Ratio) is:",
    "feedback": "the ratio of the turbine outlet total pressure to the compressor inlet total pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the autopilot Control Wheel Steering (CWS) mode is:",
    "feedback": "to consider as target parameters, the current pitch and roll angles at the time the mode becomes active"
  },
  {
    "question": "To indicate a temperature, a thermocouple requires:",
    "feedback": "no power supply"
  },
  {
    "question": "Note: For this question, only consider the system as a standalone part not including other aircraft systems that may also be affected by the scenario.\nAn Air-Data Inertial Reference Unit (ADIRU) has separate controls for switching the air data and inertial reference part ON or OFF. Following a procedure to address a fault the pilot accidentally switches OFF the incorrect system. Which of the following are correct?\n1) If the air-data part is switched OFF instead of the inertial reference part, there is no effect as the data can be recovered when the air-data part is switched back on2) If the air-data part is switched OFF instead of the inertial reference part, the function is severely limited as the air-data part cannot be initialised when switched back on3) If the inertial reference part is switched OFF instead of the air-data part, the function is severely limited as the inertial reference part cannot be fully re-aligned when switched back on4) If the inertial reference part is switched OFF instead of the air-data part, there is no effect as the data can be recovered when the inertial reference part is switched back on",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A line running through positions where the magnetic and the true meridians are parallel, is called",
    "feedback": "An agonic line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the alignment procedure for Inertial Navigation Systems(INS)/Inertial Reference Systems (IRS) at mid-latitudes is correct?",
    "feedback": "INS/IRS can be aligned in either the ALIGN or NAV mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying level in the cruise the ...... holds altitude and the ...... holds the speed",
    "feedback": "autopilot; autothrottle"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a multi-engine aircraft, a synchroscope is used to:\n1) Reduce structural vibration and noise\n2) Have symmetrical thrust and fuel consumption",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "What states can an auto throttle be in?\n1) Armed 2) Active 3) disconnected  Which answer comprises all correct states?",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Soft iron magnetism in aircraft",
    "feedback": "Is non-permanent of nature, and cannot be reduced by de-gaussing (de-magnetisation)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the automatic trim is to:  1- reduce to zero the hinge moment of the entire control surface in order to relieve the load on the servo-actuator 2- ensure the aeroplane is properly trimmed when the autopilot is disengaged 3- maintain the same stability/manoeuverablity trade-off within the whole flight envelope  The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "The following information can be displayed on the Navigation Display (ND) with the MAP (or ARC) mode:\n1) Selected and current heading\n2) Next waypoint distance\n3) Weather radar information\n4) Autopilot mode\n5) Landing capacity\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The copilot's PFD LCD fails. What happens?",
    "feedback": "The PFD of the copilot is shown on the copilot's ND"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason for mounting the detector unit of a remote reading compass in the wingtip of an aeroplane is:",
    "feedback": "to minimise the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits"
  },
  {
    "question": "Machmeter readings are subject to:",
    "feedback": "position pressure error"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following ATC clearances can be received via the datalink application:",
    "feedback": "departure, oceanic"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the approach, a crew reads on the radio altimeter the value of 650 ft. This is an indication of the true:",
    "feedback": "height of the lowest wheels with regard to the ground at any time."
  },
  {
    "question": "The properties of a gyroscope are:\n\n1) rigidity in space\n2) rigidity on earth\n3) precession\n4) Schuler oscillations\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to give the flight crew control of the required lateral guidance functions, the RNAV equipment should be able to perform several of functions.  Which of the following are these functions?",
    "feedback": "select or enter the required flight plan through the Control and Display Unit (CDU)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper system is operative:",
    "feedback": "during manual or automatic flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMC determines and updates present aircraft position from the following systems:\n\n1) SATCOM\n2) GPS\n3) DME\n4) IRS\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a modern transport category aeroplane, the engagement of the automatic pilot is checked on the display of:",
    "feedback": "the PFD (Primary Flight Display)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The drift of the gyroscopes of a stand alone inertial system:",
    "feedback": "is the main error source"
  },
  {
    "question": "Direct reading magnetic compass errors are:",
    "feedback": "due to north change, depending on the bank angle and magnetic heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "A remote reading compass is fitted with a free/slave switch. \"Free\" is selected when the compass is synchronised. What supplies the magnetic data?",
    "feedback": "The magnetic data is not provided to the remote reading compass when \"free\" is selected"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nPt = total pressure\nPs = static pressure\n\nDynamic pressure is:",
    "feedback": "Pt-Ps"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct with regard to INS/IRS?",
    "feedback": "Inertial navigation is a method of deduced (dead) reckoning"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight director is engaged in the heading select mode (HDG SEL), heading 180° selected. When heading is 160°, the vertical bar of the FD:",
    "feedback": "is centered if the bank angle of the aircraft is equal to the bank angle computed by the flight director computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mach number is equal to:\n(\"a\" indicates the local speed of sound)",
    "feedback": "TAS/a"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying in cold air (colder than standard atmosphere), the altimeter will:",
    "feedback": "over-read."
  },
  {
    "question": "To obtain the instantaneous speed from the acceleration, it is necessary to:\n\n1) integrate once the acceleration in time\n2) know the initial position\n3) know the initial speed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The force of attraction or repulsion between two magnets:",
    "feedback": "varies inversely as the square of the distance between them"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"airspeed hold\" mode can be engaged and maintained during:",
    "feedback": "climbs, descents, turns and power changes"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, the unit which ensures sequencing and co-ordination of operations is (are) the:",
    "feedback": "control unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), the following fuel flow parameters may be displayed:\n1) Present fuel flow of each engine\n2) Mean fuel flow over 1 minute\n3) Maximum admissible fuel flow\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the FMS temperature compensation function is:",
    "feedback": "to provide compensated altitudes for temperatures different from ISA along the vertical approach profile."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the HUD data related to the data from the PFD?",
    "feedback": "The HUD data is replicated from the PFD"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of a laser gyro is based on:",
    "feedback": "frequency difference between two laser beams rotating in opposite direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is flying at FL150 in an aircraft equipped with a modern EADI (Electronic Attitude Director Indicator). Which of the data listed below is likely to be displayed on the EADI in this phase of the flight?\n1) Attitude information2) Flight director command bars3) Heading and track4) Radio height",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operation of the GPWS (Ground Proximity Warning System) is governed by laws taking the aircraft height into account as well as :\n1- the descent rate\n2- the climb rate\n3- the aircraft configuration\n4- the selected engine rpm\nThe combination of correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an automatic landing, from a height of about 50 ft the:",
    "feedback": "autopilot maintains a vertical speed depending on the radio altimeter height."
  },
  {
    "question": "TAS is obtained from EAS by correcting for:",
    "feedback": "density error"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a descent at a constant IAS below the tropopause in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "Mach number and TAS decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "The notification phase (LOG ON) is a FANS application which consists in:",
    "feedback": "establishing air/ground connection to verify if the datalink communication can be performed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct regarding an Inertial Reference System (IRS)?",
    "feedback": "Once the IRS is aligned, the NAV mode should be selected"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shown are figures presenting a pilot's view from an aeroplane that is equipped with a head-up display (HUD). Which figure(s) present(s) the information that the pilot is able to select to view through the HUD?",
    "feedback": "Figure 1 only"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning a fuel gauge system, a pilot is more interested by the:",
    "feedback": "mass of the fuel than the volume of the fuel"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an engine vibration monitoring system for a turbojet any vibration produced by the engine is :",
    "feedback": "amplified and filtered before being fed to the cockpit indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of the vertical speed indicator (VSI) is based on the measurement of the rate of change of:",
    "feedback": "Static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "For which non-standard configuration can an FMS normally compute the fuel prediction?",
    "feedback": "One engine inoperative"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the TAS input, from the air data computer, to the Inertial Navigation System is for:",
    "feedback": "the calculation of wind velocity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the Flight Director (FD)?",
    "feedback": "It helps the crew with attitude control and guidance tasks"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common system used to monitor turbine gas exhaust temperature is the:",
    "feedback": "hot and cold junction, alumel/chromel system."
  },
  {
    "question": "The sustained oscillation in the Ring Laser Gyro (RLG) is initially caused by",
    "feedback": "the gas (or plasma) inside the triangular cavity is ionised by the voltage, causing \nhelium atoms to collide with and transfer energy to the neon atoms."
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a modern thrust computer, during a steady climb:",
    "feedback": "N1 is automatically adjusted as aircraft climbs"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Head Up Display (HUD) is a device allowing the pilot, while still looking outside, to have:",
    "feedback": "a synthetic view of the instrument procedure."
  },
  {
    "question": "An airspeed indicator includes a capsule; inside this capsule is:",
    "feedback": "total pressure and outside is static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field:",
    "feedback": "is approximately the same at magnetic latitudes 50°N and 50°S"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical speed indicator (VSI)  is fed by :",
    "feedback": "static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The calibrated airspeed (CAS) is obtained by applying to the indicated airspeed (IAS) :",
    "feedback": "an instrument and position/pressure error correction."
  },
  {
    "question": "Mode \"Localizer ARM\" active on Flight Director means:",
    "feedback": "System is armed for localizer approach and coupling will occur upon capturing center line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Today's airspeed indicators (calibrated to the Saint-Venant formula), indicate, in the absence of static (and instrumental) error :",
    "feedback": "The calibrated airspeed (CAS) in all cases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The quadrantal deviation of a magnetic compass is corrected by using:",
    "feedback": "pairs of permanent magnets"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auto throttle can hold which of the following:\n1) IAS2) Mach number3) Altitude4) N1/EPR5) VOR capture6) Vertical profile",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a large aeroplane and according to the CS 25: the stall warning system must provide an alarm with sufficient margin to prevent inadvertent stalling:",
    "feedback": "with the flaps and landing gear in any normal position"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft flight envelope computations is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "Performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the loss of alignment by an Inertial Reference System (IRS) in flight is correct?",
    "feedback": "The navigation mode, including present position and ground speed outputs, is inoperative for the remainder of the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "When climbing at a constant CAS through an isothermal layer, the Mach number:",
    "feedback": "increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Match true airspeed (TAS) with the associated definition:",
    "feedback": "Calibrated airspeed corrected for altitude and non-standard temperature."
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer architecture, which of these statements about a bus are correct or incorrect?  1) A bus ensures sequencing and co-ordination of operations 2) A bus transfers data between computer components",
    "feedback": "1 is incorrect, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are typical inputs to a Flight Management System (FMS)?",
    "feedback": "Air Data computer (ADC) data"
  },
  {
    "question": "The systems than can be connected to the Communication Management Unit (CMU) are:\n1) EGPWS2) HF Communication Unit3) Multipurpose Control and Display Unit (MCDU)4) VHF Communication Unit5) Satcom\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following statements is true with regard to the operation of a Mach trim system :",
    "feedback": "It only operates above a pre-determined Mach number."
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the airspeed indicator, IAS is:",
    "feedback": "the indicated reading on the instrument"
  },
  {
    "question": "Coefficient A is corrected for",
    "feedback": "Moving the compass housing around its vertical axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System (INS), the main causes of cumulative distance errors are",
    "feedback": "wander in the levelling gyros and integrator errors in the second stage of integration."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft is moved to a place of lower magnetic latitude",
    "feedback": "The deviation values will decrease because the horizontal component of the terrestrial field is becoming stronger"
  },
  {
    "question": "With reference to inertial navigation systems, a TAS input is:",
    "feedback": "required to provide a W/V read out"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning INS and IRS, which statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "Only the IRS is rigidly fixed to the aircraft chassis (strapped-down)"
  },
  {
    "question": "ACARS systems consist of:",
    "feedback": "on-board units and ground units"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does lag error in an Instantaneous VSI (IVSI) compare to that in a normal VSI?",
    "feedback": "It is virtually eliminated by using an acceleration pump."
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer technology, an example of an output peripheral is a:",
    "feedback": "screen unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Decision Height (DH) warning light comes on when an aircraft:",
    "feedback": "descends below a pre-set radio altitude."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nC = the temperature in Celsius\nK = the temperature in Kelvin\nF = the temperature in Fahrenheit\n\nWhich of these statements about temperature units are correct or incorrect?\n1) C = K + 273\n2) F = (C x 1.8) + 32",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The radio altimeter uses the following wavelenghts:",
    "feedback": "centimetric"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering the relationship between CAS and EAS:",
    "feedback": "EAS is always lower than or equal to CAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describe a bar magnet?\n1) Opposite poles attract2) The North pole of a freely suspended bar magnet would turn towards North, which is a South magnetic pole3) Magnetic force is strongest in the centre of the magnet4) Magnetic force is stongest a short way in form the poles of the magnet5) Opposite poles repel6) A freely suspended magnet would dip down towards the near pole",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "To avoid a collision, an ACAS may issue:",
    "feedback": "Command orders in the vertical plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "The combined Mach meter / ASI ist subject to the following errors:",
    "feedback": "position, density, instrument, compressibility, manoeuvre induced"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), the following EGT parameters may be displayed:\n1) Instantaneous EGT\n2) Commanded EGT\n3) Maximum continuous EGT limit\n4) Maximum takeoff EGT limit\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a trim system of a large transport aeroplane is to:",
    "feedback": "adjust the neutral position of a control surface"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the option which groups all the correct statements regarding the Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS):\n1) The Navigation Display (ND) displays Flight Director bars2) The altimeter setting is displayed on the Primary Flight Display (PFD)3) The PFD is the main flying instrument4) The Flight Mode Annunciator (FMA) is part of the ND",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gyrocompassing of an inertial reference system (IRS) is accomplished with the mode selector switched to:",
    "feedback": "ALIGN"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by the \"performance factor\"?",
    "feedback": "A percentage that must be applied to get a better fuel burn prediction from the FMS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The command bars of a flight director are displayed on an:",
    "feedback": "ADI"
  },
  {
    "question": "After having programmed your flight director, you see that the indications of your ADI (Attitude Director Indicator) are as represented in diagram N°1. On this instrument, the command bars indicate that you must bank your airplane to the left and :",
    "feedback": "increase the flight attitude until the command bars recentre on the symbolic airplane."
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram representing straight and level flight is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "What time is left for a pilot to respond to an EGPWS warning alert before htting terrain?",
    "feedback": "20 to 30 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main limitations of the Synthetic Vision System (SVS)?",
    "feedback": "The terrain is created from a database that needs to be updated regularly and there is a risk of CFIT in case of reduced aircraft position accuracy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rotary mode-selector knob (CTR) of the EFIS ND allows the crew to select ......",
    "feedback": "an aircraft symbol in the centre or in the lower part of the screen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average position error of the Inertial Navigation System?",
    "feedback": "1.5 NM per hour or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic principle of a capacitance fuel gauge system is that the:",
    "feedback": "capacity of a capacitor depends on the nature of the dielectric in which it is immersed"
  },
  {
    "question": "When accelerating on a westerly heading in the Northern hemisphere, the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass will turn:",
    "feedback": "anti-clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the deviation when flying on a heading of 332°(C)?",
    "feedback": "2°W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Following 180° stabilized turn with a constant attitude and bank, the artificial horizon indicates (assume air-driven and turning clockwise, when viewed from above):",
    "feedback": "too high pitch-up and correct banking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are main components of a CVR?\n1) Two control units (start sequence, event mark setting)2) An area microphone3) A control unit with the following controls: auto/on, test and erase, and a headset jack4) Limited flight-deck controls such as erase and test switches5) Limited flight-deck controls but includes an event switch6) A shock-resistant tape recorder or digital storage associated with an underwater locating device beacon (ULB)",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying with an indicated altitude of 3000 ft into a low pressure area, the actual altitude:",
    "feedback": "will decrease."
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) :",
    "feedback": "No protection is available against aircraft not equipped with a serviceable SSR transponder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of an inertial system consists in:",
    "feedback": "measuring the acceleration of the aircraft and performing integrations to elaborate the ground speed and the position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principal advantage of a gyromagnetic compass (slaved gyro compass) is:",
    "feedback": "It combines the north-seeking ability of the magnetic compass with the stability of the direction indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical flight path modes of an autopilot system are:\n\n1) FMS vertical navigation\n2) flight path angle hold\n3) glide slope intercept and track\n4) altitude hold\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the slaving torque motor is:",
    "feedback": "to produce a precessive force in order to align the gyro with the earth's magnetic field."
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of the flight director computer are:",
    "feedback": "two channels : pitch and roll."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) navigation database typically includes the following data:\n1) SID, STAR2) radio aids3) optimum flight level4) company routes5) cruise speeds\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A millivoltmeter measuring the electromotive force between the \"hot junction\" and the \"cold junction\" of a thermocouple can be directly graduated in temperature values provided that the temperature of the:",
    "feedback": "cold junction is maintained constant."
  },
  {
    "question": "On the following display, the .... is indicated by a filled (solid) diamond at your 1 o'clock position.",
    "feedback": "proximate intruder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Flight Mode Annunciator FMA is to:",
    "feedback": "check and confirm any selection made by the pilot on the autopilot control panel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMC determines and updates present aircraft position from the following systems:\n\n1) GPS\n2) IRS\n3) navigation radios\n4) ACARS\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A leak in the pitot total pressure line of a non-pressurized aircraft to an airspeed indicator would cause it to:",
    "feedback": "under-read."
  },
  {
    "question": "The airline you are working for has a FDM system in operation. What is true about the acquired information?\n1) If the pilot purposely and recklessly exceeds stated parameters and limitations, the company can put him/her under investigation2) The data will be used to find recurring adverse safety trends3) The information will be used to improve crew training",
    "feedback": "all of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is lined up on runway 24, which is aligned with a magnetic bearing of 242°. In order to comply with maximum permissible deviation errors, the direct reading magnetic compass readings should be between:",
    "feedback": "232° - 252°"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying manually in a fly-by-wire aircraft equipped with automatic pitch trim. You do not need to move the control column when:\n1) You encounter wind shear2) You change the aircraft configuration (flaps, slats)3) Change the power/thrust setting\nSelect the correct combination of statements:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A directional gyro is corrected for an apparent drift due to the earth's rotation at latitude 30°S. During a flight at latitude 60°N, a drift rate of 15.5°/h to the right is observed.\n\nThe apparent wander due to change of aircraft position is:",
    "feedback": "5°/hour to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a magnetic compass calibration is to:",
    "feedback": "determine the residual deviations"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an EFB, Type A software applications ......",
    "feedback": "must have no adverse effect on flight safety"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is flying a GNSS non-precision approach using the autopilot. The pilot intends to disconnect the autopilot on final approach after having obtained sufficient visual references to complete a manual landing. What can the pilot expect when disconnecting the autopilot using the instinctive or quick disengagement control? There will be.....",
    "feedback": "a unique autopilot disconnect aural warning and a visual warning for a limited period of time confirming that the autopilot is disconnected"
  },
  {
    "question": "By what means are messages from an Aeroplane Condition Monitoring System (ACMS) transmitted to the maintenance base?",
    "feedback": "Digital datalink, without crew notification"
  },
  {
    "question": "Without readjusting the barometric setting of the Altimeter, it will under-read when:",
    "feedback": "flying from a low pressure area into a high pressure area."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the pitot tube becomes blocked during a descent, the airspeed indicator:",
    "feedback": "under-reads"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gas turbine engine rotational speed (RPM) is usually sensed using either:",
    "feedback": "a 3 phase AC tachometer generator or an AC phonic wheel system."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft, flying at 20°N latitude, executes a left turn from 045° Magnetic Heading (MH) to 315° (MH). The pilot reads the MH indication from a Direct Reading Magnetic Compass (DRMC). Which of the following should the pilot take into consideration before commencing the turn?\n1) He/she should roll out when the DRMC reads 335°, in order to read 315° MH with the wings level2) He/she should roll out when the DRMC reads 295°, in order to read 315° MH with the wings level3) The turning error of the DRMC increases as the bank angle increases4) A timed turn would be more practical to execute; it would take 30 seconds with a rate-1 turn5) A timed turn would be more practical to execute; it would take 90 seconds with a rate-1 turn",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider a multi-engine aircraft with a synchroscope. It provides an indication of the difference in:",
    "feedback": "Speed (RPM) between the engines"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the components of a typical HUD installation?",
    "feedback": "The HUD projector, the stowable combiner, the HUD controls (declutter and dimmer), and the HUD computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying a fly-by-wire aeroplane manually, which of these statements are correct or incorrect?\n1) The automatic pitch trim system adapts the aircraft configuration (slats/flaps) according to the airspeed2) The automatic pitch trim system controls the pitch to maintain a relatively constant flight path",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time for a normal alignment (not a quick alignment) of a strapdown inertial system is:",
    "feedback": "3 to 10 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot wants to have the fuel tank filled to 70% of its capacity for the mission. Using the information above, approximately how much more fuel must be uplifted to achieve this?",
    "feedback": "109 litres"
  },
  {
    "question": "During deceleration following a landing in a southerly direction, a direct reading compass indicates:",
    "feedback": "no apparent turn."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is in steady cruise at flight level 270. The autothrottle maintains a constant calibrated airspeed. If the total temperature increases, the Mach number :",
    "feedback": "remains constant."
  },
  {
    "question": "Select from the statements below the one that applies best to an ADIRU:",
    "feedback": "ADIRU is an Air Data Computer which is integrated with an Inertial Reference Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The yellow sector of the temperature gauge corresponds to:",
    "feedback": "an exceptional operating range."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a compensated capacitance type quantity indicating system, the contents gauge of a half-full fuel tank indicates a fuel mass of 8000 kg. If a temperature rise increase the volume of fuel by 5%, the indicated fuel mass would:",
    "feedback": "remain the same"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main function of the control surface position sensors?",
    "feedback": "Comparing the directed inputs with the actual surface movement"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens when the ADIRU is switched to ATT mode?",
    "feedback": "The Inertial System provides attitude and heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the threats when operating an automatic thrust control system (autothrust):",
    "feedback": "Flight in turbulence and windshear giving fluctuating airspeed indications may lead to the autothrust overcompensating"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a straight and uniform climb, the pilot maintains a constant calibrated airspeed (CAS) :",
    "feedback": "The Mach number increases and the true airspeed (TAS) increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "The directional gyro axis no longer spins about the local vertical when it is located :",
    "feedback": "on the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason for having a square-law compensation in the airspeed-indicator mechanism is:",
    "feedback": "The differential pressure increases with the square of the airspeed."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS) data relating primarily to navigation in the FMC is provided by:",
    "feedback": "Navigation radios, GPS, Inertial Reference Systems"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "Since inertial systems accumulate position errors as a function of time, the position information being used by the FMC is slowly accumulating errors"
  },
  {
    "question": "A servo-assisted altimeter is more accurate than a simple altimeter because the small movements of:",
    "feedback": "the capsules are detected by a very sensitive eletro-magnetic pick-off"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the colour associated with an armed mode is:",
    "feedback": "white or cyan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Air-driven gyro rotors are prevented from spinning too fast by the",
    "feedback": "vacuum relief valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Iron and brass are commonly used in bimetallic thermometers, because",
    "feedback": "they have two different coefficients of linear expansion."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where and when are the IRS positions updated?",
    "feedback": "Only on the ground during the alignment procedure"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airplane is in steady descent. The autothrottle maintains a constant Mach number. If the total temperature remains constant, the calibrated airspeed:",
    "feedback": "increases."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the MCDU inserted data represented?",
    "feedback": "It will be displayed as white text in the scratchpad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a result of the initial phase of the autopilot?",
    "feedback": "A new trajectory is obtained via a change in attitude to achieve a desired parameter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The data output from the ADC are:\n\n1) Barometric altitude\n2) Mach number\n3) CAS\n4) TAS\n5) SAT\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The picture shows an angle of attack sensor. The aircraft nose is to the (1) ...... .If the angle of attack is increasing the vane will rotate (2) ...... .",
    "feedback": "(1) left, (2) up"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Flight Data Recorder together with an Aeroplane Condition Monitoring System (ACMS) can be used for:",
    "feedback": "Accident analysis and trouble-shooting"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gyroscope used in an attitude indicator has a spin axis which is:",
    "feedback": "vertical"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fuel flow meter is located:",
    "feedback": "in the high pressure fuel line to the burners"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the automatic trim control system of an autopilot, automatic trimming is normally effected about the :",
    "feedback": "pitch axis only."
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the pilot flying of an aeroplane established on an ILS to perform an autoland. The aircraft is equipped with two autopilots, which are both engaged, and the autoland capability of the aeroplane is fail-operational. One of the autopilots suddently disengages when the FLARE mode activates at 35 ft. Given the information below, what are the consequences?\nRVR: 75 mApproach minima: 0 ftAlert height: 100 ft",
    "feedback": "The landing capability is now fail-passive but there is no annunciation of this downgrade or of the autopilot failure. The autoland will be completed as originally planned."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an autopilot system, the flight path modes are:\n\n1) pitch attitude hold\n2) IAS and Mach number hold\n3) altitude hold\n4) glide slope intercept and track\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a vacuum operated attitude indicator, automatic erection of the gyro is performed by",
    "feedback": "the pendulous unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a standard atmosphere and at the sea level, the calibrated airspeed (CAS) is :",
    "feedback": "equal to the true airspeed (TAS)."
  },
  {
    "question": "When an aircraft has turned 360 degrees with a constant attitude and bank, the pilot observes the following on a classic artificial horizon :",
    "feedback": "attitude and bank correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pitot tube supplies:",
    "feedback": "Impact pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the core functionality of the Flight Management System (FMS):",
    "feedback": "Construction of a four-dimensional flight plan and assistance with navigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gyro axis of an electric artificial horizon is tied to the:",
    "feedback": "earth's vertical by two mercury level switches and two torque motors"
  },
  {
    "question": "An autopilot is selected \"ON\" in mode \"altitude hold,\" the pilot alters the barometric pressure set on the sub-scale of his altimeter the:",
    "feedback": "aircraft will remain at the same altitude, the autopilot takes its pressure information from the static source"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the yaw damper system sends motion orders to the rudder:",
    "feedback": "no feedback is provided on the rudder pedals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Can an FMS receive position inputs from the GPS system, if installed?",
    "feedback": "Yes, this is common"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Cockpit Voice Recorder (CVR) is to record:\n1) Communications transmitted or received by radio\n2) Communications of crew members using the public address system\n3) Some air data parameters\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Magnetic compass swinging is carried out to reduce as much as possible :",
    "feedback": "deviation."
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram representing a left turn with too much rudder is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the approach, the radio altimeter indicates 950 ft. This is:",
    "feedback": "the height of the lowest wheels with regard to the ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the static source of an altimeter becomes blocked during a descent the instrument will:",
    "feedback": "continue to display the reading at which the blockage occured"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main advantage of a ratiometer-type temperature indicator is that it:",
    "feedback": "carries out an independent measurement of the supply voltage."
  },
  {
    "question": "When decelerating on a westerly heading in the Northern hemisphere, the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass will turn:",
    "feedback": "clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the south"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ADC (Air Data Computer) uses the following parameters as input data:",
    "feedback": "TAT, static pressure, total pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS (Ground Proximity Warning System) is active for a height range from:",
    "feedback": "50 ft to 2 500 ft measured by the radio altimeter."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\n\nPt = total pressure\nPs = static pressure\nPso = static pressure at sea level\n\nDynamic pressure is:",
    "feedback": "Pt-Ps"
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of a D.C. generator tachometer are:\n\n1- easy transmission of the information.\n2- independence of the information relative to the airborne electrical power supply.\n3- freedom from any spurious current due to the commutator.\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2."
  },
  {
    "question": "The measurement of SAT (static air temperature) by direct means is not possible on some (fast) aircraft because",
    "feedback": "of the effects from adiabatic compression and friction."
  },
  {
    "question": "When sent, a MAYDAY datalink message to the ATC has the following effect on ADS:",
    "feedback": "the ADS contract is switched to high periodic reporting rate"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the pilot wants to see which auto throttle mode is engaged, he/she will look at the:",
    "feedback": "FMA (Flight Mode Annunciator)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) gives avoidance resolutions :",
    "feedback": "only in the vertical plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb after take-off from a contaminated runway, if the total pressure probe of the airspeed indicator is blocked, the pilot finds that indicated airspeed :",
    "feedback": "increases steadily"
  },
  {
    "question": "The low-altitude radio altimeters used in precision approaches:\n\n1 operate in the 1540-1660 MHz range.\n2 are of the pulsed type.\n3 are of the frequency modulation type.\n4 have an operating range of 0 to 5000 ft.\n5 have a precision of +/- 2 feet between 0 and 500 ft.\n\nThe combination of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The signal transmitted by a radio altimeter is:",
    "feedback": "a frequency modulated carrier wave"
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the errors of a magnetic compass, errors are:",
    "feedback": "in North seeking, due to bank angle and magnetic heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot uses FMS inputs to automatically fly a flightplan, if:",
    "feedback": "A route is selected and activated and NAV mode is active"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a gyromagnetic compass, the direction of the earth's magnetic field is given by the:",
    "feedback": "flux valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is used to quickly respond to altitude changes and provide instant climb/descent indications in a barometric type Instantaneous Vertical Speed Indicator (IVSI)?",
    "feedback": "An accelerometer to temporarily change the pressure in the capsule"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the G/S mode (holding of ILS Glide Slope). The position of the horizontal command bar indicates:\n\n1) the position of the aircraft relative to the ILS Glide Slope\n2) the correction on the pitch to be applied to join and follow the ILS Glide Slope\n3) the instantaneous deviation between the aircraft position and the ILS Glide Slope\n\nthe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approval of electronic documentation on an aircraft is certified under:",
    "feedback": "EUROCAE"
  },
  {
    "question": "A free gyro has the axis of the spinning rotor horizontal and aligned with the geographic meridian.\nIf this free gyro is situated at latitude 60°N, the apparent drift rate according to the earthbound observer is:",
    "feedback": "13°/hour to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "The autopilot:",
    "feedback": "Uses speed, aircraft configuration or flight phase as a measure for the magnitude of control inputs"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is under guidance mode following a VOR radial. From the ADI and HSI in the attached diagram, it is possible to deduce that the aircraft is :",
    "feedback": "experiencing a left side wind."
  },
  {
    "question": "During the take-off an aeroplane experiences the separation of the engine cowlings on one of its engines. This causes damage to some of the engine control circuits on the engine, leading to an engine shutdown. The aeroplane has an electronic checklist system which guides the pilots through the appropriate actions to address the engine failure. The last item on the list directs the pilots to attempt an engine relight procedure. Is this appropriate for this particular situation?",
    "feedback": "No, because the engine is damaged but the checklist system is not able to analyse the extent of this damage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field:",
    "feedback": "is very small close to the magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "The use of the TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) for avoiding an aircraft in flight is now general. TCAS uses for its operation :",
    "feedback": "the replies from the transponders of other aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bellows sensor can be used for the following instrument:",
    "feedback": "Cabin differential pressure gauge"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressure of 20000 pascal equals to:",
    "feedback": "0.2 bar"
  },
  {
    "question": "During pre-flight, while checking the route entered in the FMS by the pilot, it is noticed that the FMS navigation database is out of date. The decision is taken to change the FMS navigation database cycle to the current cycle. After changing the navigation database cycle ......",
    "feedback": "all previously entered route data will be deleted"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the directional gyro, the apparent drift rate due to the earth's rotation is a function of:",
    "feedback": "latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The computers of the electrical flight controls system comply with programs defined by attitude control laws such as :\n\n1- on the longitudinal axis, the law may combine the load factor and the changes in the pitch rate as control data sources\n2- the trimming is automatic and ensures neutral stability\n3- the protections apply to pitch and bank attitudes depending on the speed\n4- these laws do not apply to the whole flight envelope \n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS II has inputs from the radio altimeter in order to:",
    "feedback": "gradually inhibit the Resolution Advisories (RAs) when getting closer to the ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "The null-seeking (slotted) probe AoA sensor of (1) ...... will automatically rotate (2) ...... to automatically seek a balance point.",
    "feedback": "(1) figure B, (2) anti-clockwise"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of compass check swing is to:",
    "feedback": "measure the angle between Magnetic North and Compass North"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode is selected on the Navigation Display (EHSI)?",
    "feedback": "Full NAV mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Flight Management Computer (FMC) position is:",
    "feedback": "the computed position based on a number of sources (IRS, Radio, ILS, GPS etc)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The unit used to measure the capacitance of a capacitor is the:",
    "feedback": "Farad"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason for usually mounting the detector unit of a remote reading compass in the wingtip of an aeroplane is to:",
    "feedback": "reduce the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the FMS, the parameters used to work out the vertical flight profile are;\n\n1) zero fuel weight\n2) cost index\n3) fuel quantity\n4) oxygen quantity available for flight crew\n5) minimum safe enroute altitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC (Full Authority Digital Engine Control) provides:\n\n1) engine automatic shut-down if maximum N1 is exceeded\n2) engine automatic shut-down if maximum EGT is exceeded\n3) automatic thrust rating control\n4) fully automatic engine starting\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The parameters used to represent thrust are:\n1) N1 (low pressure shaft speed)\n2) N2 (high pressure shaft speed)\n3) EGT\n4) EPR\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The disadvantage of an electronic tachometer is the :",
    "feedback": "necessity of providing a power supply"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure of 200 bar equals approximately:",
    "feedback": "3000 psi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about hard and soft iron in relation to magnetism is correct?",
    "feedback": "Hard iron magnetism is of a permanent nature and soft iron is of a non-permanent nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inertia of a gyroscope is greater when:",
    "feedback": "its rotation speed is higher and the mass of the spinning wheel is located further from the axis of rotation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The input of some data for the function of the FMS is compulsory, while other data is optional. Which of the following describes the symbology correctly?",
    "feedback": "The symbology used for compulsory data are rectangular boxes"
  },
  {
    "question": "There are several types of temperature sensors. Which one has a maximum scale range from -50ºC up to 400ºC?",
    "feedback": "Bimetallic thermometer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select from the statements below the one that applies best to an ADIRU:",
    "feedback": "ADIRU is an Air Data Computer which is integrated with an Inertial Reference Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a strapdown inertial system, the accelerations are measured in a trihedron which is fixed regarding to the:",
    "feedback": "aircraft's trihedron (pitch, roll and yaw axis)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment time, at mid-latitudes, for an Inertial Reference System using laser ring gyros is approximately:",
    "feedback": "10 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "A vertical speed indicator measures the difference between:",
    "feedback": "the instantaneous static pressure and the static pressure at a previous moment"
  },
  {
    "question": "When compared with the volumetric fuel flowmeter, the mass fuel flowmeter takes into account the fuel :",
    "feedback": "density."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a conventional ASI (Airspeed Indicator), the white arc corresponds to the ....",
    "feedback": "flap operating speed range"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Primary Flight Display (PFD) of an EFIS equipped aircraft displays the following parameters:\n1) radio height\n2) IAS\n3) localizer and glide slope deviation pointers\n4) flight director modes\n5) autopilot modes\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Erection systems are provided for the purpose of:",
    "feedback": "Erecting and maintaining the gyro in its vertical position."
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert(s) associated with the mode 4 of the GPWS(unsafe terrain clearance while not in the landing configuration) is(are):",
    "feedback": "\"TOO LOW GEAR\", \"TOO LOW FLAPS\", \"TOO LOW TERRAIN\""
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to INS/IRS:\n1) Inertial navigation and inertial reference systems are the main source of attitude and one of the main sources of navigational data in commercial air transport aeroplanes2) Inertial systems require external input other than TAS to determine aircraft attitude and navigational data3) INSs can be considered to be stand-alone, wheras IRSs are integrated with the flight management system (FMS)4) Earlier gyro mechanically stabilised platforms are coventionally referred to as inertial navigation systems (INSs)\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The HUD replicates information from the ......",
    "feedback": "PFD"
  },
  {
    "question": "A landing is performed automatically when the autopilot and auto-throttle ensure good performance from the final approach :",
    "feedback": "during the landing roll and sometimes until the aircraft comes to a complete stop."
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram which shows a 20° left bank and 18° nose down is number:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The parameters taken into account by the flight director computer in the altitude holding mode (ALT HOLD) are:\n\na) altitude deviation\nb) roll\nc) bank attitude\nd) pitch attitude\n\nthe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "a, d"
  },
  {
    "question": "The characteristics of the SATCOM transmissions, used for datalink communications are:",
    "feedback": "no line of sight limitation, no variable quality of signals disturbed by ionospheric conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "A bellows sensor installed in an engine can be used for the following instrument:",
    "feedback": "Manifold pressure gauge"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert(s) associated with the mode 4 of the GPWS(unsafe terrain clearance while not in the landing configuration) is(are):\n\n1) \"TOO LOW GEAR\"\n2) \"TOO LOW TERRAIN\"\n3) \"TOO LOW FLAPS\"\n4) \"PULL UP\"\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parameters recorded by a Flight Data Recorder include ......",
    "feedback": "attitude, heading, and thrust/power on each engine"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a ring laser gyro, the purpose of the dither motor is to:",
    "feedback": "overcome laser lock"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following information can be displayed on a Primary Flight Display (PFD):\n1) IAS\n2) Vertical speed\n3) TAS\n4) Selected airspeed\n5) Radio altitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The correction of the control surface deflection made by the auto-pilot calculator in order to keep a given altitude will be all the more significant when the :\n\n1- difference between the attitude necessary to keep the given or reference altitude and the instantaneous attitude is high.\n2 - variation speed of the difference between the attitude necessary to maintain the altitude and the instantaneous attitude is high.\n3 - difference between the altitude of reference and the instantaneous altitude is high.\n4 - variation speed of the difference between the reference altitude and the instantaneous altitude is high.\n\nThe combination regrouping the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3 and 4."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a triple-fit IRS system, present positions on the CDU:",
    "feedback": "are likely to differ as the information comes from different sources"
  },
  {
    "question": "When climbing at a constant CAS:",
    "feedback": "Mach number increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nCompass Heading = 233°\nTrue Track = 256°\nDrift Angle = 10°R\nDeviation = -3°\n\nWhat is the variation?",
    "feedback": "16°E"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of detection of a vibration monitoring system is based on the use of:",
    "feedback": "2 accelerometers."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a remote indicating compass system the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits may be minimised by:",
    "feedback": "mounting the detector unit in the wingtip"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following may trigger false TAWS warnings?\n1) Poor navigation fix or malfunctioning nav system2) Rapidly rising terrain3) Thunderstorms4) High descent rates5) High airspeeds\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) navigation database typically includes the following data:\n1) waypoints2) details of radio navigation aids3) optimum altitudes4) company routes5) landing reference speeds\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reading of a Mach indicator is independent of :",
    "feedback": "the outside temperature"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 1 represents:",
    "feedback": "straight and level flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic dip at any point on the Earth's surface is the angle:",
    "feedback": "made by a compass needle with the local horizontal"
  },
  {
    "question": "When, in flight, the needle and ball of a needle-and-ball indicator are on the right, the aircraft is :",
    "feedback": "turning right with too much bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "FMS calculations are based on ......",
    "feedback": "the FMS position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) true heading\n2) drift angle\n3) ground speed\n4) Mach number\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The indication of a fuel float gauge varies with:\n\n1) pitch attitude\n2) accelerations\n3) temperature\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is;",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The EGPWS may propose the Terrain Look-Ahead Alerting function. This function uses:",
    "feedback": "An electronic map of the world giving ground elevation"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS (Flight Management System) is organised in such a way that the pilot can:",
    "feedback": "insert additional temporary navigation data between two database updates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Few modern INS systems use a mechanically stabilised platform and mechanical gyros. These components has been replaced by",
    "feedback": "Strap down ring laser gyros and accelerometers plus advanced digital computers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What undesired state can be caused in this situation?",
    "feedback": "You might intercept the G/S before the LOC and descend outside protected airspace"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can a pilot enter a waypoint into his FMS RNAV system?",
    "feedback": "Control Display Unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "The location of the Earth's magnetic poles:",
    "feedback": "periodically wanders (as much as 15 km every year)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The measurement of the turbine temperature or of the EGT (Exhaust Gas Temperature) is carried out at the :",
    "feedback": "outlet of the high pressure stage of the turbine"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS lateral offset function consists in:",
    "feedback": "flying along the flight plan legs with a constant right or left offset manually entered on the FMS CDU."
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb after take-off from a contaminated runway, if the total pressure probe of the airspeed indicator is blocked, the pilot finds that indicated airspeed :",
    "feedback": "increases steadily"
  },
  {
    "question": "A laser gyro can measure:",
    "feedback": "a rotation motion"
  },
  {
    "question": "At a low bank angle, the measurement of rate-of-turn actually consists in measuring the :",
    "feedback": "yaw rate of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the pilot increases the reference pressure using the sub-scale setting knob, the altitude indicated by the altimeter:",
    "feedback": "increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compass heading can be derived from the magnetic heading by reference to a:",
    "feedback": "compass deviation card"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to angle of attack measurement:",
    "feedback": "Probes and vane detectors are mounted either side of the fuselage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a stabilised platform inertial system, the principle of operation requires the use of at least:",
    "feedback": "3 rate gyros and 2 accelerometers"
  },
  {
    "question": "At a specific location, the value of magnetic variation:",
    "feedback": "varies slowly over time"
  },
  {
    "question": "How exactly is a fail-operational hybrid autopilot designed?",
    "feedback": "It consists of a primary fail-passive system with a secondary independent system (HUD), that allows the pilot to land manually in case of failure of the primary system"
  },
  {
    "question": "A directional gyro consists of a:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "2 degrees-of-freedom horizontal axis gyro"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical speed indicator of an aircraft flying at a true airspeed of 100 kt, in a descent with a slope of 3 degrees, indicates :",
    "feedback": "- 500 ft/min."
  },
  {
    "question": "During a climb at a constant CAS below the tropopause in standard atmosphere:",
    "feedback": "TAS and Mach number increase"
  },
  {
    "question": "The functions of the altitude alerting system is to alert the flight crew:\n\n1) upon approaching a pre-selected altitude\n2) upon approaching a pre-selected altitude, during climb only\n3) of a loss of altitude during take-off or missed approach\n4) of a wrong landing configuration\n5) when deviating from the selected altitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an ADC, the altitude is computed with the:",
    "feedback": "static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hard iron magnetism in aircraft",
    "feedback": "Is permanent of nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic on-board datalink communication system is typically composed by the following sub systems:\n\n1) Communication Management Unit (CMU)\n2) Multi-purpose Control and  Display (MCDU)\n3) Communication unit (VHF, HF, Satcom)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "To obtain total air temp. (TAT) the airflow to the sensor",
    "feedback": "must be brought to rest without addition or removal of heat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Heading information from the gyromagnetic compass flux gate is transmitted to the :",
    "feedback": "error detector."
  },
  {
    "question": "A radio altimeter uses the following frequency band:",
    "feedback": "4200 MHz to 4400 MHz"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is lined up on runway 05, which is aligned with a magnetic bearing of 047°. In order to comply with maximum permissible deviation errors, the direct reading magnetic compass readings should be between:",
    "feedback": "037° - 057°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The computer of the autopilot system uses, among others, input signals from the :\n\n1) ADC\n2) attitude reference system\n3) ILS receiver\n4) mode control panel\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "When performing the FMS pre-flight set-up, the pilot notices that the current navigation database is out of date. Which of the following is the action which should be taken before continuing the FMS initialisaion? The pilot should:",
    "feedback": "Select the valid database"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CPDLC is a FANS application which consists in:",
    "feedback": "transmitting datalink formatted messages between the pilot and ATC controller"
  },
  {
    "question": "Machmeter readings are subject to:",
    "feedback": "position error"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the following formula EAS = CAS x K, the compressibility factor K:\n\n1) may be greater than 1\n2) is always lower or equal to 1\n3) depends on Mach number only\n4) depends on pressure altitude only\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "List the typical equipment of an EFB:\n1) Laptop2) Tablet3) MCDU4) Avionics Suite",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is total indicated fuel consumption calculated?",
    "feedback": "By integrating the rate of fuel consumption over flight time"
  },
  {
    "question": "During descent, the total pressure probe of the airspeed indicator becomes blocked. In this case:\n\n1) IAS becomes greater than CAS\n2) IAS becomes lower than CAS\n3) while trying to maintain IAS constant, VMO may be exceeded\n4) while trying to maintain IAS constant, aeroplane may stall\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are modes of operation of a HUD?",
    "feedback": "Normal display and declutter mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "What reversion law is the auto throttle subject to?",
    "feedback": "Minimum and maximum speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the main functions of the Flight Management System (FMS) is....",
    "feedback": "to construct a four-dimensional aircraft trajectory"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS Flight Plan, Navigation, Progress or Leg page generally displays the following parameters relative to the flight plan legs or waypoints:\n1-distance\n2- time prediction\n3- waypoint elevation\n4- track\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which colour is used for caution lights?",
    "feedback": "Amber or yellow"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aneroid capsule:\n\n1) measures differential pressure\n2) measures absolute pressure\n3) is used for low pressure measurement\n4) is used for very high pressure measurement\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning a fail-operational flight control system, in the event of a failure:\n\n1) the system will operate as a fail-passive system\n2) the landing is not completed automatically\n3) the landing is completed automatically\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS include:\n\n1) satellites status\n2) altitude\n3) drift angle\n4) present position (lat, long)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The functions of an autopilot (basic modes) consist of :",
    "feedback": "stabilizing and monitoring the movement around the airplane centre of gravity."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can the TCS (Touch Control Steering) system be activated?",
    "feedback": "By pressing a button to disengage the flight controls from the autopilot"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight director comprises a channel for:\n\na) the attitude\nb) the bank control\nc) the pitch control\nd) the speed\n\nthe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "b, c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the Random Access Memory (RAM) are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) Data stored are lost after the power is switched off\n2) It can be read and written to anytime the processor commands it",
    "feedback": "1 is correct, 2 is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "When engaging the autopilot, the function providing a smooth \"take-over\" is the:",
    "feedback": "automatic synchronisation function"
  },
  {
    "question": "With regard to inertial navigation, (1) is the more recently developed system and (2) operates with laser gyroscopes.",
    "feedback": "(1) IRS, (2) IRS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FD command bars on the ADI (illustration number 2) indicate that:",
    "feedback": "the pilot should rise the aircraft nose and roll to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "The range of a low altitude radio altimeter is:",
    "feedback": "2500 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the case of altitude loss during the initial climb after take-off, GPWS generates an aural alert:",
    "feedback": "\"DON'T SINK\""
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following functions of an autopilot, those related to the aeroplane guidance are:\n\n1) pitch attitude holding\n2) horizontal wing holding\n3) IAS or Mach number holding\n4) altitude holding\n5) VOR axis holding\n6) yaw damping\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a large aeroplane, the computer of a stall warning system receives information about the:\n\n1) angle of attack\n2) engine RPM\n3) configuration\n4) pitch and bank attitude\n5) sideslip\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS Flight Plan, Navigation, Progress or Leg page generally displays the following parameters relative to the flight plan legs or waypoints:\n1- FMS position\n2- time prediction\n3- track\n4- distance\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2,3,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS receives data from the following systems:\n\n1) landing gear and flaps systems\n2) engine control computer (FADEC or ECU)\n3) radio altimeter\n4) TCAS\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an EFIS equipped aircraft, the FMA is typically located on the ....",
    "feedback": "top of the PFD"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the final approach, ILS and FD show contradicting information. The pilot flying should ......",
    "feedback": "follow the ILS and ignore the FD"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which option correctly completes the statement on angle of attack sensors? Null-seeking (slotted) probe and vane-detector angle of attack sensors are connected to a (1) ..... contact, and both types are subject to (2) ..... error, which can be corrected in the ADC.",
    "feedback": "(1) potentiometer wiper, (2) position"
  },
  {
    "question": "A direct reading compass is used. Accelerating an aircraft on heading 090 at South Magnetic Latitude will result in",
    "feedback": "An indication of a right turn on the compass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Match indicated airspeed (IAS) with the associated definition:",
    "feedback": "The airspeed you read directly from the airspeed indicator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will probably NOT result in a deviation change on a DRC",
    "feedback": "Turning the ADF on in flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on coefficient A, as used to describe deviation:",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the Cockpit Voice Recorder (CVR) is to record:\n1) The audio environment in the flight deck\n2) Specific aircraft performance parameters\n3) The communications of crew memebers using the interphone system\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a turn at a constant angle of bank, the rate of turn is:",
    "feedback": "inversely proportional to the aircraft TAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a declutter function of a HUD?",
    "feedback": "It removes the altitude and speed tapes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gyro with (1) vertical spin axis and (2) horizontal spin axis can ......",
    "feedback": "(1) only topple, (2) drift and topple"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which instruments are required for an automatic landing?\n1) Radio altimeter2) Barometric altimeter3) Autopilot4) Autothrottle",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System (INS), the main causes of cumulative track errors are",
    "feedback": "initial azimuth misalignment of the platform and wander of the azimuth gyro."
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following engine instruments, the one operating with an aneroid pressure diaphragm is the :",
    "feedback": "manifold pressure gauge."
  },
  {
    "question": "The different types of tachometers are:\n1) electrical\n2) mechanical\n3) electronic\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the flight warning system (FWS), caution messages:",
    "feedback": "are the next highest priority alert messages after warning messages"
  },
  {
    "question": "In standard atmosphere at sea level, the EAS is:",
    "feedback": "equal to the TAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a transport airplane, an autopilot comprises, in addition to the mode display devices, the following fundamental elements :\n\n1- Airflow valve\n2- Sensors\n3- Comparators\n4- Computers\n5- Amplifiers\n6- Servo-actuators\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, what is meant by the term \"multiprocessing\"?",
    "feedback": "Two or more Central Processing Units (CPUs) are used within a single computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The quadrantal deviation of the magnetic compass is due to the action of :",
    "feedback": "the soft iron pieces influenced by the geomagnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "A machine for manipulating data according to a list of instructions is:",
    "feedback": "a computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS provides the following functions:\n1- lateral and vertical flight plan management \n2- de icing management\n3- aircraft position computation\n4- terrain awareness and warning\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of the Flight Data Monitoring (FDM)?",
    "feedback": "To record systems status and flight conditions and automatically send reports to the company for investigation and training"
  },
  {
    "question": "When accelerating on an easterly heading in the Northern hemisphere, the compass card of a direct reading magnetic compass will turn:",
    "feedback": "clockwise giving an apparent turn towards the north"
  },
  {
    "question": "Comparing the radio navigation system and the Inertial Navigation System:\n\n1) the radio position is accurate when in DME range\n2) the radio position may be obtained whatever the position on the earth\n3) the inertial position may be obtained whatever the position on the earth\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "An engine vibration monitoring system is installed in aircraft with jet engines, to ......",
    "feedback": "monitor changes in the level of engine vibrations and thereby indicate a possible engine failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a multi-engine aircraft, a synchroscope provides:",
    "feedback": "qualitative indication of the difference in speed between the engines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of the compass swinging procedure is to:",
    "feedback": "determine the amount by which the compass readings are affected by hard and soft iron magnetism"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS II data display devices can be in the form of:\n\n1) a specific dedicated screen \n2) a screen combined with the weather radar\n3) a variometer represented on a liquid crystal screen which allows the display of Traffic Advisory (TA) and Resolution Advisory (RA)\n4) an EFIS screen\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft speeds for long-range cruise, maximum endurance and holding are stored in the:",
    "feedback": "performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ambient temperature decreases, the TAS of an aircraft cruising at a constant Mach number will:",
    "feedback": "decrease because local speed of sound decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select parts of an FMS CDU (Control Display Unit) from the list below:\n1) Alphanumeric and miscellaneous keys2) Circuit breaker3) Display4) Function and excecute keys5) Line select keys6) Printer",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What measures are to be taken in case of loss of all fuel indications?",
    "feedback": "Pull and reset the circuit breaker to check if the system restarts, unless checklists say otherwise"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an operational difference between the turn coordinator and the turn and slip indicator?",
    "feedback": "the turn coordinator indicates roll rate, rate of turn, and co-ordination; the turn and slip indicator indicates rate of turn and co-ordination"
  },
  {
    "question": "An altitude alert system must at least warn the crew:\n1) when approaching the pre-selected altitude2) when the aeroplane is approaching the ground too fast3) in case of a given deviation above or below the pre-selected altitude4) in case of excessive vertical speed5) when approaching the ground with the gear retracted\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an autothrust system (A/THR) is in the SPEED mode, the A/THR is:",
    "feedback": "active"
  },
  {
    "question": "A VMO-MMO warning device consists of an alarm connected to :",
    "feedback": "a barometric aneroid capsule subjected to a static pressure and an airspeed sensor subjected to a dynamic pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "A pressure of 3000 psi equals to approximately:",
    "feedback": "200 bar"
  },
  {
    "question": "The deviation of a compass is described as +4. This means that",
    "feedback": "The compass heading will have a lower number in degrees than the magnetic heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"overfly\" symbol related to a waypoint on an FMS page indicates that:",
    "feedback": "the aircraft is required to pass directly over this waypoint"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a TCAS Resolution Advisory (RA) requires an immediate descent while at the same time ATC requests an immediate climb, the crew should:",
    "feedback": "follow the TCAS RA and inform ATC"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the case of multiple threats, TCAS II can display up to ....",
    "feedback": "30 targets and will issue commands in the vertical plane only"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, what is meant by the term \"multitasking\"?",
    "feedback": "Multiple tasks share common resources, such as the same Central Processing Unit (CPU)"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the magnetic equator, when accelerating after take off on heading West, a direct reading compass :",
    "feedback": "indicates the correct heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "You have just taken off in a fast aircraft fitted with a vacuum operated attitude indicator.  While climbing straight ahead - still accelerating - the instrument may for a short while indicate",
    "feedback": "a climbing turn to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is established on the ILS to conduct an autoland. At 1000 feet the FMA indicates the display as shown in FMA-1. Select the normal sequence of FMA displays after FMA-1, until aeroplane touch-down on the runway.",
    "feedback": "FMA-3, then FMA-4"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a normal take-off, what is the autothrust set to?",
    "feedback": "To maintain a constant pre-set thrust setting, in accordance with the performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flying manually during a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the G/S mode (holding of ILS glide slope). If the aircraft is below the ILS glide slope, the horizontal command bar:",
    "feedback": "may be centred if the pilot is correcting to come back on the ILS glide slope"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode is selected on the Navigation Display (EHSI)?",
    "feedback": "Full VOR mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the event of a failure, a fail-operational flight control system will operate as a:",
    "feedback": "fail-passive system"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the building principle of a gyroscope, the best efficiency is obtained through the concentration of the mass :",
    "feedback": "on the periphery and with a high rotation speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Navigation System, the integration process:\n\n1) amounts to making a time division\n2) amounts to making a time multiplication\n3) enable to get accelerations from position\n4) enable to get position from accelerations\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A synchroscope is used on aircraft to:",
    "feedback": "set several engines to the same speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the software certification type when in case of failure it does not impact the safety of the flight?",
    "feedback": "Type A"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is equipped with an autopilot and an auto throttle. When the altitude hold mode (ALT HOLD) is active:",
    "feedback": "The indicated airspeed (IAS) is maintained constant by the autothrottle system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the TCAS II:\n\n1) neither advisory nor traffic display is provided for aircraft that do not have an operating transponder\n2) TCAS II operation is independent of ground-based air traffic control\n3) TCAS II has feeds from the radio altimeter\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A TCAS II provides:",
    "feedback": "the intruder relative position and possibly an indication of a collision avoidance manoeuvre within the vertical plane only."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main function(s) of a TCAS is to:\n\n1) alert the crew to ground proximity\n2) alert the crew to possible conflicting traffic\n3) provide terrain alerting and display\n4) automatically resolve conflict when autopilot engaged\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an automatic ILS final approach, the auto-throttle:",
    "feedback": "can be operated in the SPEED mode (holding of IAS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS generates a warning in the following cases:\n\n1) excessive descent rate\n2) excessive terrain closure rate\n3) altitude loss after take-off or go-around\n4) unsafe terrain clearance with abnormal gear/flaps configuration\n5) excessive deviation under the glidepath\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "When comparing a TCAS Traffic Advisory (TA) and a Resolution Advisory (RA), which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "A TA indicates the relative position of the intruding traffic; an RA provides a vertical traffic avoidance manoeuvre"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rigidity in a gyroscope is",
    "feedback": "the tendency it has to remain in its plane of rotation and resist attempts to alter its position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The parameters taken into account by the flight director computer in the altitude holding mode (ALT HOLD) are:\n\n1) altitude deviation\n2) engine rpm\n3) ground speed\n4) pitch attitude\n\nthe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of the vibrating device of an altimeter is to:",
    "feedback": "reduce the effect of  friction in the linkages"
  },
  {
    "question": "Changes in temperature of the fuel affect its density, volume and dielectric value Er. A decrease in temperature causes:",
    "feedback": "a decrease in volume, increase in density and increase in Er"
  },
  {
    "question": "If warning, caution, or advisory lights are installed in the flight deck, they must, unless otherwise approved by the Authority, be amber for:",
    "feedback": "caution lights"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct regarding the modes of operation of a dual FMS installation?",
    "feedback": "In independent mode, the boxes do not exchange data"
  },
  {
    "question": "The synchronization of the autopilot control channel system :\n\n1- enables the prevention of jerks during disengagement  \n2- enables the cancellation of rudder control signals\n3- enables the prevention of jerks during engagement\n4- functions in the heading, navigation, approach modes\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "When turning onto a northerly heading the rose of a magnetic compass tends to \"undershoot;\" when turning onto a southerly heading it tends to \"overshoot\":\n\n1)these compass indications are less reliable in the northern hemisphere than in the southern hemisphere.\n2)these compass oscillations following a lateral gust are not identical if the aircraft is heading north or south.\n3) this behaviour is due to the mechanical construction of the compass. \n4) this behaviour is a symptom of a badly swung compass.\n\nThe correct statements are :",
    "feedback": "2 and 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "The alternate static source of a light non-pressurized aircraft is located in the flight deck. When used, the altimeter:",
    "feedback": "tends to over-read"
  },
  {
    "question": "A gyromagnetic compass consists of:\n\n1) a horizontal axis gyro\n2) a vertical axis gyro\n3) an earth's magnetic field detector\n4) an erection mechanism to maintain the gyro axis horizontal\n5) a torque motor to make the gyro precess in azimuth\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "If incorrect data was entered into the EFB, would performance calculations be affected?",
    "feedback": "Yes, the take-off speeds may be incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft engine-thrust characteristics are stored in the:",
    "feedback": "performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gyro-compassing in an INS:",
    "feedback": "is not possible in flight as the gyros cannot differentiate between acceleration due to aircraft movement and initial alignment errors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct concerning the effect of turning errors on a direct reading compass?",
    "feedback": "Turning errors are greatest on north/south headings, and are greatest at high latitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the colour associated with an engaged mode is:",
    "feedback": "green"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IRS mode selector is inadvertently set from NAV to ATT mode, resulting in loss of alignment in flight. What are the implications of this?",
    "feedback": "Navigation data is lost and realignment is not possible in flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "TCAS II uses for its operation:",
    "feedback": "the replies from the transponders of other aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the flight warning system (FWS), advisory messages may be:",
    "feedback": "any colour except red, and preferably not amber"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fundamental laws of magnetism are correct or incorrect?\n1) Like poles attract\n2) Unlike poles repel each other",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is incorrect"
  },
  {
    "question": "In response to a temperature rise, a thermocouple increases its....",
    "feedback": "voltage"
  },
  {
    "question": "The GPWS warns the crew in case of:\n\n1) excessive descent rate\n2) excessive terrain closure rate\n3) potential midair collision threat\n4) serious midair collision threat\n5) unsafe terrain clearance with landing gear not down\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The autothrust must not to be used in severe turbulence:",
    "feedback": "The autothrust may overcompensate in an oscillating manner"
  },
  {
    "question": "The alignment of an inertial system can be successfully performed:",
    "feedback": "when the aircraft is stationary"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most common sensors interfacing a FMS to compute the aircraft position along the flight plan are: 1- IRS 2- DME 3- NDB 4- GPS The combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "An automatic landing system necessitating that the landing be continued manually in the case of a system failure during an automatic approach is called \"FAIL....\"",
    "feedback": "\"PASSIVE\""
  },
  {
    "question": "If the navigation function of an INS is inoperative, the back up mode if existing, used to operate the INS is:",
    "feedback": "the ATT mode which supplies attitude and heading data"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computing, what is the function of a control unit?",
    "feedback": "It ensures sequencing and co-ordination of operations"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a final approach, the flight director system is engaged in the G/S mode (holding of ILS Glide Slope). If the horizontal command bar is deviating upward, it means that:",
    "feedback": "the pitch attitude must be increased"
  },
  {
    "question": "If, in the event of a failure, there is no significant out-of-trim condition or deviation of flight path or attitude but the landing is not completed automatically, such an automatic landing system is considered as:",
    "feedback": "fail-passive"
  },
  {
    "question": "A simple magnet is surrounded by a magnetic field having the following properties:",
    "feedback": "The field's direction is from the magnets red pole to the magnets blue pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is correct regarding the autopilot and flight director?",
    "feedback": "The autopilot is engaged and is conducting an autoland. The flight director is giving flight guidance as a backup"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the acceleration of an aircraft is zero, its velocity:",
    "feedback": "is constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Non-electrical temperature measurements may be done by",
    "feedback": "all of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer architecture, the systems that ensures the transfer of data between computer components is:",
    "feedback": "a bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aural alert associated with the mode 5 (excessive deviation below glide slope) of the GPWS is:",
    "feedback": "\"GLIDESLOPE\""
  },
  {
    "question": "When the intruding aircraft is equipped with a serviceable mode C transponder, the TCAS II (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) generates a :",
    "feedback": "\"traffic advisory\" and vertical \"resolution advisory\"."
  },
  {
    "question": "The directive force acting on a compass needle in an aircraft",
    "feedback": "Is the resultant magnetic force in the horizontal plane in the position where the compass is installed"
  },
  {
    "question": "IRS differs from INS in that it:",
    "feedback": "has a shorter spin-up time and suffers from laser lock"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the installed EFB has a malfunction, which of the following may be inoperative?",
    "feedback": "Take-off and landing performance calculations"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Flight Mode Annunciator FMA is displayed on the:",
    "feedback": "PFD"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the pitot and static system, the static pressure error:",
    "feedback": "is caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by pilot-induced oscillations in Automatic Flight Control Systems?",
    "feedback": "Anomalous interactions between the pilot and the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Torque can be determined by measuring the :",
    "feedback": "change in phase between the torque shaft and the reference shaft"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight envelope protection system prevents the aircraft from exceeding the limits of the following parameters (among others):\n\n1) cabin altitude\n2) bank angle\n3) angle of attack\n4) speed\n5) pitch attitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "For internal communication with the memory, the central processing unit makes use of:",
    "feedback": "Three buses: one address bus, one data bus, and one control bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The principle of the TCAS makes use of:",
    "feedback": "transponders fitted in the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about temperature are correct or incorrect?\n\n1) 20° Celsius = 68° Fahrenheit\n2) 0° Celsius = 273° Kelvin",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The QNH is by definition the value of the:",
    "feedback": "altimeter setting so that the needles of the altimeter indicate  the altitude of the location for which it is given."
  },
  {
    "question": "After the initial 90 degrees of a turn at constant pitch and bank, a classic artificial horizon indicates:",
    "feedback": "too much nose-up and too little bank"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ADS is a FANS application performed:",
    "feedback": "automatically, without any crew action to define the set of data to downlink or the type of report contract"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pitot tube covered by ice which blocks the ram air inlet will affect the following instrument (s) :",
    "feedback": "airspeed indicator only."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Navigation Display (ND) modes can be:\n1) ARC or MAP, covering 45 degrees on either side of the instantaneous track\n2) ROSE or MAP CENTERED: rose with current heading up\n3) PLAN: map orientated to true north\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many software certification levels for aviation exist according to EUROCAE?",
    "feedback": "5 Levels: A (Catastrophic), B (Hazardous), C (Major,) D (Minor) and E (no effect)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stall warning is inhibited:\n\n1) when the flaps are retracted\n2) when the aeroplane is on the ground\n3) when encountering a windshear\n4) upon receiving a GPWS alert\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying a fly-by-wire aeroplane manually, the automatic pitch trim system eliminates the need for the pilot to make control column inputs to compensate for:\n1) thrust changes2) gear configuration changes3) a terrain proximity warning\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the selected Mach number is displayed above the PFD speed tape, the speed bug shows the corresponding ......",
    "feedback": "IAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "If OAT decreases when at a constant TAS:",
    "feedback": "Mach number increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "After having programmed your flight director, you see that the flight director indications are as represented in the diagram. This indicates that you must:",
    "feedback": "increase the flight attitude and bank your airplane to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of the pendulous vane unit erecting system is:",
    "feedback": "The air flow reaction through the open vanes."
  },
  {
    "question": "The annunciator of a remote indicating compass system is used when:",
    "feedback": "synchronising the magnetic and gyro compass elements"
  },
  {
    "question": "What angle of bank should you adopt on the attitude indicator for a standard rate\n(rate 1) turn while flying at an IAS of 130 Kt?",
    "feedback": "20°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the typical, most basic equipment of the EFB?",
    "feedback": "Laptop, tablet device"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a closed-loop system overcompensates for deviations from the desired state:",
    "feedback": "It may enter a state of self-induced oscillation"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is cruising at FL 60 with a TAS of 100 kt in standard atmosphere. In these conditions:\n\n1) the TAS is approximately 10% higher than the IAS\n2) the difference between the EAS and the CAS is negligible\n3) the speed displayed on the airspeed indicator is a CAS if the position error and instrument error are zero\n\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stick shaker calculator receives the following informations :\n\n1- mass of the airplane\n2- angle of attack\n3- wing flap deflection\n4- position of the landing gear\n5- total air temperature\n6- pressure altitude\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a twin-engined aeroplane, the synchroscope can consist of:",
    "feedback": "a rotor fed by the alternator driven by the master engine, and a stator fed by the alternator driven by the engine to by synchronised"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS II provides :\n\n1- traffic information (TA: Traffic Advisory)\n2- horizontal resolution (RA: Resolution Advisory)\n3- vertical resolution (RA: Resolution Advisory)\n4- ground proximity warning\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS provides the following functions:\n1- radio tuning \n2- fuel management\n3- lateral flight plan management\n4-traffic alerts\n\nThe combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,2,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "EAS is equal to:",
    "feedback": "CAS corrected for compressibility error"
  },
  {
    "question": "The radio altimeter is required to indicate zero height AGL as the main wheels touch down on the runway. For this reason it is necessary to:",
    "feedback": "compensate for residual height and cable length"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the calculation of deviation, the following  headings are recorded:\nMH       CH\n358        356\n091        087\n182        186\n273        271\nCoefficient B is",
    "feedback": "+1"
  },
  {
    "question": "TAS can be obtained from the following data:",
    "feedback": "EAS and density altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 4 represents:",
    "feedback": "a left turn with insufficient rudder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The electromotive force of a thermocouple is not modified if one or several intermediate metals are inserted in the circuit provided that:",
    "feedback": "contact points are maintained at equal temperature between these different metals."
  },
  {
    "question": "The advantages of single-phase A.C. generator tachometer are:\n\n1- the suppression of spurious signals due to a D.C. generator commutator\n2- the importance of line resistance on the information value\n3- the independence of the information in relation to the airborne electrical power supply\n4- the ease of transmission of the information\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a PFD, the Vertical Speed Indicator (VSI) is represented by:",
    "feedback": "A vertical scale, showing climb or descent, or zero"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a Flight Data Monitoring (FDM) programme is to collect flight data ......",
    "feedback": "anonymously, to improve safety"
  },
  {
    "question": "The automatic trim is a component of the autopilot pitch channel. Its function is to:",
    "feedback": "transfer a stabilized aeroplane to the pilot during autopilot disengagement."
  },
  {
    "question": "The artificial horizon uses a gyroscope with:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "two degrees of freedom, and its rotor spin axis is continuously maintained to local vertical by an automatic erecting system"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Engine Pressure Ratio (EPR) is computed by :",
    "feedback": "dividing turbine discharge pressure by compressor inlet pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "A remote indicating compass has usually less deviation error than a panel mounted \ncompass because:",
    "feedback": "it is normally mounted in a part of the airplane where magnetic interference is minimal."
  },
  {
    "question": "The input data of an ADC are:\n\n1) OAT\n2) TAT\n3) static pressure\n4) total pressure\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the navigation function of an INS is inoperative and the control rotary switch is set to ATT, the output data of the INS is(are):",
    "feedback": "attitude and heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "The velocity of sound at the sea level in a standard atmosphere is:",
    "feedback": "661 kt."
  },
  {
    "question": "The alternate static source of a light non-pressurized aircraft is located in the flight deck. When used:",
    "feedback": "the airspeed indicator tends to over-read"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum operating speed VMO is expressed in:",
    "feedback": "CAS or EAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens in case of failure of a tablet EFB?",
    "feedback": "The table is not covered by the MEL and is not repaired by aircraft maintenance personnel. The flight crew should refer to the company abnormal procedures in case of EFB failure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper system controls:",
    "feedback": "the rudder, with the angular rate about the yaw axis as the input signal"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a modern FMS-equipped aircraft with a modern ADF receiver, the Beat Frequency Oscillator:",
    "feedback": "is activated automatically"
  },
  {
    "question": "The CVR (Cockpit Voice Recorder) includes:\n1. a microphone\n2. a recorder in compliance with the shock and fire resistance standards\n3. an independent battery\n4. a flight data recorder\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The uplink datalink message \"AT(position) CLIMB TO (altitude) AND MAINTAIN\" is part of the:",
    "feedback": "CPDLC application"
  },
  {
    "question": "The temperature measured by the CHT (Cylinder Head temperature) probe is the :",
    "feedback": "temperature within the hottest cylinder, depending on its position in the engine block."
  },
  {
    "question": "In computer architecture, a bus is a system that:",
    "feedback": "transfers data between computer components"
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the correct statements from the selection below: \n1) The radio altimeter measures the height of an aircraft above ground with a low degree of accuracy2) Incorrect radio altimeter indications due to unreliable input signals can be dangerous when operating in a phase of flight with marginal ground clearance3) During an auto-landing procedure, the auto-thrust system requires accurate radio altimeter inputs to function correctly4) The radio altimeter provides crucial height information to the ground proximity warning system (GPWS)5) The radio altimeter supplies the automatic flight system with data that affects automatic landings",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "A directional gyro is:\n\n1) a gyroscope free around two axis\n2) a gyroscope free around one axis\n3) capable of self- orientation around an earth-tied direction\n4) incapable of self-orientation around an earth-tied direction\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:\n\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram which shows a 40° left bank and 15° nose up attitude is number:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "During cruise with full automation engaged and the autothrottle in speed mode, speed control is achieved by the:",
    "feedback": "Autothrottle varying engine thrust, while the autopilot varies the aircraft pitch to maintain altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the source of magnetic variation information in a Flight Management System (FMS)?",
    "feedback": "Magnetic variation information is stored in each IRS memory; it is applied to the true heading calculated by the respective IRS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of a compass swing is to attempt to coincide the indications of:",
    "feedback": "compass north and magnetic north."
  },
  {
    "question": "On a TCAS II, a preventative resolution advisory:",
    "feedback": "advises the pilot to monitor the vertical speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diagram which shows a 40° right bank and 8° nose down is:",
    "feedback": "diagram 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Vertical Speed Indicator (VSI) give:",
    "feedback": "Immediate trend information and stable climb or descent information after 6 to 12 seconds (depending on type)."
  },
  {
    "question": "If immediate crew awareness is required and subsequent crew action will be required, the flight warning system (FWS) generates:",
    "feedback": "a caution message"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding the Mach meter and limiting Mach numbers:",
    "feedback": "VMO and MMO are indicated on the face of the velocity instruments as barber poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a remote indicating compass system the amount of deviation caused by aircraft magnetism and electrical circuits may be minimised by:",
    "feedback": "mounting the detector unit (flux valve) in the wingtip"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS navigation database includes the following data: 1- airports 2- obstacles 3- navaids 4- airways 5- relief  The combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,3,4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following are factors that determine the type and number of parameters to be recorded by a FDR (Flight Data Recorder)?",
    "feedback": "Recording capacity and applicable operational requirements"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure capsule of an airspeed indicator is sensitive to the difference:",
    "feedback": "(Total Pressure - Static Pressure), called Dynamic Pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main difference between the more common portable electronic devices (PED) EFB and the integrated avionics EFB?",
    "feedback": "The PEDs are not certified as a part of the aircraft, do not have a part number, and are not maintained by certified aircraft maintenance personnel"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following information can be displayed on a Primary Flight Display (PFD):\n1) Traffic information from the ACAS\n2) Flight path vector\n3) Altitude\n4) ILS indications\n5) Lower selectable airspeed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mode in which the EFIS ND display shows the desired track to the Initial Approach Fix, the magnetic heading at the lubber line, and the aircraft symbol in the lower part of the screen?",
    "feedback": "MAP mode"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "It is important to check the flight management computer (FMC) data through the FMA when using the FDS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter consists of one or several aneroid capsules located in a sealed casing.\nThe pressures in the aneroid capsule (i) and casing (ii) are respectively :",
    "feedback": "(i) vacuum (or a very low pressure) (ii) static pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to aircraft fuel flow parameters is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "Performance database"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the earth's magnetic field is completely correct?",
    "feedback": "The blue pole of the earth's magnetic field is situated in North Canada"
  },
  {
    "question": "An Air Data Computer (ADC) :",
    "feedback": "Transforms air data measurements into electric impulses driving servo motors in instruments"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot wishes to turn left on to a northerly heading with 10° bank at a latitude of 50° North. Using a direct reading compass, in order to achieve this he must stop the turn on an approximate heading of :",
    "feedback": "030°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your aircraft is TCAS II equipped; an intruding traffic only has a mode C transponder. The information relating to this intruding traffic available on your TCAS equipment is:",
    "feedback": "three dimensional; your TCAS can generate both TAs (Traffic Advisories) and RAs (Resolution Advisories)"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the speed exceeds VMO/MMO and according to the type of aeroplane, the overspeed protection function can:\n1) reduce thrust to idle2) send a pitch up order3) inhibit the pitch trim orders in the nose up direction\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A basic computer (\"Von Neumann architecture\" type) consists of the following components:\n\n1) a cache memory\n2) a single separate storage structure\n3) a Central Processing Unit (CPU)\n4) an Asymmetric and Logic Unit (ALU)\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "An \"altitude warning system\" must at least warn the crew :\n\n1- when approaching the pre-selected altitude\n2- when the airplane is approaching the ground too fast\n3- in case of a given deviation above or below the pre-selected altitude\n4- in case of excessive vertical speed\n5- when approaching the ground with the gear retracted\n\nThe combination regrouping all the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about the properties of a simple bar magnet are correct or incorrect?\n1) North or south poles can exist separately2) Magnetism is concentrated at the extremities of the bar",
    "feedback": "1) is not correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "For compatibility between the different components of a flight warning system, the priority from the highest to the lowest is:",
    "feedback": "stall, windshear, GPWS, TCAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which instrument is represented in the picture?",
    "feedback": "IRS"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lateral flight path modes of an autopilot system are:\n\n1) speed hold\n2) Localiser intercept and track\n3) track hold\n4) FMS lateral navigation\n5) pitch attitude hold\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is :",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnitude of a torque is defined as:",
    "feedback": "force times its lever arm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The vertical reference unit of a three-axis data generator is equipped with a gyro with :",
    "feedback": "2 degrees of freedom and vertical spin axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "A landing will be considered to be performed in the AUTOMATIC mode when: 1- the autopilot maintains the airplane on the ILS beam until the decision height is reached then is disengaged automatically. 2- the autothrottle maintains a constant speed until the decision height is reached then is disengaged automatically. 3- the autopilot maintains the airplane on the ILS beam until the flare. 4- the autothrottle decreases the thrust when the height is approximately 30 ft. 5- the flare and the ground roll are performed automatically. The combination regrouping all the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4 and 5."
  },
  {
    "question": "The yaw damper system sends a motion order to the rudder if the yawing rate of the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "not constant"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following information can be displayed on the Navigation Display (ND) with the MAP (or ARC) mode:\n1) Selected and current track\n2) Decision height\n3) TAS\n4) Ground speed\n5) Wind direction and speed\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of communication is used in ACMS (Aeroplane Condition Monitoring System)?",
    "feedback": "By datalink without crew notification"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a loss of GPS signal, the FMS position:",
    "feedback": "May deviate from the actual position"
  },
  {
    "question": "The nose of the airplane is located to the .... of this instrument. Imagine the picture shows a straight and level flight. As soon as the angle of attack is increased, the right part of the instrument will move......:",
    "feedback": "left, up"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FADEC (Full Authority Digital Engine Control):\n\n1) provides fully automatic engine starting\n2) modifies aircraft airspeed in order to allow for the lowest fuel consumption\n3) counters any yaw moment in case of engine failure\n4) provides thrust reverser control\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering a stabilised platform inertial system:\n\n1) the rate gyros and the accelerometers are mounted on the same platform\n2) the rate gyros and the accelerometers are mounted on two separated platforms\n3) the principle of operation requires at least 2 rate gyros\n4) the principle of operation requires at least 2 accelerometers\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Indication of Mach number is obtained from:",
    "feedback": "Indicated speed and altitude using a speed indicator equipped with an altimeter type aneroid"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the characteristics of an RA (Resolution Advisory) generated by TCAS above 1600 ft AGL?",
    "feedback": "A red square on the display unit, an annunciation (eg \"CLIMB, CLIMB\") and at the end of the RA sequence the annunciation \"CLEAR OF CONFLICT\""
  },
  {
    "question": "CAS is equal to:",
    "feedback": "IAS corrected for position and instrument errors"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS provides the following functions:\n\n1) traffic advisories emission\n2) resolution advisories emission\n3) aid for fuel management\n4) lateral flight plan management\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The white arrow in the lower-left corner indicates:",
    "feedback": "Current wind of 305°/8 kts is being experienced"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gauge indicating the quantity of fuel measured by a capacity gauging system can be graduated directly in weight units because the dielectric constant of fuel is:",
    "feedback": "twice that of air and varies directly with density."
  },
  {
    "question": "When available, the yaw damper indicator supplies the pilot with information regarding the:",
    "feedback": "yaw damper action on the rudder"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is fitted with EFIS, including PFD, ND, and ECAM. Where would an advisory message be displayed?",
    "feedback": "ECAM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What data can be shown on the HUD?",
    "feedback": "Attitude, altitude, heading, FMA, GPWS, and wind shear commands"
  },
  {
    "question": "To obtain the instantaneous speed from the accelerations:",
    "feedback": "it is necessary to integrate the acceleration once in time, and to know the initial speed only"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter is subject to static pressure error. This error results from:",
    "feedback": "incorrect pressure sensing caused by disturbed airflow around the static ports"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to maintain an accurate vertical using a pendulous system, an aircraft inertial platform incorporates a device:",
    "feedback": "with damping and a period of 84.4 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following is an advantage of a multi-sensor system using inputs from a global navigation satellite system (GNSS) and an inertial reference system (IRS)?",
    "feedback": "The GNSS can be used to update the FMS position from a drifting IRS"
  },
  {
    "question": "If OAT increases when at a constant Mach number:",
    "feedback": "TAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Auto thrust protects against:",
    "feedback": "Current thrust limits"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is correct regarding the FDM? A Flight Data Monitoring (FDM) programme collects and analyzes aircraft flight data for the purpose of:",
    "feedback": "Identifying adverse safety trends and tailoring training programmes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The green symbol of a circle with T/D appears on the EHSI display. It represents:",
    "feedback": "The FMC calculated top of descent"
  },
  {
    "question": "The direction of magnetic north at a certain position coincides with the direction of:",
    "feedback": "the horizontal component of the earth's magnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a capacitor are correct or incorrect?\n1) The capacitance is proportional to the surfaces of the plates\n2) The capacitance is proportional to the relative permittivity",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The stick pusher is part of the:",
    "feedback": "Stall Protection System"
  },
  {
    "question": "If crew awareness is required and subsequent crew action may be required, the flight warning system (FWS) generates:",
    "feedback": "an advisory message"
  },
  {
    "question": "A negative (westerly) magnetic variation signifies that :",
    "feedback": "True North is East of Magnetic North"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an Inertial Reference System, accelerations are measured in relation to:",
    "feedback": "aircraft axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about a capacitor are correct or incorrect?\n1) The capacitance is proportional to distance between plates\n2) The capacitance is proportional to the relative permittivity",
    "feedback": "1) is incorrect, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft is at 400 ft AGL on an approach. What will be generated on the TCAS regarding an intruder?",
    "feedback": "TA, yellow/amber solid circle, no aural alert"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the typical selections that may be available on an EFIS control panel?\n1) Altimeter pressure setting2) Navigation display (ND) mode selector3) ND range and colour selector4) ND data selector, such as waypoints, facilities, constraints, data5) Radio navigation aids selector6) Decision altitude/height selection",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The initiation of an automatic go-around can be:",
    "feedback": "in a range of approach airspeeds"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight path vector (FPV) of an EFIS shows:",
    "feedback": "the glide angle"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Navigation Display (ND) indicates the magnetic heading of the aircraft. The detector unit that senses the (1) .... component of the Earth's magnetic field, is the (2) .... .",
    "feedback": "(1) horizontal, (2) flux valve"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Navigation Display (ND) of an EFIS equipped aircraft can display the following data:",
    "feedback": "flight plan, weather radar, terrain map, intruding traffic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct?\n1) The automatic flight control system incorporates elements that adapt the magnitude of control inputs in response to the received input signals2) At high airspeed, the autopilot system reduces the magnitude of the control inputs",
    "feedback": "1) and 2) are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning the flexible take-off mode, the temperature selected in the FMS is:",
    "feedback": "higher than the ambient airfield temperature, in order to achieve a reduced power setting"
  },
  {
    "question": "A strapdown inertial system consists in:",
    "feedback": "a platform attached to the aircraft chassis which includes gyroscopes and accelerometers"
  },
  {
    "question": "The use of autopilot can lead to a loss of situational awareness and the comprehension of the implication of the used mode. How can these risks be mitigated?",
    "feedback": "Apply Standard Operating Procedures and follow/respect the call-outs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be the indication on the magnetic compass when rolling into a standard rate\nturn to the right from a south heading in the Northern Hemisphere?",
    "feedback": "The compass will indicate a turn to the right, but at a faster rate than is actually occurring."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can be provided through an EFB?\n1) Performance calculations2) Mass and balance calculations3) Information about the status of the AFCS4) Aeronautical charts5) Operations Manual",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight warning system (FWS) generates an advisory message if:",
    "feedback": "crew awareness is required and subsequent crew action may be required"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at a 120 kt true airspeed (VV), in order to achieve a rate 1 turn, the pilot will have to bank the aircraft at an angle of:",
    "feedback": "18°."
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the magnetic compass most effective?",
    "feedback": "About midway between the magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements with regards to an IVSI is correct?",
    "feedback": "The IVSI can give erroneous readings at the beginning or end of a turn if the bank angle is about 40° or steeper"
  },
  {
    "question": "With constant weight and configuration, an aeroplane takes off at the same :",
    "feedback": "EAS"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning thrust measurement, the N1 is defined as the:",
    "feedback": "low pressure shaft speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compared with a stabilised platform inertial system, a strapdown inertial system:\n\n1) has a longer alignment phase in time\n2) has a shorter alignment phase in time\n3) is more reliable in time\n4) is less reliable in time\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding a typical post-refuelling procedure:\n1) It is the responsibility of the flight crew to record the volume of fuel that was filled and to compare the actual indicated fuel content to the calculated fuel content2) It is the responsibility of the ground personnel to confirm that the uplifted fuel corresponds with the quantities of fuel displayed on the fuel gauges in the aircraft",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is not correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The north and south magnetic poles are the only positions on the earth's surface where:",
    "feedback": "a freely suspended compass needle will stand vertical"
  },
  {
    "question": "Concerning a fail-passive flight control system, in the event of a failure:\n\n1) there may be a significant deviation of flight path or attitude\n2) there is no significant deviation of flight path or attitude\n3) there is no significant out-of-trim condition\n4) there may be significant out-of-trim condition\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The data supplied by a radio altimeter:",
    "feedback": "indicates the distance between the ground and the aircraft."
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is in steady descent. The autothrottle maintains a constant calibrated airspeed. If the total temperature remains constant, the Mach number :",
    "feedback": "decreases."
  },
  {
    "question": "The flux valve of a gyromagnetic compass:\n\n1) feeds the error detector\n2) feeds the direct indicating compass\n3) gives the earth's magnetic field direction\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "The deviation will change with a change in aircraft heading",
    "feedback": "Because the undesired magnetic pole then is moved relative to the direction of the Earth's magnetic field"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in a steady right turn, with not enough right rudder (slipping turn). The yaw damper system:",
    "feedback": "is not designed to provide a balanced turn"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a manual ILS final approach, the auto-throttle:",
    "feedback": "can be operated in the SPEED mode (holding of IAS)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 3 is showing:",
    "feedback": "a 40° right bank and 8° nose down attitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the ADC fails, which piece of information is no longer available from an inertial navigation unit?",
    "feedback": "Wind direction and speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "During cruise with autothrottle/autothrust engaged at M 0.70, a cold front is crossed and the SAT drops by a few degrees.\nAs a consequence, the IAS....",
    "feedback": "will remain constant and the TAS will decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Inertial Reference System sensors include:",
    "feedback": "accelerometers and laser gyros, mounted in the direction of the aircraft axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "The value shown by the indicator of a vibration monitoring system is 4. This is:",
    "feedback": "a level of vibration without any unit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Diagram 2 represents:",
    "feedback": "a left turn with too much rudder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gyroscope of a turn indicator has:\n(NB: the rotor spin axis is not counted for the number of degrees of freedom of the gyro)",
    "feedback": "1 degree of freedom"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight envelope protection function(s) consist(s) in:\n\n1) alerting the flight crew in case of dangerous proximity with the ground\n2) avoiding midair collisions\n3) preventing the aircraft from exceeding some aerodynamic limits\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in a steady left turn, with too much left rudder (skidding turn). The yaw damper system:",
    "feedback": "is not designed to provide a balanced turn"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"Bourdon tube\" is used to measure :",
    "feedback": "pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight warning system (FWS) generates an warning message if:",
    "feedback": "immediate recognition and corrective or compensatory action by the crew is required"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about fundamental laws of magnetism are correct or incorrect?\n1) Unlike poles attract\n2) Like poles repel each other",
    "feedback": "1) is correct,2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "feedback": "An ADIRU is an ADC integrated with an Inertial Reference Unit (IRU), comprising separate controls for the ADC part and Inertial Reference (IR) part"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TCAS (Traffic Collision Avoidance System) is a proximity alarm system which detects a \"traffic\" when the conflicting traffic is equipped with a :",
    "feedback": "serviceable SSR transponder"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Machmeter is subject to position error. This error results from:",
    "feedback": "incorrect pressure sensing caused by disturbed airflow around the pitot tube and/or static ports"
  },
  {
    "question": "The output data of an IRS are:\n\n1) true track\n2) Mach number\n3) present position (lat, long)\n4) true heading\n5) attitude\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "If immediate recognition and corrective or compensatory action by the crew is required, the flight warning system (FWS) generates:",
    "feedback": "a warning message"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pressure of 1 bar equals:",
    "feedback": "100000 pascal"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the vicinity of the magnetic North Pole the magnetic compass is useless because:",
    "feedback": "The horizontal component of the magnetic field is too weak."
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS is approved for Localizer approaches:",
    "feedback": "if the Localizer signals are used by the FMS."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements concerning the aircraft positions indicated on a triple fit Inertial Navigation System (INS)/ Inertial Reference System (IRS) on the CDU is correct?",
    "feedback": "The positions are likely to differ because they are calculated from different sources"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of an automatic landing system is to:",
    "feedback": "make the landing possible in poor weather conditions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Regarding touch control steering (TCS):",
    "feedback": "Unlike with CWS the appropriate automatic control channels and servomotors are disengaged while the TCS button is held depressed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sensors used to measure the exhaust gas temperature on an airplane equipped with gas turbine engines are:",
    "feedback": "thermocouples."
  },
  {
    "question": "If the outside temperature at 35 000 feet is -40°C, the local speed of sound is :",
    "feedback": "595 kt."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following situtations will trigger a MASTER WARNING?\n1) Engine fire2) Brakes overheat3) Overspeed",
    "feedback": "1, 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "A torque my be expressed in:",
    "feedback": "Newton meter (N m)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"Bourdon Tube\" is used in:",
    "feedback": "pressure sensors"
  },
  {
    "question": "When comparing GPS altitude with the reading on the pressure altimeter:\n1) GPS altitude is an indication of absolute altitude2) GPS altitude is almost perfectly accurate3) When QFE is set on the pressure altimeter, it displays altitude above mean sea level4) When QFE is set at the aerodrome reference point, GPS altitude may be used to check the accuracy of the pressure altimeter\nThe combination regrouping all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The data that needs to be inserted into an Inertial Reference System in order to enable the system to make a successful alignment for navigation is:",
    "feedback": "aircraft position in latitude and longitude or airport ICAO identifier"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to AMC 25-11 concerning the electronic display systems, the colour associated with a warning-type alert is:",
    "feedback": "red"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ground routing of the ATC datalink communications is performed:",
    "feedback": "by service providers (SITA, ARINC..) that can be interconnected to provide continuity of the transmissions"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating frequency of the Radio Altimeter is normally",
    "feedback": "between 4,250 and 4,350 MHz, FMCW"
  },
  {
    "question": "The FMS is approved to provide guidance for the following approaches: 1- RNAV 2- PAR 3- VOR/DME, VOR 4- MLS The combination which regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1,3"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is equipped with one altimeter which is compensated for position error and another altimeter which is not. Assuming all other factors are equal, during a straight symmetrical flight:",
    "feedback": "the greater the speed, the greater the error between the two altimeters"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TAS is obtained from the CAS by correcting for the following errors:\n\n1) instrument\n2) compressibility\n3) position\n4) density\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the ND, the TCAS generates the TA intruder aircraft symbol represented in the picture. The correct intruder information concerning this TA is:",
    "feedback": "300 ft above and descending with a vertical speed of 500 ft/min or more"
  },
  {
    "question": "The altimeter indicates 15000 ft with a subscale setting of 1013,25 hPa. OAT is -21°C. \n\nThe pressure altitude of the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "15000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following must a Cockpit Voice Recorder record?\n1) Audio or voice signals identifying navigation or approach aids introduced into a headset or speaker2) The aural environment of the flight deck3) Flight crew members on the flight deck using the aeroplane's interphone system4) Flight crew members using the aeroplane's interphone system between cabin crew stations (if installed)5) Voice communications transmitted from or received in the aeroplane by radio6) Flight crew members on the flight deck using the public address system (if installed)",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 5, 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "In an autopilot system:",
    "feedback": "the inner loops provide the stability functions and the outer loops provide the guidance functions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering an airspeed indicator, a second striped needle, if installed, indicates:",
    "feedback": "VMO"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to know in which mode the auto-throttles are engaged, the crew will check the:\n\n1) auto-throttle ARM switches\n2) auto-throttle disengage switches\n3) mode control panel\n4) mode annunciator panel\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a TCAS Resolution Advisory (RA) climb instruction is generated, the required vertical speed range displayed on the vertical speed indicator:",
    "feedback": "does not take into account the stall margin"
  },
  {
    "question": "When an automatic thrust control system is in the SPEED mode:",
    "feedback": "it maintains the selected airspeed"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is true if the autothrottle (A/T) is maintained in the SPEED HOLD mode?",
    "feedback": "The A/T is active"
  },
  {
    "question": "One FMS is in disagreement with another, what happens?",
    "feedback": "Nothing, the pilots must keep cross-checking the FMS to make sure they stay in agreement"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Flight Management Computer (FMC) of the Flight Management System (FMS), data relating to waypoints is stored in the:",
    "feedback": "navigation database"
  },
  {
    "question": "While flying at their assigned cruising level, the pilot of an aeroplane fitted with conventional flight controls experiences a stabiliser trim runaway to the full nose-down position. If the pilot applies full elevator deflection in the opposite direction, it will .....",
    "feedback": "still result in a loss of altitude because the elevator nose up direction is restricted"
  },
  {
    "question": "The manifold pressure gauge measures",
    "feedback": "absolute pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "The operating principle of a oil torque meter is:\n1) Axial movement is generated by the helically cut gears\n2) Axial force is proportional to the torque",
    "feedback": "1) is correct, 2) is correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "To warn the flight crew, an overspeed warning system can use:\n1) an aural warning2) a stick shaker connected to the control column3) a vibration device connected to the autothrottle\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "A temperature sensor having a recovery factor of 0.75 indicates 30° C.  Static Air Temperature (SAT) is 25° C. How high is the Ram-rise?",
    "feedback": "5° C."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following options is correct regarding the Synthetic Vision System (SVS)?",
    "feedback": "The SVS solely uses data from a predefined fixed database to create a synthetic vision representation of the surroundings of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about the navigational database of a FMS?",
    "feedback": "Crew-created navigational data may be saved in additional space in the database"
  }
]